ty O
of O
California B-GPE
|
| O
ern O
Regional O
|
| O
ary O
Facility O
|

      

 

| O
ie O
|

| O
ae O
|
| O
Sb O
4 O
ae O
a O
|

 

 

 

 

 

| O
THE O
|

| O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
oF O
|

| O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
, O
|

| O
THE O
FACTORY O
BOY O
. O
|

| O
BY O
|

| O
FRANCES O
TROLLOPS O
, O
|

| O
Aur O
|

 

| O
oF O
|

| O
“ O
JESSIE B-PERSON
PHILLIPS O
, O
” O
“ O
THE B-WORK_OF_ART
BARNABYS I-WORK_OF_ART
IN I-WORK_OF_ART
AMERICA I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
” O
& O
e. O
|

| O
WITH O
NUMEROUS O
ILLUSTRATIONS O
. O
|

| O
LONDON B-GPE
: O
|
| O
HENRY B-PERSON
COLBURN I-PERSON
, O
PUBLISHER O
, O
|
| O
GREAT O
MARLBOROUGH O
STREET O
. O
|

| O
1844 B-DATE
. O
|

 

| O
Digitized O
by O
the B-ORG
Inter I-ORG
|

| I-ORG
7 I-ORG
. O
) O
in O
2007 B-DATE
with O
fundi B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Microsoft I-ORG
Corpo I-ORG
: O
|

  
   
 

| O
ee O
|

| O
http://www.archive.org/details/lifeadventuresof00troli O
|

| O
Stack O
|
| O
Annex O
, O
|

| O
56 B-PERCENT
% I-PERCENT
|
| O
T3A O
|
| O
1SA4 O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
|

 

| O
Wuewn B-NORP
the O
author O
of O
‘ O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
” O
first B-ORDINAL
determined O
on O
|

| O
attempting O
to O
draw O
the O
attention O
Of O
her O
countrymen O
to O
the O
fearful O
|
| O
evils O
inherent O
in O
the B-FAC
Factory I-FAC
System I-FAC
, O
as O
carried O
out O
in O
our O
manufac- O
|
| O
turing O
towns O
, O
she O
intended O
to O
divide O
her O
work O
into O
two B-CARDINAL
portions O
, O
which O
|
| O
should O
present O
the O
same O
subject O
under O
two B-CARDINAL
different O
phases O
. O
It O
was O
|
| O
her O
intention O
in O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
of O
these O
to O
drag O
into O
the O
light O
of O
day O
, O
and O
|
| O
place O
before O
the O
eyes O
of O
Englishmen B-LANGUAGE
, O
the O
hideous O
mass O
of O
injustice O
|
| O
and O
suffering O
to O
which O
thousands B-CARDINAL
of O
infant O
labourers O
are O
subjected O
, O
who O
|
| O
toil O
in O
our O
monster O
spinning O
- O
mills O
, O
In O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
, O
she O
proposed O
that O
the O
|
| O
hero O
of O
her O
tale O
, O
having O
lived O
through O
his O
toil O
- O
worn O
boyhood O
, O
should O
|
| O
haye B-PERSON
been O
seen O
embarked O
in O
those O
perfectly O
constitutional O
struggles O
|
| O
for O
the O
amelioration O
of O
the O
sufferings O
of O
his O
class O
, O
in O
which O
many O
of O
|
| O
the O
more O
enlightened O
operatives O
have O
been O
for O
some B-DATE
years I-DATE
engaged O
. O
|
| O
” O
‘ O
The O
first B-ORDINAL
division O
of O
the O
subject O
has O
been O
some O
time O
in O
the O
reader O
's O
|
| O
hands O
. O
The O
true O
but O
most O
painful O
picture O
has O
been O
drawn O
faithfully O
|
| O
and O
conscientiously O
. O
Of O
course O
voices O
have O
been O
raised O
to O
deny O
|
| O
loudly O
the O
truth O
of O
all O
the O
author O
’s O
statements O
, O
and O
to O
assert O
the O
whole O
|
| O
to O
be O
a O
mere O
tissue O
of O
invention O
and O
falsehood O
. O
The O
same O
charges O
|
| O
have O
been O
made O
against O
her O
upon O
another O
occasion O
, O
and O
she O
has O
lived O
|
| O
to O
see O
the O
truth O
of O
her O
statements O
, O
so O
impugned O
, O
universally O
admitted O
. O
|
| O
She O
awaits O
with O
perfect O
confidence O
the O
time O
when O
similar O
justice O
shall O
|
| O
be O
rendered O
to O
these O
pages O
. O
|

| O
But O
with O
respect O
to O
that O
division O
of O
the O
subject O
which O
it O
was O
in- O
|
| O
tended O
to O
bring O
forward O
in O
the O
latter O
part O
of O
ler B-ORG
work O
, O
the O
author O
's O
|
| O
views O
have O
undergone O
very O
considerable O
change O
. O
Knowing O
the O
immense O
|
| O
amount O
of O
evil O
to O
be O
remedied O
, O
and O
the O
urgent O
necessity O
, O
for O
many O
|
| O
reasons O
, O
that O
this O
remedy O
should O
not O
be O
delayed O
, O
it O
is O
grievous O
to O
see O
|

 

| O
iy O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
misguided O
and O
unfortunate O
men O
pursuing O
a O
course O
which O
must O
neces- O
|
| O
sarily O
neutralize O
the O
efforts O
of O
their O
true O
friends O
. O
When O
those O
in O
whose O
|
| O
behalf O
she O
hoped O
to O
move O
the O
sympathy O
of O
their O
country O
are O
found O
|
| O
busy O
in O
scenes O
of O
outrage O
and O
lawless O
violence O
, O
and O
uniting O
themselves O
|
| O
with O
individuals O
whose O
doctrines O
are O
subversive O
of O
every O
species O
of O
|
| O
social O
order O
, O
the O
author O
feels O
that O
it O
would O
be O
alike O
acting O
in O
violation O
|
| O
of O
her O
own O
principles O
, O
and O
doing O
injury O
to O
the O
cause O
she O
wishes O
to O
|
| O
serve O
, O
were O
she O
to O
persist O
in O
an O
attempt O
to O
hold O
up O
as O
objects O
of O
public O
|
| O
sympathy O
, O
men O
who O
have O
stained O
their O
righteous O
cause O
with O
deeds O
of O
|
| O
violence O
and O
blood O
. O
The O
author O
is O
well O
aware O
that O
many O
, O
as O
well O
|
| O
operatives O
as O
their O
superiors O
, O
who O
were O
engaged O
in O
a O
virtuous O
struggle O
|
| O
against O
the O
lawless O
power O
which O
oppresses O
them O
, O
deplore O
the O
madness O
|
| O
of O
these O
ill O
- O
advised O
men O
as O
much O
as O
herself O
. O
But O
the O
cause O
has O
been O
|
| O
too O
much O
sullied O
, O
and O
the O
sufferers O
too O
closely O
associated O
in O
the O
public O
|
| O
eye O
with O
those O
who O
have O
been O
guilty O
of O
all O
she O
most O
deprecates O
, O
to O
|
| O
permit O
her O
coutinuing O
the O
work O
as O
she O
intended O
. O
|

| O
Under O
these O
circumstances O
she O
has O
determined O
that O
the O
existence O
of O
|
| O
her O
hero O
as O
an O
operative O
shall O
close O
with O
his O
childhood O
. O
No O
miscon- O
|
| O
struction O
of O
principles O
, O
no O
misconception O
of O
motives O
can O
exist O
with O
|
| O
regard O
to O
an O
attempt O
to O
ameliorate O
the O
lot O
of O
infant O
labourers O
. O
That O
her O
|
| O
pages O
may O
assist O
in O
promoting O
this O
object O
is O
her O
humble O
and O
most O
|
| O
ardent O
hope O
. O
‘ O
The B-WORK_OF_ART
Life I-WORK_OF_ART
and I-WORK_OF_ART
Adventures I-WORK_OF_ART
of O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
” O
are O
, O
|
| O
therefore O
, O
concluded O
in O
the O
twelfth B-ORDINAL
number O
. O
|

 

| O
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
I. O
|

| O
PAGE O
|
| O
Description B-ORG
of I-ORG
Dowling I-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
and O
its O
appurtenances O
— O
Of O
its O
master O
— O
|
| O
Of O
its O
mistress O
— O
And O
all O
the O
Masters B-ORG
and O
Misses B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
— O
A O
large O
|
| O
dinner O
- O
party O
— O
A O
hot O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
and O
the O
way O
to O
escape O
fromit O
... O
1 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
I. O
|
| O
A O
delightful O
ramble O
— O
Friendship O
and O
the O
Muse B-ORG
— O
An O
adventure O
— O
Danger O
|

   

 

 

| O
and O
escape O
— O
Gratitude O
and O
benevolence O
........... O
4++ O
9 O
|
| O
CHAPTER O
Il O
. O
|

| O
Introduction O
of O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
into O
the O
family O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
— O
Conjectures O
concerning O
his O
parentage O
— O
A O
confabulation O
|
| O
between O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
and O
Mr O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
Parsons I-PERSON
. O
24 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
IV O
. O
|
| O
A O
little O
cottage O
gossip O
— O
Avisit O
of O
charity O
— O
Practical O
benevolence O
... O
35 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CHAPTER O
V O
, O
|

| O
A O
separation O
of O
loving O
hearts O
— O
A O
specimen O
of O
finished O
composition O
— O
|
| O
Condescension O
and O
generosity O
— O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
clothes O
little O
Michael B-PERSON
|
| O
with O
his O
own O
hands O
.......... O
44 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
CHAPTER O
VI O
. O
|

| O
Michael B-PERSON
's O
introduction O
to O
all O
the O
Miss O
Dowlings B-PERSON
— O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
feeds O
|
| O
him O
with O
his O
own O
hand O
, O
aud O
presents O
him O
to O
all O
his O
most O
valued O
|
| O
friends O
..... O
|

   

| O
CHAPTER O
Vil O
. O
|

| O
A O
popular O
character O
— O
More O
benevolence O
— O
Interesting O
intelligence O
re- O
|
| O
ceived O
with O
becoming O
animation O
— O
A O
select O
committee O
— O
A O
farewell O
|
| O
fullof O
meaning O
... O
cae B-PERSON
207 B-CARDINAL
|

 

 

| O
vi O
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
VIII O
. O
|

| O
PAGE O
|
| O
A O
very O
innocent O
téfe O
- O
d O
- O
téte O
, O
but O
in O
which O
Miss O
Martha B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
comes O
|
| O
to O
a O
wrong O
conclusion O
— O
An O
unfortunate O
embassy O
— O
An O
agreeable O
ex- O
|

| O
cursion O
— O
A O
philosophical O
disquisition O
— O
A O
visit O
to O
the O
factory O
... O
72 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
IX I-LAW
. O
|
| O
Some O
particulars O
respecting O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
— O
A O
demonstration O
of O
|
| O
neighbonrly O
friendship O
and O
anxiety O
— O
The O
wilfulness O
of O
an O
heiress O
— O
A O
|
| O
gleam O
of O
light O
canght O
in O
the O
darkness O
..... O
8 B-CARDINAL
t O
|

 

| O
CHAPTER O
X. O
|

| O
More O
wilfulness O
on O
the O
part O
of O
the O
heiress O
— O
Private O
theatricals O
— O
Failure O
|
| O
ofa O
young O
performer O
, O
and O
its O
consequences O
— O
Philosopliical O
breakfast- O
|
| O
table O
— O
A O
morning B-TIME
's O
excursion O
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XI I-LAW
. O
|

| O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
pushes O
her O
inquiries O
further O
— O
A O
well O
- O
arranged O
scheme O
|
| O
disagreeably B-ORG
defeated O
— O
A O
visit O
, O
and O
its O
consequences O
.. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XiIL O
. O
|

| O
An O
unfortunate O
rencounter O
— O
Anadventure O
— O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
grows O
wiser O
|

 

 

 

 

| O
every O
day O
sss O
|

| O
CHAPTER B-PERSON
Xill I-PERSON
. O
|

| O
Disagreeable B-PERSON
meditations O
— O
A O
confidential O
interview O
with O
a O
faithful O
ser- O
|

| O
vant O
— O
Another O
interview O
, O
not O
quite O
so O
confidential O
, O
with O
a O
danghter O
— O
|
| O
Martha B-PERSON
and O
Michael B-PERSON
take O
a O
pleasant O
walk O
together O
to O
visit O
the O
widow O
|
| O
Armstrong B-PERSON
— O
A O
consultation O
... O
. O
187 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XIV O
. O
|

| O
Mary B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
continues O
sick O
in O
heart O
and O
mind O
— O
But O
is O
roused O
and O
|
| O
cheered O
by O
her O
own O
steadfast O
will O
— O
An O
o’er O
true O
tale O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XV O
. O
|

| O
A O
téte O
- O
d O
- O
tite O
walk O
— O
Lively O
if O
not O
instructive O
conversation O
— O
The O
rich O
|
| O
visiting O
the O
poor O
— O
Misplaced O
confidence O
— O
Innocent O
sin O
|

 

 

 

| O
CHAPTER O
XVI O
. O
|

| O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
visits O
the O
widow O
Armstrong B-PERSON
, O
and O
lays O
the O
foundation O
of O
|
| O
a O
very O
lasting O
friendship O
— O
She O
then O
calls O
at O
Dowling B-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
, O
but O
fails O
|
| O
of O
obtaining O
what O
she O
went O
for O
+ O
» O
163 B-CARDINAL
|

 

 

| O
CONTENTS O
. O
vii O
|

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XVII I-LAW
. O
|

| O
PAGE O
|
| O
‘ O
A O
journey O
begun O
in O
very O
good O
style O
, O
but O
ending O
not O
quite O
so O
well O
— O
A O
|

| O
faithful O
description O
of O
a O
valley O
in O
Derbyshire B-GPE
— O
Michael B-PERSON
makes O
some O
|

   

| O
new O
acquaintance O
... O
peeeeteeeress O
Recess O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XVIII O
. O
|

| O
An O
explanatory O
epistle O
, O
which O
does O
not O
prove O
satisfactory O
— O
Plans O
for O
the O
|
| O
future O
, O
followed O
by O
active O
measures O
to O
carry O
them O
into O
effect O
— O
A O
|
| O
morning B-TIME
visit O
to O
Mrs O
, O
Gabberly B-ORG
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XIX I-LAW
. O
|

| O
A O
voyage O
of O
discovery O
— O
A O
plain O
statement O
, O
leading O
to O
the O
conviction O
|
| O
that O
even O
where O
ignorance O
is O
not O
bliss O
, O
knowledge O
is O
not O
always O
hap- O
|
| O
piness O
— O
A O
hasty O
friendship O
that O
may O
nevertheless O
prove O
lasting O
... O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XX O
. O
|
| O
Trade O
in O
a O
flourishing O
state O
— O
The O
benefits O
conferred O
thereby O
to O
those O
|
| O
employed O
in O
it O
— O
The O
natural O
logic O
of O
religion O
— O
Its O
fallibility O
when O
|
| O
put O
to O
the O
test O
... O
sssereeee O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXI O
. O
|

| O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
exerts O
her O
cloquence O
, O
and O
nurse O
Tremlett B-PERSON
is O
brought O
to O
|
| O
reason O
thereby O
— O
The O
heiress O
hardens O
her O
heart O
, O
and O
speaks O
harsh O
|
| O
truths O
to O
Martha B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
but O
all O
in O
vain O
— O
She O
conceives O
a O
project O
, O
|
| O
and O
sets O
about O
putting O
it O
in O
execution O
with O
great O
spirit O
.... O
1 B-CARDINAL
219 I-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXII O
, O
|
| O
Miss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
sets O
off O
on O
her O
travels O
, O
and O
feels O
frightened O
at O
her O
own O
|
| O
temerity O
— O
But O
speedily O
recovers O
her O
courage O
, O
and O
plays O
the O
heroine O
— O
|
| O
She O
visits O
some O
factories O
, O
and O
is O
introduced O
to O
a O
Sunday B-DATE
- O
school O
— O
She O
|

 

 

 

 

 

 

| O
approaches O
the O
precincts O
of O
the B-LOC
Deep I-LOC
Valley I-LOC
« I-LOC
.. O
sscsscsssssssenes O
|

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XXIII I-LAW
. O
|

| O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
and O
her O
friend O
arrive O
at O
the B-FAC
Deep I-FAC
Valley I-FAC
— O
A O
review O
— O
|
| O
Disappointment O
— O
“ O
A O
sudden O
thought O
strikes O
” O
the O
heiress O
— O
She O
con- O
|
| O
cludes O
a O
bargain O
, O
though O
not O
the O
one O
for O
which O
she O
meditated O
— O
She O
|
| O
sets O
out O
upon O
a O
walk O
.. O
, O
aap B-PERSON
ee I-PERSON
aed I-PERSON
|

| I-PERSON
CHAPTER O
XXIV O
. O
|

| O
The O
waik O
proves O
too O
fatiguing O
to O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
party O
, O
but O
not O
to O
Miss O
Bro- O
|
| O
therton O
— O
She O
wanders O
further O
, O
and O
meets O
with O
an O
adventure O
, O
but O
at O
|
| O
last O
returns O
in O
safety O
to O
her O
inn O
— O
A O
journey O
homeward O
, O
and O
a O
fact O
re- O
|
| O
lated O
without O
ornament O
....... O
+4 O
|

 

 

| O
viii O
CONTENTS O
, O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXV O
. O
|
| O
PAGE O
|
| O
The O
narrative O
returns O
to O
its O
hero O
— O
And O
relates O
why O
and O
wherefore O
he O
|

| O
was O
kept O
alive O
— O
The O
boy O
grows O
tall O
, O
and O
takes O
to O
thinking.essseessee O
278 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXVI O
. O
|

| O
‘ O
A O
dismal O
enterprise O
, O
and O
its O
melancholy O
result O
— O
Martha B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
pu- O
|
| O
nished O
more O
severely O
than O
she O
deserved O
— O
Very O
wild O
projects O
conceived O
|
| O
by O
Miss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
, O
and O
speedily O
put O
in O
execution O
... O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXVII O
. O
|

| O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
sets O
out O
upon O
a O
dangerous O
expedition O
— O
Its O
termi- O
|
| O
nation O
proves O
rather O
more O
than O
he O
can O
bear O
— O
He O
meets O
a O
good O
man O
|
| O
and O
takes O
service O
under O
him O
— O
He O
asks O
and O
obtains O
a O
holiday O
, O
and O
|

| O
289 B-CARDINAL
|

 

 

| O
meets O
several O
adventures O
in O
the O
course O
of O
it O
. O
stsessseaneecesereseesses O
207 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CHAPTER O
XXVIII O
. O
|
| O
An O
important O
interview O
— O
Doubts O
and O
fears O
« O
+ B-CARDINAL
821 I-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
CHAPTER O
XXIX O
. O
|
| O
Michael B-PERSON
calls O
his O
wisdom O
to O
council O
, O
and O
the O
points O
to O
be O
discussed O
puzzle O
|

 

 

| O
them O
— O
An O
early O
walk O
— O
An O
old O
friend O
with O
a O
changed O
face O
.... O
severe O
BSF B-ORG
|
| O
CHAPTER O
XXX O
. O
|
| O
Michael B-PERSON
grows O
rich O
, O
and O
takes O
very O
delightful O
walk O
back O
to O
Westmor- B-DATE
|
| O
land O
— O
His O
preparations O
for O
a O
longer O
journey O
are O
suddenly O
stopped O
— O
|
| O
He O
makes O
a O
painful O
visit O
, O
but O
meets O
many O
old O
acquaintances O
... O
. O
340 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXXI O
. O
|

| O
AA O
friendly O
consultation O
— O
A O
dangerous O
embassy O
— O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
receives O
|
| O
some O
disagreeable O
intelligence O
— O
An O
awkward O
contest O
— O
Unpleasant O
|
| O
visions O
— O
A O
fitting O
termination O
to O
the O
confidential O
union O
between O
|

| O
master O
and O
man O
... O
seeesseeereesenee O
BOF B-ORG
|

 

 

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XXXIl I-LAW
. I-LAW
|

| O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
gives O
his O
sister O
Martha B-PERSON
notice O
to O
quit O
the O
pre- O
|
| O
mises O
, O
which O
occasions O
Michael B-PERSON
to O
appear O
in O
a O
new O
character O
— O
A O
long O
|
| O
journey O
taken O
by O
novices O
, O
but O
they O
do O
not O
lose O
their O
way O
, O
and O
arrive O
|
| O
at O
the O
right O
place O
at O
last O
....... O
vee O
870 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CHAPTER O
XXXIII O
. O
|
| O
A O
tite O
- O
a O
- O
téte O
— O
A O
second B-ORDINAL
— O
A B-CARDINAL
third I-CARDINAL
— O
A O
mysterious O
result O
— O
Conclusion O
.... O
879 B-CARDINAL
|

 

 

| O
THE O
|

| O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
oF O
|

| O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
, O
|

| O
THE O
FACTORY O
BOW O
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
I. O
|

| O
DESCRIPTION O
OF O
DOWLING O
LODGE O
AND O
ITS O
APPURTENANCES O
— O
|
| O
OF O
ITS O
MASTER O
— O
OF O
ITS O
MISTRESS O
— O
AND O
ALL O
THE O
MASTERS O
AND O
|
| O
MISSES O
DOWLING O
— O
A O
LARGE O
DINNER O
- O
PARTY O
— O
A O
HOT O
DRAWING- O
|
| O
ROOM O
, O
AND O
THE O
WAY O
TO O
ESCAPE O
FROM O
It O
. O
|

 

| O
No O
traveller O
can O
ride O
or O
drive O
within O
sight O
of O
Dowling B-PERSON
Lodge I-PERSON
, O
|
| O
without O
being O
tempted O
to O
inquire O
, O
Whose O
house O
is O
that O
? O
” O
|

| O
It O
forms O
, O
indeed O
, O
a O
very O
striking O
object O
on O
the O
right O
of O
the O
London B-GPE
|
| O
road O
, O
as O
the O
hill O
rises O
gradually O
, O
and O
overlooks O
the O
town O
of O
Ashleigh B-GPE
, O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
busiest O
in O
Lancashire B-GPE
, O
to O
the O
left O
  O
for O
although O
thé B-PERSON
trees O
|
| O
about O
the O
mansion O
are O
not O
yet O
of O
sufficient O
growth O
to O
make O
it O
pic- O
|
| O
turesque O
, O
its O
lofty O
portico O
, O
well O
- O
proportioned O
wings O
, O
and O
command- O
|
| O
ing O
site O
, O
render O
it O
an O
ornament O
to O
the O
neighbourhood O
for O
miles B-CARDINAL
|
| O
round O
. O
|

| O
Those O
who O
are O
admitted O
to O
a O
nearer O
view O
of O
the O
house O
( O
and O
, O
for O
|
| O
the O
convenience O
of O
the O
public O
, O
every O
Wednesday B-DATE
is O
set O
apart O
for O
|
| O
its O
being O
shown O
) O
, O
will O
find O
still O
more O
to O
admire O
, O
than O
such O
as O
see O
it O
|
| O
only O
from O
a O
distance O
. O
It O
has O
its O
park O
and O
its O
pinery B-ORG
  O
conservatories O
, O
|
| O
which O
cause O
the O
merenry B-ORG
in O
the O
thermometer O
, O
when O
paraded O
through O
|
| O
them O
, O
to O
run O
up O
to O
the O
cocoa O
- O
ripening O
heat O
of O
the O
tropics O
, O
and O
ice- O
|
| O
houses O
that O
would O
bring O
it O
down O
again O
to O
the O
temperature O
of O
Bhering B-GPE
’s O
|
| O
Straits B-LOC
. O
It O
has O
three B-CARDINAL
drawing O
- O
rooms O
, O
two B-CARDINAL
dining O
- O
rooms O
, O
a O
great O
|
| O
library O
, O
all O
full O
of O
new O
books O
  O
as O
many O
bedrooms O
, O
dressing O
- O
rooms O
, O
|
| O
and O
boudoirs O
, O
as O
a O
great O
man O
’s O
house O
ought O
to O
have O
, O
and O
a O
study O
|
| O
hesides O
— O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
’s O
own O
private O
study O
. O
This O
de- O
|
| O
lightful O
little O
apartment O
is O
small O
, O
not O
more B-QUANTITY
than I-QUANTITY
twelve I-QUANTITY
feet I-QUANTITY
square I-QUANTITY
  O
|
| O
but O
nothing O
can O
be O
more O
agreeable O
and O
convenient O
. O
It O
opens O
by O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
door O
from O
the O
great O
hall O
of O
entrance O
, O
and O
by O
another O
commu- O
|

| O
B O
|

| O
2 B-CARDINAL
THE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
nicates O
through O
a O
long O
stone O
- O
passage O
with O
the O
offices O
of O
the O
mansion O
  O
|
| O
enabling O
the O
knight O
to O
receive O
, O
without O
interruption O
, O
not O
only O
his O
|
| O
overlookers O
( O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
being O
the O
proprietor O
of O
many O
cotton O
- O
mills O
) O
, O
|
| O
but O
his O
coachman O
, O
gardener O
, O
bailiff O
, O
and O
whomever O
else O
he O
might O
|
| O
wish O
to O
transact O
business O
with O
. O
|

| O
Of O
the O
fitting O
up O
of O
this O
princely O
mansion O
, O
it O
is O
only O
necessary O
to O
|
| O
say O
, O
that O
it O
is O
done O
in O
a O
spirit O
of O
emulative O
imitation O
, O
which O
ren- O
|
| O
ders O
it O
fully O
equal O
, O
in O
this O
respect O
, O
to O
the O
most O
finished O
private O
|
| O
dwellings O
in O
Europe B-LOC
. O
‘ O
The O
furniture O
is O
uniformly O
rich O
throughout O
: O
|
| O
the O
picture O
- O
frames O
in O
the O
best O
style O
of O
art O
  O
Saxony B-GPE
carpets O
in O
the O
|
| O
drawing O
- O
rooms O
, O
Turkey B-GPE
ditto O
in O
the O
dining O
- O
rooms O
, O
Brussels B-GPE
in O
the O
|
| O
bedrooms O
, O
and O
indeed O
not O
a O
single O
inch O
of O
Kidderminster B-GPE
any O
|
| O
where O
, O
except O
in O
the O
garrets O
. O
|

| O
I O
will O
not O
attempt O
to O
state O
the O
amount O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
’s O
|
| O
wealth O
  O
Cocker B-PERSON
himself O
would O
have O
found O
it O
a O
laborious O
task O
to O
|
| O
make O
the O
calculation O
  O
and O
it O
is O
sufficient O
for O
the O
gratification O
of O
all O
|
| O
reasonable O
curiosity O
to O
say O
, O
that O
throughout O
the O
whole O
line O
of O
that O
|
| O
Golconda B-ORG
country O
, O
which O
, O
being O
the O
busiest O
of O
the O
manufacturing O
|
| O
districts O
, O
is O
probably O
the O
richest O
in O
the O
world O
, O
there O
was O
not O
any O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
who O
could O
vie O
in O
wealth O
with O
him O
. O
Ina B-PERSON
word O
, O
he O
shone O
amidst O
his O
|
| O
rich O
neighbours O
like O
a B-LOC
golden I-LOC
sun I-LOC
, O
surrounded O
by O
silver O
moons O
. O
|

| O
But O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
was O
a O
superior O
man O
in O
all O
ways O
. O
He O
was O
six B-QUANTITY
|
| I-QUANTITY
feet I-QUANTITY
two I-QUANTITY
inches I-QUANTITY
in O
height O
, O
and O
stout O
in O
proportion O
, O
with O
hands O
and O
|
| O
feet O
that O
might O
have O
sufficed O
a O
giant O
. O
His O
intellectual O
gifts O
were O
|
| O
also O
of O
no O
ordinary O
character O
, O
He O
liked O
well O
enough O
, O
perhaps O
, O
to O
|
| O
stand O
pre O
- O
eminent O
in O
the O
commercial O
estimation O
of O
his O
neighbours O
  O
|
| O
but O
so O
enlightened O
was O
his O
spirit O
, O
that O
he O
liked O
better O
still O
to O
shine O
be- O
° O
|
| O
fore O
their O
eyes O
as O
aman O
of O
taste O
, O
a O
literary O
and O
accomplished O
gentle- O
|
| O
man O
, O
a O
speaker O
of O
modern O
languages O
, O
a O
critical O
French B-NORP
scholar O
, O
a O
|
| O
playful O
votary O
of O
the O
muses O
himself O
, O
and O
a O
universal O
Meceenas B-PERSON
to O
all O
|
| O
who O
wielded O
a O
pen O
in O
their O
service O
. O
But O
beyond O
all O
else O
, O
Sir O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
valued O
himself O
upon O
his O
reputation O
for O
the O
lighter O
graces O
of O
|
| O
wit O
and O
gallantry O
: O
he O
sought O
to O
make O
himself O
into O
something O
of O
|||| O
|
| O
a O
delightful O
mixture O
between O
Killigrew B-PERSON
and O
the O
Count O
de O
Gra- O
|
| O
mont O
  O
and O
there O
was O
no O
receptacle O
of O
wit O
from O
Joe B-PERSON
Miller I-PERSON
downwards O
, O
|
| O
no O
gallant O
memoirs O
in O
an O
intelligible O
tongue O
, O
that O
he O
did O
not O
study O
|
| O
with O
assiduity O
and O
perseveraiice O
of O
the O
highest O
order O
. O
|

| O
He O
was O
often O
heard O
to O
declare O
, O
that O
he O
loved O
nothing O
so O
well O
as O
|
| O
the O
promotion O
of O
mirth O
and O
light O
- O
heartedness O
among O
his O
fellow- O
|
| O
creatures O
  O
but O
tragedy O
and O
comedy O
often O
walk O
through O
the O
: O
|
| O
world O
hand O
in O
hand O
together O
, O
and O
their O
alliance O
may O
be O
traced O
|
| O
without O
difficulty O
in O
the O
career O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
. O
|

| O
The O
wife O
of O
this O
prosperous O
gentleman O
had O
also O
many O
admirable O
! O
|
| O
qualities O
. O
She O
was O
not O
one O
of O
the O
idle O
gossipers O
who O
delight O
in O
|
| O
chattering O
about O
their O
own O
concerns O
to O
every O
one O
who O
will O
listen O
  O
  O
|
| O
she O
despised O
such O
weakness O
, O
and O
had O
never O
been O
heard O
to O
atl O
) O
|
| O
her O
own O
parentage O
, O
or O
early O
history O
, O
to O
any O
one O
  O
rightly O
considering O
, O
, O
|
| O
that O
when O
such O
matters O
are O
unceasingly O
discussed O
, O
they O
may O
be O
ex- O
|
| O
ceedingly O
likely O
to O
prevent O
people O
’s O
minding O
their O
own O
business O
, O
|
| O
while O
devoting O
an O
undue O
share O
of O
attention O
to O
that O
of O
others O
. O
|

  
   
 
 
 
 
   
   

 

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
« O
3 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
Nevertheless O
, O
with O
nice O
and O
laudable O
discrimination O
, O
she O
took O
care O
|
| O
that O
her O
neighbours O
should O
be O
well O
acquainted O
with O
all O
such O
facts O
|
| O
respecting O
her O
as O
it O
concerned O
them O
to O
know O
. O
There O
was O
hardly O
an O
|
| O
individual O
within O
ten B-QUANTITY
miles I-QUANTITY
who O
was O
not O
aware O
that O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Kept I-PERSON
two B-CARDINAL
carriages O
, O
six B-CARDINAL
horses O
, O
one B-CARDINAL
coachman O
, O
one B-CARDINAL
postilion O
, O
five B-CARDINAL
|
| O
gardeners O
, O
two B-CARDINAL
grooms O
, O
three B-CARDINAL
footmen O
, O
one B-CARDINAL
butler O
, O
and O
a O
page O
— O
|
| O
not O
to O
mention O
two B-CARDINAL
nurses O
, O
four B-CARDINAL
nursery O
- O
maids O
, O
and O
more O
ladies’= B-ORG
|
| O
maids O
, O
housemaids O
, O
cookmaids O
, O
kitchen O
- O
maids O
, O
laundry O
- O
maids O
, O
still- O
|
| O
room O
maids O
, O
dairy O
- O
maids O
, O
and O
the O
like O
, O
than O
any O
other O
lady O
in O
the O
|
| O
county O
. O
Neither O
could O
any O
be O
ignorant O
that O
, O
except O
in O
the O
article O
|
| O
of O
jewels O
, O
her O
wardrobe O
might O
vie O
with O
that O
of O
any O
duchess O
in O
the O
|
| O
land O
, O
and O
all O
might O
see O
, O
moreover O
, O
that O
she O
was O
comely O
still O
, O
both O
|
| O
in O
form O
and O
feature O
. O
She O
conversed O
with O
great O
ability O
on O
all O
sub- O
|
| O
jects O
connected O
with O
fashionable O
life O
  O
and O
though O
some O
few O
carping O
|
| O
critics O
thought O
that O
she O
was O
too O
apt O
to O
diversify O
the O
monotony O
of O
the O
|
| O
English B-LANGUAGE
language O
, O
by O
indulging O
in O
some O
remarkable O
variations O
from O
|
| O
its O
ordinary O
laws O
, O
nobody O
, O
or O
scarcely O
any O
body O
, O
attempted O
to O
deny O
|
| O
that O
she O
was O
on O
the O
whole O
a O
very O
charming O
woman O
. O
Such O
was O
the O
|
| O
testimony O
of O
her O
general O
acquaintance O
  O
those O
who O
knew O
her O
better O
|
| O
were O
aware O
that O
her O
moral O
qualities O
outshone O
, O
as O
they O
always O
ought O
|
| O
to O
do O
, O
all O
her O
external O
graces O
. O
She O
was O
a O
faithful O
and O
exceedingly O
|
| O
fond O
wife O
, O
and O
doted O
upon O
all O
her O
children O
  O
no O
woman O
could O
more O
|
| O
heartily O
detest O
every O
species O
of O
light O
flirting O
airs O
in O
females O
, O
and O
, O
|
| O
being O
deeply O
sensible O
of O
the O
dangerous O
attractions O
of O
youth O
and O
|
| O
beauty O
in O
her O
own O
sex O
, O
she O
studiously O
avoided O
bringing O
those O
of O
|
| O
her O
family O
who O
might O
suffer O
thereby O
from O
coming O
in O
contact O
with O
|

| O
* O
any O
thing O
of O
the O
kind O
  O
so O
that O
the O
female O
portion O
of O
her O
establish O
|
| O
ment O
consisted O
of O
the O
ugliest O
set O
of O
neat O
and O
carefully O
dressed O
|
| O
middle O
- O
aged O
women O
that O
ever O
were O
found O
assembled O
together O
. O
|

| O
The O
knight O
and O
his O
excellent O
lady O
were O
blessed O
with O
a O
very O
|
| O
numerous O
progeny O
, O
certainly O
not O
less B-CARDINAL
than I-CARDINAL
eighteen I-CARDINAL
or I-CARDINAL
twenty O
  O
but O
, O
|
| O
as O
they O
were O
rarely O
all O
at O
home O
together O
, O
it O
was O
at O
no O
time O
easy O
to O
|
| O
count O
them O
, O
|

| O
Augustus B-PERSON
, O
the O
eldest O
of O
the O
family O
, O
was O
a O
prodigiously O
fine O
young O
|
| O
man O
, O
just O
returned O
from O
college O
. O
He O
had O
not O
indeed O
thought O
it O
|
| O
necessary O
to O
take O
a O
degree O
, O
nor O
did O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
or O
her O
ladyship O
|
| O
particularly O
wish O
it O
  O
both O
of O
them O
being O
of O
opinion O
that O
little O
dis- O
|
| O
tinction O
could O
be O
gained O
by O
the O
assumption O
of O
a O
title O
which O
was O
never O
|
| O
used O
in O
society O
, O
and O
to O
which O
he O
conceived O
every O
Englishman O
to O
be O
|
| O
eligible O
who O
could O
just O
read O
and O
write O
alittle O
. O
But O
as O
, O
on.all B-CARDINAL
points O
|
| O
that O
concemed O
the O
interest O
of O
his O
eldest O
son O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
was O
too O
|
| O
deeply O
interested O
to O
run O
any O
risk O
of O
blundering O
: O
he O
did O
not O
give O
his O
|
| O
consent O
for O
the O
return O
of O
Augustus B-PERSON
, O
without O
his O
having O
gone O
through O
|
| O
this O
idle O
academic O
ceremony O
, O
till O
he O
had O
paid O
a O
visit O
to O
the O
rector O
|
| O
of O
his O
parish O
, O
to O
elicit O
from O
him O
some O
information O
on O
the O
subject O
. O
|

| O
May B-DATE
I O
ask O
, O
sir O
, O
” O
said O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
abruptly O
, O
“ O
« O
what O
degree O
you O
|
| O
took O
at O
the O
university O
? O
” O
|

| O
Mr. O
Hetherington B-PERSON
was O
a O
new O
incumbent O
, O
and O
might O
, O
perhaps O
, O
have O
|
| O
been O
a O
little O
affronted O
at O
a O
question O
which O
, O
by O
the O
blunt O
manner O
of O
|
| O
it O
, O
seemed O
almost O
to O
insinuate O
a O
doubt O
whether O
he O
had O
taken O
any O
|

| O
B2 O
|

| O
= O
THE O
LIPE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
degree O
at O
all O
  O
but O
, O
though O
a O
good O
man O
, O
and O
an O
excellent O
clergyman O
|
| O
to O
boot O
, O
he O
had O
a O
strong O
taste O
for O
humour O
, O
and O
had O
already O
dis- O
|
| O
covered O
that O
his O
neighbour O
at O
the O
great O
house O
was O
rich O
in O
more O
|
| O
ways O
than O
one O
. O
It O
was O
, O
therefore O
, O
with O
the O
utmost O
civility O
that O
he O
|
| O
answered O
, O
“ O
‘ O
My O
degree O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
was O
that O
of O
Master B-ORG
of I-ORG
Arts I-ORG
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
And O
pray O
, O
sir O
, O
does O
it O
give O
you O
any O
title O
by O
which O
you O
can O
be O
|
| O
distinguished O
as O
in O
any O
way O
a O
superior O
sort O
of O
person O
in O
society O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Tam B-PERSON
afraid O
not O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
” O
was O
the O
reply O
. O
|

| O
“ O
T O
thank O
you O
, O
sir O
, O
for O
your O
sincerity O
, O
” O
rejoined O
the O
knight O
. O
« O
It O
|
| O
‘ O
was O
important O
that O
I O
should O
ascertain O
the O
truth O
on O
this O
point.—You O
|
| O
are O
, O
then O
, O
never O
addressed O
in O
company O
as O
: O
Mr. O
Master B-PERSON
of I-PERSON
Arts I-PERSON
, O
or O
|
| O
any O
thing O
of O
that O
kind O
2 O
” O
= O
a2 O
. O
|

| O
« O
Thave O
never O
yet O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
met O
with O
any O
one O
of O
sufficient O
|
| O
politeness O
to O
do O
me O
that O
honour O
, O
” O
replied O
Mr. O
Hetherington B-PERSON
gravely O
. O
|

| O
“ O
And O
I O
suppose O
you O
have O
lived O
in O
respectable O
society O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Very O
decent O
society O
— O
very O
decent O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
” O
replied O
|
| O
Hetherington B-ORG
, O
whose O
mother O
was O
the O
daughter O
of O
a O
distinguished O
|
| O
nobleman O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Good O
morning O
, O
sir O
  O
I O
shall O
be O
happy O
to O
see O
you O
at O
Dowling B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
— O
that O
is O
to O
say O
, O
sir O
, O
if O
your O
gown O
does O
not O
lead O
you O
to O
object O
|
| O
to O
elegant O
amusements O
. O
I O
love O
science O
, O
Mr. O
Hetherington B-PERSON
, O
and O
am O
|
| O
indeed O
devoted O
to O
every O
thing O
intellectual O
  O
but O
, O
notwithstanding O
|
| O
this O
, O
I O
am O
a O
worshipper O
at O
the O
shrine O
of O
grace O
and O
wit O
, O
and O
could O
|
| O
not O
exist O
among O
people O
who O
did O
not O
relish O
the O
lighter O
embellish- O
|
| O
ments O
of O
society O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
T O
shall O
be O
ST O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
to O
share O
in O
your O
gayer O
hours O
, O
|
| O
provided O
I O
am O
fortunate O
enough O
to O
find O
that O
you O
have O
no O
objection O
|
| O
to O
profit O
by O
my O
graver O
ones O
, O
” O
replied O
the O
clergyman O
. O
|

| O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
returned O
from O
this O
visit O
very O
well O
pleased O
with O
the O
|
| O
new O
rector O
. O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
was O
immediately O
comforted O
by O
a O
letter O
, O
|
| O
informing O
him O
that O
he O
might O
call O
in O
his O
accounts O
, O
and O
prepare O
to O
|
| O
leave O
the O
university O
as O
soon O
as O
he O
pleased O
  O
and O
, O
within O
ten B-DATE
days I-DATE
|
| O
after O
receiving O
it O
, O
the O
amiable O
young O
man O
was O
restored O
to O
the O
bosom O
|
| O
of O
his O
family O
. O
|

| O
Next O
to O
this O
primal O
hope O
of O
the O
Dowling B-PERSON
race O
, O
came O
three B-CARDINAL
young O
|
| O
ladigs O
, O
between B-DATE
the I-DATE
ages I-DATE
of I-DATE
. O
seventeen B-CARDINAL
and I-CARDINAL
twenty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
one I-CARDINAL
  O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
|
| O
eldest O
of O
thiem O
being O
as O
like O
as O
two O
peas O
, O
and O
the O
third B-ORDINAL
like O
nothing O
|
| O
‘ O
on O
earth O
but O
herself O
. O
Then O
followed O
several O
young O
gentlemen O
, O
|
| O
who O
were O
placed O
at O
different O
fashionable O
schools O
  O
for O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
who O
was O
a O
man O
of O
very O
enlarged O
mind O
, O
declared O
it O
to O
be O
his O
opinion O
|
| O
and O
his O
principle O
  O
that O
the O
patronage O
of O
such O
a O
fortune O
as O
his O
should O
|
| O
be O
extended O
as O
widely O
as O
possible O
. O
After O
these O
young O
gentlemen O
|
| O
came O
, O
one O
after O
the O
other O
, O
with O
the O
interval O
of O
about B-DATE
eleven I-DATE
months I-DATE
|
| O
between O
them O
, O
ever O
so O
many O
little O
girls O
, O
who O
, O
for O
the O
present O
, O
were O
|
| O
all O
educated O
at O
home O
, O
having O
a O
particularly O
clever O
French B-NORP
governess O
. O
|
| O
All O
the O
rest O
were O
nice O
little O
children O
of O
different O
degrees O
of O
baby- O
|
| O
hood O
  O
the O
dear O
little O
girls O
being O
remarkable O
for O
their O
long O
plaited O
|
| O
hair O
, O
short O
frocks O
, O
and O
furbelowed O
trousers O
, O
and O
the O
dear O
little O
boys O
|
| O
for O
the O
manly O
, O
bustle O
with O
which O
they O
wore O
their O
Scotch B-NORP
bonnets O
and O
|
| O
plaided O
tunics O
, O
which O
, O
considering O
that O
neither O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
nor O
his O
|

| O
‘ O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
5 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
lady O
had O
ever O
been O
in O
Scotland B-GPE
in O
their O
lives O
, O
showed O
great O
enlarge- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
national O
feeling O
. O
Altogether O
, O
it O
was O
considered O
to O
be O
the O
|
| O
finest O
family O
ever O
seen O
. O
|

| O
It O
happened O
upon O
a O
broiling O
day O
about O
the B-DATE
middle I-DATE
of I-DATE
July I-DATE
, O
during O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the B-DATE
hottest I-DATE
summers I-DATE
England B-GPE
had O
ever O
known O
, O
that O
Sir O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
and O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
“ O
entertained O
a O
party O
of O
distinguished O
|
| O
fashionables O
” O
at O
dinner O
. O
|

| O
It O
may O
have O
been O
remarked O
by O
those.who O
study O
such O
subjects O
, O
|
| O
that O
there O
is O
a O
difference O
between O
a O
dinner O
- O
party O
given O
at O
such O
a O
|
| O
grand O
mansion O
as O
that O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
. O
Dowling B-PERSON
, O
and O
one O
at O
, O
a.dwell- O
|
| O
ing O
of O
perhaps O
not O
a O
quarter O
the O
size O
, O
where O
the O
owners O
are O
of O
a O
dif- O
|
| O
ferent O
order O
of O
the O
aristocracy O
, O
having O
a O
longer O
pedigree O
, O
and O
a O
|
| O
shorter O
purse O
. O
At O
both O
, O
probably O
, O
the O
banquet O
will O
be O
a O
costly O
one O
, O
|
| O
yet O
the O
one B-CARDINAL
entertainment O
will O
come O
off O
in.a O
manner O
as.unlike O
as O
|
| O
possible O
to O
the O
other O
. O
There O
is O
something O
in O
the O
usual O
way.of B-ORG
wearing O
|
| O
stiff O
new O
- O
made O
grandeur O
, O
not O
far O
unlike O
that O
of O
wearing O
stiff O
new- O
|
| O
made O
clothes O
. O
Neither O
the O
one’nor O
the O
other O
sit O
easily O
. O
F O
|

| O
At O
this O
splendid O
dinner O
at O
Dowling B-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
, O
the O
company O
consisted O
|
| O
of O
a O
selection O
from O
the O
neighbouring O
families O
, O
made O
on O
the O
most.le- B-LOC
|
| O
gitimate O
principles O
of O
exclusiveness O
  O
no O
family O
being O
invited O
who O
|
| O
did O
not O
drive O
four B-CARDINAL
horses O
at O
the O
races O
. O
To O
this O
there O
were O
indeed O
|
| O
two B-CARDINAL
exceptions O
. O
The O
first B-ORDINAL
was O
the O
Right O
Honourable O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Shrimpton I-PERSON
  O
but O
this O
distinguished O
lady O
, O
though.she O
drove O
only B-CARDINAL
one I-CARDINAL
|
| O
pony O
instead O
of O
four B-CARDINAL
horses O
, O
was O
considered O
by O
all O
the O
country O
|
| O
round O
as O
the O
one B-CARDINAL
thing O
needful O
to O
render O
a O
party O
completely O
elegant O
. O
|
| O
She O
was O
, O
indeed O
, O
neither O
young O
, O
handsome O
, O
nor O
rich O
, O
but O
she O
was O
|
| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
, O
and O
this O
was O
enough O
. O
|

| O
The O
other O
exception O
was O
to O
be O
found O
in O
the O
rotund O
person O
of O
Dr. O
|
| O
Crockley O
, O
who O
having O
formerly O
been O
a O
celebrated O
quack O
, O
.made O
a O
|
| O
little O
fortune O
, O
and O
taken O
out O
a O
diploma O
, O
had O
lately O
married O
a O
beauty O
, O
|
| O
and O
settled O
in O
the O
town O
of O
Ashleigh B-PERSON
, O
where O
he O
was O
well O
pleased O
to O
|
| O
pick O
up O
a O
few O
guinea O
fees O
, O
both O
as O
a O
public O
evidence O
of O
his O
being O
a O
|
| O
real O
M.D. B-PERSON
, O
and O
asa O
private O
fund O
wherewith O
to O
indulge O
his O
still O
|
| O
very O
tender O
passion O
, O
by O
buying O
finery O
for O
his O
pretty O
young O
wife O
. O
|

| O
‘ O
This O
fat O
little O
gentleman O
was O
an O
especial O
favourite O
with O
Sir O
Mat- O
|
| O
thew B-PERSON
, O
chiefly O
on O
account O
of O
his O
jocund O
humour O
and O
ready O
laugh O
  O
|
| O
and O
also O
, O
perhaps O
, O
because O
he O
had O
a O
pleasant O
way O
, O
peculiar O
to O
him- O
|
| O
self O
, O
of O
paying O
compliments O
in O
the O
bluntest O
and O
, O
most O
unstudied O
|
| O
manner O
possible O
. O
  O
|

| O
But O
, O
notwithstanding O
the O
presence O
of O
all O
. O
these O
distinguished O
per- O
|
| O
sons O
, O
the O
dinner O
moved O
on O
very O
slowly O
. O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
indeed O
, O
was O
|
| O
as O
brilliant O
as O
it O
was O
possible O
for O
any O
man O
to O
be O
under O
the O
circum- O
|
| O
Stances O
, O
and O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
who O
did O
not O
scruple O
to O
declare O
that O
she O
|
| O
Was O
very O
partial O
to O
him O
, O
-listened O
to O
all O
he O
said O
to O
her O
with O
as O
much O
|
| O
attention O
at O
east O
as O
any O
lady O
could O
be O
expected O
to O
do O
, O
who O
was O
|
| O
making O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
sixteen B-CARDINAL
at O
a O
dinner O
, O
where O
there O
were O
an O
equal O
num- O
|
| O
ber O
of O
dishes O
of O
hot O
meats O
reeking O
upon O
the O
table O
, O
and O
the O
thermo- O
|
| O
meter O
standing O
at O
87 B-QUANTITY
° I-QUANTITY
. O
Dr. O
Crockley B-PERSON
, O
too O
, O
laughed O
repeatedly O
  O
|
| O
but O
his O
laugh O
was O
like O
a O
Lucifer B-PERSON
match O
that O
fails O
, O
just O
kindling O
and O
|

| O
6 O
. O
THE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
see O
a O
little O
, O
but O
going O
out O
before O
it O
is O
able O
to O
communicate O
its O
|
| O
ight O
. O
|

| O
The O
very O
sight O
of O
the O
servants O
as O
they O
panted O
round O
the O
table O
, O
|
| O
was O
quite O
enough O
to O
smother O
and O
stifle O
all O
inclination O
for O
enjoyment O
|
| O
— O
their O
shoes O
creaked O
— O
their O
faces O
shone O
— O
ice O
became O
water O
— O
the O
|
| O
salad O
looked O
as O
if O
it O
were O
stewed O
— O
the O
cucumbers O
seemed O
to O
have O
|
| O
fainted O
away O
— O
the O
prodigious O
turbot O
smelt O
fishy O
, O
and O
its O
attendant O
|
| O
lobster O
- O
sauce O
glowed O
not O
with O
a O
deeper O
tint O
, O
than O
did O
my O
Lady O
Dow- O
|
| O
ling O
’s O
cheeks O
as O
her O
nose O
caught O
the O
unfragrant O
gale O
. O
In O
short O
, O
|
| O
it O
was O
a O
great O
dinner O
in O
the O
dog O
- O
days O
, O
and O
no O
more O
need O
be O
said O
of O
|
| O
it O
, O
|

| O
Great O
was O
the O
inward O
satisfaction O
of O
every O
guest O
, O
when O
at O
last O
|
| O
Lady O
Dowling B-PERSON
rose O
, O
and O
gave O
signal O
that O
the O
party O
was O
to O
be O
|
| O
divided O
in O
half B-CARDINAL
. O
The O
languid O
ladies O
welcomed O
the O
coolness O
of O
the O
|
| O
marble O
hall O
as O
they O
passed O
through O
it O
, O
and O
the O
gentlemen O
gazed O
|
| O
eagerly O
at O
the O
butler O
as O
he O
brought O
forward O
a O
fresh O
supply O
of O
claret O
, O
|
| O
and O
a O
reinforcement O
of O
ice O
. O
But O
the O
enjoyment O
of O
neither O
party O
|
| O
lasted O
long O
  O
for O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
was O
too O
grand O
and O
too O
solemn O
not O
|
| O
to O
marshal O
all O
her O
company O
into O
her O
fine O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
where O
they O
|
| O
were O
all O
ceremoniously O
deposited O
on O
satin O
sofas O
, O
amidst O
swelling O
|
| O
pillows O
that O
might O
have O
defied O
the O
frosts O
of O
January B-DATE
  O
while O
seven B-CARDINAL
or O
|
| O
eight B-CARDINAL
hot O
- O
looking O
children O
were O
commanded O
to O
walk O
round O
the O
circle O
|
| O
and O
kiss O
every O
body O
. O
|

| O
Nor O
did O
the O
gentlemen O
fare O
much O
better O
  O
for O
scarcely O
had O
the O
|
| O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
closed O
after O
the O
ladies O
, O
before O
the O
shining O
bald- O
|
| O
head O
of O
Dr. O
Crockley B-PERSON
stretched O
itself O
up O
nearly O
to O
a O
level O
with O
the O
|
| O
long O
- O
backed O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
's O
breast O
- O
pin O
, O
whilst O
, O
with O
a O
very O
ominous O
|
| O
sort O
of O
growl O
, O
making O
itself O
heard O
before O
his O
lips O
opened O
, O
he O
first B-ORDINAL
|
| O
preluded O
, O
and O
then O
uttered O
the O
following O
speech O
. O
|

| O
“ O
JT B-PERSON
do O
n’t O
like O
it O
, O
Sir O
Matthew.—I O
do O
n’t O
like O
this O
business O
at O
the O
|
| O
‘ O
Weavers B-WORK_OF_ART
’ I-WORK_OF_ART
Arms I-WORK_OF_ART
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
What O
business O
, O
Doctor O
? O
” O
replied O
his O
friend O
sharply O
. O
|

| O
« O
Why O
this O
meeting O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
. O
I O
ca O
n’t O
get O
the O
notion O
of O
a O
strike O
|
| O
out O
of O
my O
head O
. O
” O
Every O
chair O
was O
drawn O
towards O
the O
little O
doctor O
: O
no- O
|
| O
body O
had O
heard O
a O
word O
of O
it O
. O
“ O
Well O
, O
gentlemen O
, O
perhaps O
I O
am O
mis- O
|
| O
taken O
— O
perhaps O
there O
has O
been O
no O
meeting O
, O
” O
resumed O
the O
friendly O
|
| O
doctor O
. O
“ O
God O
knows O
, O
I O
do O
n’t O
wish O
to O
spoil O
the O
enjoyment O
of O
this O
|
| O
delightful O
hour O
  O
but O
at O
any O
rate O
, O
my O
good O
friends O
, O
it O
is O
as O
well O
for O
|
| O
you O
to O
be O
on O
the O
look O
- O
out O
. O
” O
Then O
lowering O
his O
voice O
, O
he O
muttered O
, O
|
| O
as O
near O
to O
the O
ear O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
as O
he O
could O
reach O
, O
“ O
I O
know O
that O
|
| O
your O
people O
are O
meeting O
, O
in O
doors O
and O
out O
of O
doors O
. O
But O
you O
are O
|
| O
such O
a O
good O
, O
generous O
, O
kind O
- O
hearted O
creature O
, O
that O
I O
dare O
say O
we O
|
| O
shall O
hear O
, O
before O
long O
, O
of O
your O
having O
done O
some O
d O
— O
d O
good- O
|
| O
natured O
thing O
or O
other O
, O
and O
that O
perhaps O
will O
set O
all O
right O
  O
who O
|
| O
knows O
? O
” O
|

| O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
gave O
an O
almost O
imperceptible O
nod O
, O
and O
pushed O
on O
|
| O
the O
claret O
- O
jug O
  O
but O
the O
gaiety O
of O
the O
party O
had O
been O
effectually O
|
| O
checked O
, O
and O
it O
was O
not O
long O
before O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
richest O
man O
in O
com- O
|
| O
pany O
( O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
of O
course O
being O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
) O
said O
, O
“ O
Ido B-PERSON
think O
and O
|

 

 

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
believe O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
that O
my O
lady O
’s O
coffee O
would O
do O
more O
to O
cool O
|
| O
us O
than O
your O
wine O
. O
” O
The O
opinion O
was O
not O
opposed O
, O
and O
, O
much O
|
| O
earlier O
than O
usual O
, O
the O
gentlemen O
rose O
, O
and O
followed O
the O
ladies O
. O
|

| O
But O
this O
movement O
did O
not O
appear O
greatly O
to O
increase O
the O
enjoy- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
either O
party O
. O
It O
was O
near O
nine B-TIME
o’clock I-TIME
, O
but O
the O
heat O
con- O
|
| O
tinued O
to O
be O
most O
oppressive O
, O
and O
the O
company O
being O
for O
the O
most O
|
| O
part O
massive O
in O
all O
ways O
, O
their O
union O
produced O
more O
additional O
ca- O
|
| O
loric O
than O
gaiety O
. O
The O
whole O
process O
seemed O
to O
have O
the O
power O
of O
|
| O
turning O
the B-TIME
hours I-TIME
into O
molten O
lead O
as O
they O
passed O
, O
a O
portion O
|
| O
of O
which O
appeared O
to O
drop O
, O
and O
weigh O
heavily O
on O
each O
individual O
|
| O
head O
. O
In O
vain O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
made O
the O
circuit O
of O
the O
company O
, O
|
| O
pausing O
in O
front O
either O
of O
the O
richest O
or O
handsomest O
ladies O
, O
as O
duty O
|
| O
or O
inclination O
? O
preponderated O
  O
in O
vain O
he O
uttered O
his O
newest O
puns O
|
| O
and O
freshest O
bon O
- O
mots O
— O
not O
one O
of O
them O
had O
strength O
to O
laugh O
, O
|
| O
beyond O
a O
little O
feeble O
“ O
he O
, O
he O
! O
” O
and O
even O
that O
was O
evidently O
a O
|
| O
painful O
effort O
. O
|

| O
‘ O
Things O
were O
in O
this O
state O
, O
when O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
Shrimpton I-PERSON
suddenly O
_ O
|

| O
rose O
from O
the O
silken O
couch O
amidst O
whose O
pillows O
she O
was O
im- O
|
| O
bedded O
, O
and O
, O
without O
explaining O
her O
intentions O
to O
my O
Lady O
Dowling B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
or O
any O
one O
else O
, O
darted O
through O
the O
open O
French B-NORP
- O
window O
, O
and O
out O
|
| O
upon O
the O
well O
- O
shaven O
lawn O
. O
|

| O
Had O
it O
been O
possible O
that O
any O
one“in O
the O
room O
could O
have O
been O
|
| O
ignorant O
of O
the O
rank O
of O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
, O
he O
must O
from O
that O
moment O
. O
|
| O
have O
feltan B-GPE
innate O
conviction O
that O
she O
was O
somebody O
  O
for O
nobody O
that O
|
| O
was O
not O
somebody O
could O
have O
ventured O
upon O
so O
daring O
an O
escapade O
|
| O
from O
suchi B-GPE
a O
solemn O
presence O
- O
chamber O
. O
’ O
The O
effect O
it O
produced O
was O
|
| O
electric O
. O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
darted O
across O
the O
room O
with O
the O
eagerness O
of O
a O
|
| O
man O
of O
gallantry O
and O
gaiety O
. O
He O
piqued O
himself O
upon O
being O
, O
of O
all O
the O
|
| O
great O
men O
in O
the O
neighbourhood O
, O
the O
one O
upon O
whom O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
|
| O
bestowed O
the O
most O
attention O
. O
His O
estimate O
of O
the O
outward O
advan- O
|
| O
tages O
of O
his O
extensive O
person O
was O
indeed O
not O
a O
low O
one O
  O
and O
, O
despite O
|
| O
all O
his O
lady O
could O
do O
to O
crush O
such O
an O
odious O
idea O
, O
he O
was O
conscious O
|
| O
that O
he O
was O
devoted O
to O
the O
fair O
sex O
, O
and O
flattered O
himself O
that'the O
|
| O
fair O
sex O
was O
not O
ungratéful O
. O
In O
fact O
, O
his O
general O
manner O
to O
ladies O
|
| O
had O
a O
good O
deal O
of O
what O
in O
female O
slang O
is O
called O
swaining O
  O
but O
to O
|
| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
it O
was O
certainly O
something O
more O
. O
Had O
she O
been O
simply O
|
| O
Miss O
Shrimpton B-PERSON
, O
it O
is O
probable O
that O
, O
notwithstanding O
her O
great O
|
| O
mental O
advantages O
, O
she O
would O
never O
have O
been O
exposed O
to O
the O
|
| O
danger O
of O
this O
fascinating O
distinction O
, O
for O
she O
was O
nearly B-DATE
forty I-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
old I-DATE
, O
had O
a O
sharp O
nose O
, O
and O
was O
deplorably O
thi O
, O
But O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
not O
a O
man O
to O
be O
insensible O
to O
the O
charm O
of O
getting O
talked O
of O
in O
|
| O
the O
neighbourhood O
about O
his O
devotion O
to O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
- O
any O
body O
, O
|
| O
even O
had O
she O
been O
a O
skeleton O
with O
a'Gorgon B-ORG
’s O
head O
. O
There O
was O
, O
|
| O
however O
, O
independently O
of O
her O
bewitching O
title O
, O
a O
charm O
in O
her O
con O
|
| O
yersation O
and O
character O
, O
to O
which O
the O
knight O
was O
peculiarly O
sensible O
. O
|
| O
Her O
ladyship O
was O
celebrated O
for O
her O
devotion O
both O
to O
literature O
and O
|
| O
art O
5 B-QUANTITY
oe I-QUANTITY
permitted O
all O
the O
world O
to’know O
, O
for O
indeed O
she O
never O
|
| O
ceased O
to O
repeat O
it O
, O
that O
talent O
of O
every O
kind O
was O
to O
her O
an O
object O
of O
|
| O
idolatry O
. O
Now O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
knew O
that O
he O
was O
full O
of O
talent O
— O
poe- O
|

| O
8 B-CARDINAL
THE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
tical O
talent O
, O
pictorial O
talent O
, O
epigrammatic O
talent O
, O
every O
kind O
of O
talent O
, O
|
| O
and O
it O
was O
certainly O
very O
delightful O
to O
be O
appreciated O
by O
such O
a O
|
| O
superior O
creature O
as O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
. O
So O
strongly O
indeed O
did O
this O
|
| O
intellectual O
sympathy O
between O
them O
occasionally O
manifest O
itself O
, O
|
| O
that O
not O
even O
the O
sharp O
elbows O
and O
red O
- O
tipped O
nose O
of O
the O
noble O
|
| O
lady O
, O
who O
, O
to O
borrow O
the O
phrase O
of O
an O
inimitable O
describer O
, O
was O
in O
|
| O
every O
sense O
“ O
preter O
- O
blue O
perfect O
, O
” O
could O
render O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
|
| O
quite O
easy O
respecting O
the O
nature O
of O
the O
friendship O
. O
Nor O
was O
it O
|
| O
without O
something O
like O
a O
pang O
that O
she O
marked O
the O
sudden O
alacrity O
|
| O
of O
movement O
with O
which O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
now O
strode O
across O
the O
floor O
to O
|
| O
accompany O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
in O
the O
extraordinary O
frolic O
which O
led O
her O
, O
|
| O
in O
white O
satin O
shoes O
and O
a O
gauze O
dress O
, O
to O
exchange O
the O
drawing- O
|
| O
room O
for O
the O
garden O
, O
at O
nine B-TIME
o’clock I-TIME
in I-TIME
the I-TIME
evening I-TIME
. O
|

| O
But O
upon O
this O
occasion O
, O
as O
upon O
many O
others O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
|
| O
found O
consolation O
in O
the O
well O
- O
known O
fact O
, O
that O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
rarely O
|
| O
moved O
a O
step O
without O
being O
obsequiously O
attended O
by O
her O
humble O
|
| O
companion O
, O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
. O
This O
young O
lady O
had O
been O
selected O
to O
fill O
|
| O
her O
present O
enviable O
situation O
, O
principally O
from O
her O
appearance O
, O
|
| O
though O
she O
was O
indeed O
by O
no O
means O
void O
of O
many O
other O
qualifica- O
|
| O
tions O
admirably O
suited O
to O
it O
. O
But O
in O
appearance O
she O
was O
a O
striking O
|
| O
contrast O
to O
her O
tall O
and O
slender O
patroness O
  O
and O
, O
notwithstanding O
|
| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
’s O
mental O
superiority O
, O
she O
was O
not O
insensible O
to O
the O
|
| O
advantage O
of O
having O
a O
foil O
that O
should O
set O
off O
the O
charms O
upon O
|
| O
which O
she O
particularly O
prided O
herself O
. O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
had O
a O
thin O
, O
|
| O
narrow O
foot O
, O
and O
an O
ancle B-ORG
that O
resembled O
nothing O
so O
much O
as O
the O
|
| O
leg O
of O
a O
Robin B-PERSON
red I-PERSON
- O
breast O
  O
the O
person O
of O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
was O
supported O
|
| O
on O
shafts O
that O
told O
her O
Saxon B-NORP
origin O
, O
and O
feet O
that O
need O
not O
have O
|
| O
shrunk O
from O
sustaining O
an O
ox O
! O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
’s O
slender O
waist O
might O
|
| O
have O
been O
encircled O
by O
a O
ring O
of O
six B-QUANTITY
inches I-QUANTITY
diameter O
  O
a O
cestus O
of O
|
| O
nearly O
double O
the O
span O
had O
often O
gone O
nigh O
to O
suffocate O
her O
plump O
|
| O
companion O
. O
The O
, O
throat O
of O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
had O
not O
only O
all O
the O
flexile O
|
| O
length O
of O
the O
swan O
’s O
, O
but O
might O
even O
be O
said O
to O
resemble O
that O
of O
the O
|
| O
stork O
in O
its O
proportions O
  O
while O
the O
head O
of O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
was O
separated O
|
| O
from O
her O
shoulders O
by O
an O
interval O
so O
trifling O
, O
as O
hardly O
to O
be O
percep- O
|
| O
tible O
at.all B-PERSON
. O
The O
hair O
of O
, O
her O
ladyship O
, O
though O
not O
very O
abundant O
, O
|
| O
was O
as O
black O
as O
ink O
, O
and O
its O
straight O
nature O
enabled O
her O
to O
lay O
-it O
in O
|
| O
classic O
bands O
upon O
her O
forehead O
, O
furnishing O
a O
graceful O
foundation O
|
| O
for O
the O
wreath O
of O
oak O
leaves O
with O
which O
, O
in O
judicious O
imitation O
of O
|
| O
Domenichino B-PERSON
's O
exquisite O
head O
of O
Sappho B-PERSON
, O
she O
usually O
adorned O
herself O
|
| O
when O
in O
full O
dress O
: O
while O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
, O
on O
the O
contrary O
, O
had O
a O
bushy O
|
| O
abundance O
, O
of O
faxen B-ORG
curls O
, O
which O
gavea O
round O
fussy O
sort O
of O
contour O
|
| O
to O
her O
face O
, O
that O
could O
not O
faihof O
setting O
off O
to O
advantage O
the O
severer O
|
| O
outline O
of O
the O
noble O
lady O
  O
and O
, O
in O
a O
word O
, O
the O
contrast O
was O
alto- O
|
| O
gether O
perfect O
. O
way O
, O
|

| O
To O
the O
great O
satisfaction O
of O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
this O
round O
little O
per- O
|
| O
sonage O
arose O
, O
as O
usual O
, O
when O
her O
principal O
rose O
, O
and O
waddled O
to O
the O
|
| O
window O
after O
her O
. O
Many O
people O
are O
apt O
to O
overlook O
and O
forget O
|
| O
companions O
, O
and O
the O
poor O
toady O
is O
as O
much O
used O
to O
- O
be O
trod O
upon O
as O
|
| O
the O
despised O
reptile O
whose O
name O
she O
bears O
. O
But O
if O
the O
world O
in O
|

 

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
9 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
general O
be O
found O
guilty‘of O
this O
scorn O
: O
towards O
what O
is O
too O
lowly O
to O
|
| O
turn O
, O
and O
scorn O
again O
, O
more O
especially O
was O
our O
knight O
liable O
to O
the O
|
| O
weakness O
, O
: O
a O
|

| O
As O
he O
now O
hastened O
to O
offer O
his O
hand O
to O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
in O
order O
|
| O
to O
assist O
her O
in O
stepping O
over O
the O
window O
- O
sill O
, O
he O
very O
nearly O
over- O
|
| O
turned O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
as O
he O
passed O
her O
  O
but O
heeding O
neither O
: O
the O
re O
|
| O
sistance O
her O
plump O
person O
offered O
to O
his O
passing O
elbow O
, O
nor O
yet O
the O
|
| O
timid O
“ O
oh O
! O
” O
which O
spoke O
her O
alarm O
, O
he O
hurried O
onward O
, O
and O
, O
|
| O
manfully O
seizing O
the O
hand O
whose O
touch O
was O
honour O
, O
walked O
out O
|
| O
side O
, O
by O
side O
with O
the O
titled O
lady O
upon O
the O
lawn O
. O
|

 

| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
II I-LAW
, O
|

| O
A O
DELIGHTFUL O
RAMBLE O
— O
FRIENDSHIP O
AND O
THE O
MUSE B-ORG
— O
AN O
AD- O
|
| O
VENTURE B-ORG
— O
DANGER O
AND O
ESCAPE O
— O
GRATITUDE O
AND O
BENEYO- O
|
| O
LENCE B-ORG
, O
|

| O
“ O
Oxny B-PERSON
see O
that O
! O
How O
very O
extraordinary O
! O
” O
exclaimed O
Lady B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
suddenly O
rising O
, O
and O
addressing O
herself O
to O
no O
one O
in O
parti- O
|
| O
cular O
, O
|

| O
“ O
Oh O
! O
how O
delightful O
! O
” O
cried O
several O
ladies O
at O
once O
. O
‘ O
“ O
How O
|
| O
clever O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
is O
! O
Such O
a O
delicious O
refreshment O
! O
” O
‘ O
‘ O
To O
be O
|
| O
sure O
, O
it O
is O
the O
only O
thing O
in O
the O
world O
" O
to O
do O
on O
such O
an O
evening B-TIME
|
| O
as O
this O
, O
” O
exclaimed O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
  O
who O
, O
as O
being O
the O
richest O
|
| O
young O
lady O
in O
company O
, O
very O
properly O
thought O
she O
ought O
to O
spéak O
|
| O
first B-ORDINAL
. O
“ O
I'am O
sure O
I O
shall O
follow O
her O
example O
  O
” O
and O
so O
saying O
, O
she O
|
| O
rose O
and O
walked O
towards O
the O
window O
. O
Three B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
most- O
daunt- O
|
| O
less O
ladies O
in O
the O
party O
started O
up O
to O
follow O
her O
  O
which O
, O
strangeas O
|
| O
the O
manccuyre B-ORG
appeared O
to O
the O
full O
- O
dressed O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
she O
did O
|
| O
not O
oppose O
, O
greatly O
preferring O
-that O
the O
garden O
party O
should O
be O
|
| O
enlarged O
. O
But O
, O
thongh O
not O
by O
- O
her O
, O
the O
adventurous O
fair O
ones O
were O
|
| O
stopped O
before O
they O
accomplished O
their O
design O
, O
bya O
chorus O
of*re- B-ORG
|
| O
monstrances O
from O
all O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
company O
, O
male O
and O
female O
. O
|

| O
“ O
‘ O
My O
dear O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
, O
you O
will O
catch O
your O
death O
! O
” O
cried O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
. O
- O
4 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
“ O
Oh O
! O
look O
at O
. O
your O
satin O
shoes O
! O
” O
screamed O
another O
. O
* O
“ O
What O
|
| O
would O
Mr. O
Tomkins B-PERSON
say O
if O
he O
was O
here O
, O
Mrs. O
‘ O
tomkins O
? O
” O
demanded O
|
| O
athird B-ORG
. O
  O
|

| O
“ O
And O
your O
neck O
and O
shoulders O
, O
Miss O
Williamson B-PERSON
! O
” O
whispered O
a. O
|
| O
fourth B-ORDINAL
. O
o O
< O
0 O
|

| O
“ O
And O
your O
blonde O
dress O
, O
Mrs. O
Simpkins B-PERSON
! O
” O
vociferated O
a O
fifth B-ORDINAL
  O
|
| O
with O
a O
vast O
deal O
more O
in O
the O
same O
strain O
. O
So O
that O
before O
the O
sortie O
|
| O
was O
accomplished O
, O
every O
lady O
, O
save O
Miss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
, O
yielded O
before O
|
| O
the O
storm O
of O
reasons O
that O
pelted O
: O
them O
on O
all O
sides O
. O
‘ O
The O
rich O
young O
|

| O
10 B-CARDINAL
THE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
lady O
, O
however O
, O
stood O
firm O
: O
what O
‘ O
young O
lady O
with O
two B-CARDINAL
hundred I-CARDINAL
|
| I-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
pounds I-CARDINAL
would O
not O
? O
|

| O
“ O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
” O
said O
she O
, O
still O
pursuing O
her O
way O
|
| O
window O
- O
ward O
, O
but O
pausing O
ere O
she O
stepped O
out O
, O
“ O
will O
you O
have O
|
| O
the O
excessive O
kindness,—vraiment O
j'ai O
honte O
  O
but O
will O
you O
have O
the O
|
| O
charity O
to O
look O
in O
the O
hall O
for O
my O
pink O
satin O
mantelet O
, O
trimmed O
with O
|
| O
swansdown O
  O
without O
it O
I O
fear O
my O
poor O
little O
shoulders O
will O
be O
|
| O
arrosées O
— O
< O
too O
rudely O
, O
alas O
! O
’ O
with O
the O
dews O
of O
night B-TIME
. O
” O
|

| O
Now O
the O
young O
lady O
’s O
shoulders O
were O
really O
very O
pretty O
little O
|
| O
shoulders O
, O
and O
, O
moreover O
, O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
notwithstanding O
|
| O
all O
his O
elegant O
nonchalance O
, O
perfectly O
well O
remembered O
that O
she O
|
| O
had O
two B-QUANTITY
hundred I-QUANTITY
thousand I-QUANTITY
pounds I-QUANTITY
  O
so O
, O
before O
she O
had O
stamped O
with O
|
| O
her O
little O
foot O
twice O
, O
in O
her O
impatience O
to O
join O
those O
who O
, O
from O
their O
|
| O
gaiety O
, O
seemed O
to O
be O
so O
greatly O
enjoying O
the O
fresh O
air O
, O
he O
returned O
|
| O
with O
the O
mantelet O
, O
and O
having O
, O
as O
usual O
, O
adjusted O
his O
glass O
in O
the O
|
| O
corner O
of O
his O
eye O
to O
prevent O
his O
making O
any O
mistakes O
, O
placed O
it O
on O
|
| O
her O
shoulders O
. O
|

| O
, O
aera B-ORG
  O
then O
! O
” O
she O
cried O
, O
“ O
give O
me O
your O
arm O
. O
Is O
not O
this O
good O
|
| O
fun O
? O
” O
|

| O
The O
young O
gentleman O
obeyed O
, O
declaring O
it O
was O
delightful O
, O
and O
in O
|
| O
@ O
moment O
they O
were O
beside O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
and O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
  O
good O
|
| O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
keeping O
a O
step O
or O
two B-CARDINAL
behind O
. O
|

| O
‘ O
Nobody O
but O
your O
ladyship O
had O
wit O
enough O
to O
find O
out O
that O
|
| O
there O
was O
more O
air O
to O
be O
got O
out O
of O
doors O
than O
in O
, O
” O
said O
the O
heiress O
, O
|
| O
venturing O
to O
pass O
her O
arm O
through O
that O
of O
her O
noble O
friend O
. O
But O
, O
|
| O
upon O
this O
occasion O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
though O
particularly O
intimate O
|
| O
with O
Miss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
, O
and O
seldom O
refusing O
to O
use O
her O
carriage O
and O
|
| O
act O
as O
her O
chaperone O
to O
all O
the O
parties O
in O
the O
neighbourhood O
, O
seemed O
|
| O
inclined O
to O
check O
her O
advances O
. O
|

| O
“ O
My O
dear O
child O
, O
” O
said O
she O
, O
“ O
I O
am O
delighted O
to O
see O
you O
come O
|
| O
out O
. O
I O
am O
sure O
you O
must O
have O
been O
half B-CARDINAL
stifled O
, O
as O
well O
as O
myself O
. O
|
| O
But O
you O
and O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
must O
wander O
away O
by O
yourselves O
, O
and O
|
| O
you O
may O
take O
Mogg B-PERSON
with O
you O
, O
if O
you O
like O
it O
, O
for O
Ihave O
just O
got O
into O
|
| O
a O
discussion O
with O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
that O
1 B-CARDINAL
would O
not O
break O
off O
for O
the O
|
| O
world O
. O
So O
away O
with O
you O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
as O
fast O
as O
you O
can O
. O
” O
|

| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
’s O
will O
was O
of O
course O
law O
, O
even O
to O
the O
heiress O
, O
but O
|
| O
it O
was O
not O
without O
a O
little O
toss O
of O
the O
head O
that O
she O
turned O
off O
to O
|
| O
another O
walk O
  O
nor O
was O
it O
without O
a O
considerable O
struggle O
between O
|
| O
her O
inclination O
and O
a O
sense O
of O
propriety O
, O
which O
, O
all O
things O
consi- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
dered I-PERSON
, O
really O
did O
her O
honour O
, O
that O
she O
permitted O
poor O
Miss O
Mogg B-PERSON
|
| O
to O
obey O
the O
hint O
of O
her O
patroness O
, O
and O
follow O
after O
. O
|

| O
“ O
And O
so O
you O
really O
have O
not O
seen O
this O
gifted O
young O
man O
yet O
, O
Sit O
|
| O
Matthew O
? O
” O
resumed O
her O
ladyship O
, O
as O
soon O
as O
they O
were O
again O
alone O
. O
|
| O
“ O
You O
have O
never O
yet O
seen O
this O
Osmund B-PERSON
Norval I-PERSON
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
No O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
T O
have O
not O
, O
” O
replied O
the O
knight O
  O
* O
* O
and O
to O
say O
the O
|
| O
truth O
, O
” O
he O
added O
, O
venturing O
to O
press O
with O
his O
stout O
arm O
the O
slender O
|
| O
one O
that O
rested O
on O
it O
, O
“ O
to O
say O
the O
truth O
, O
though O
I O
have O
heard O
a O
|
| O
monstrous O
deal O
about O
him O
, O
I O
was O
determined O
that O
I O
would O
have O
|
| O
nothing O
to O
say O
to O
him O
, O
till O
I O
had O
heard O
your O
opinion O
, O
my O
lady O
. O
” O
|

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
il B-PERSON
|

| O
“ O
How O
kind O
! O
how O
flattering O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
! O
But O
you O
will O
let O
|
| O
me O
bring O
him O
to O
you O
now O
2 O
” O
|

| O
« O
< O
Will O
1 O
? O
” O
( O
again O
pressing O
the O
lean O
arm O
. O
) O
‘ O
‘ O
Fancy O
me O
saying O
|
| O
no O
, O
when O
you O
tell O
me O
to O
say O
yes O
! O
Ah O
! O
my O
lady O
, O
you O
know O
better O
|
| O
than O
that O
, O
or O
I O
am O
greatly O
mistaken O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Oh O
! O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
you O
are O
always O
so O
kind O
! O
What O
magnificent O
|
| O
gardens O
you O
have O
! O
By O
the O
way O
, O
! O
think O
I O
never O
tasted O
such O
a O
pine O
|
| O
as O
that O
we O
had O
to O
- O
day O
. O
_ O
I O
assure O
you O
, O
my O
brother O
, O
Lord O
Highland- O
|
| O
loch O
, O
is O
celebrated O
far O
his O
pines O
— O
quite O
celebrated O
. O
‘ O
They O
are O
the O
|
| O
finest O
in O
all O
Scotland B-GPE
, O
but O
I O
give O
you O
my O
honour O
, O
I O
never O
saw O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
equal O
to O
it O
at O
- O
his O
table O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Oh O
! O
my O
lady O
, O
that O
is O
only O
your O
amiable O
condescension O
, O
” O
replied O
|
| O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
greatly O
touched O
by O
this O
preference O
. O
“ O
But O
if O
you O
|
| O
really O
can O
be O
so O
polite O
as O
to O
think O
them O
good O
, O
I O
must O
entreat O
you O
|
| O
just O
to O
let O
me O
knock O
at O
the O
head O
- O
gardener O
’s O
door O
, O
who O
lives O
close O
|
| O
outside O
this O
gate O
. O
I O
do O
n’t O
let O
him O
live O
inside O
, O
because O
of O
his O
|
| O
children O
, O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
. O
I O
know O
what O
birds O
peck O
the O
worst O
— O
ha O
! O
|
| O
ha O
! O
ha O
! O
However O
, O
you O
must O
just O
let O
me O
pass O
through O
the O
gate O
to O
|
| O
tell O
him O
to O
put O
up O
a O
brace O
for O
your O
ladyship O
. O
They O
shall O
be O
well O
|
| O
taken O
care O
of O
now O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
trust O
me O
for O
that O
  O
I O
never O
valued O
them O
|
| O
so O
much O
before O
, O
I O
promise O
you O
. O
” O
. O
|

| O
“ O
You O
are O
too O
kind O
a O
thousand O
times O
! O
” O
said O
the O
lady O
, O
stretching O
|
| O
out O
her O
own O
hand O
to O
open O
the O
gate O
. O
“ O
I O
will O
go O
with O
you O
  O
there O
is O
|
| O
nothing O
I O
doat O
upon O
like O
visiting O
a O
gardener O
. O
Could O
he O
not O
take O
|
| O
us O
into O
thé B-ORG
hot I-ORG
- I-ORG
houses I-ORG
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
? O
You O
have O
no O
idea O
how O
I O
|
| O
should O
enjoy O
it O
. O
” O
: O
|

| O
By O
no O
means O
displeased O
to O
show O
off O
the O
high O
- O
born O
lady O
upon O
his O
|
| O
arm O
, O
even O
to O
the O
eyes O
of O
his O
gardener O
, O
the O
knight O
joyfully O
assented O
|
| O
to O
peer O
onaeel O
: O
|

| O
“ O
Macnab B-ORG
! O
” O
he O
cried O
, O
’ O
knocking O
as O
he O
passed O
the O
cottage O
- O
win- O
|
| O
dow O
, O
“ O
Macnab B-ORG
! O
come O
here O
directly O
, O
and O
bring O
a O
knife O
and O
a O
|
| O
basket O
with O
you O
  O
you O
must O
come O
directly O
— O
this O
very O
moment O
, O
and O
|
| O
unlock O
the O
hot O
- O
houses O
— O
her O
ladyship O
wishes O
to O
walk O
’ O
through O
them O
, O
|
| O
and O
I O
must O
have O
one B-CARDINAL
or O
two B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
finest O
pines O
cut O
, O
and O
packed O
in O
a O
|
| O
basket O
, O
to O
be O
put O
into O
Miss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
’s O
carriage O
: O
but O
mind O
, O
they O
|
| O
are O
for O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
Shrimpton I-PERSON
  O
so O
you O
had O
better O
give O
them O
in O
|
| O
charge O
to O
her O
ladyship O
's O
own O
man O
. O
” O
|

| O
Mr. O
Alexander B-PERSON
Macnab I-PERSON
promptly O
left O
the O
seeds O
he.was O
sorting O
, O
|
| O
and O
prepared O
himself O
, O
basket O
in O
hand O
, O
to O
follow O
his O
master O
. O
The O
|
| O
Knight O
and O
the O
lady O
left O
the O
cottage O
, O
arm O
- O
and O
- O
arm O
together O
  O
but O
|
| O
before O
they O
again O
entered O
the O
garden O
, O
a O
fancy O
seized O
her O
lively O
Indy- O
|
| O
ship O
, O
that O
a O
short O
ramble O
in O
the O
green O
lane O
outside O
it O
would O
be O
the O
|
| O
most O
agreeable O
thing O
in O
the O
world O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Dear O
me O
! O
what O
a O
poetical O
idea O
! O
” O
exclaimed O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
with O
|
| O
enthusiasm O
. O
“ O
There O
’s O
only B-CARDINAL
one I-CARDINAL
thing O
, O
” O
he O
said O
, O
stopping O
short O
, O
|
| O
“ O
but O
that O
will O
spoil O
my O
pleasure O
altogether O
: O
I O
am O
so O
dreadfully O
afraid O
|
| O
that O
your O
ladyship O
will O
take O
cold O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Ask O
the O
gardener O
’s O
wife O
to O
lend O
me O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
her O
kerchiefs O
, O
” O
said O
|
| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
« O
But O
it O
will O
only O
be O
to O
satisfy O
you O
, O
Sir O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
for O
there O
is O
no O
catching O
cold O
in O
such O
weather O
as O
this O
. O
” O
|

| O
12 B-CARDINAL
THE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
It O
was O
with O
something O
quite O
like O
tender O
anxiety O
that O
the O
knight O
|
| O
stepped O
back O
, O
asked O
for O
and O
obtained O
a O
neat O
shawl O
, O
and O
himself O
|
| O
wrapped O
it O
round O
the O
slender O
person O
of O
his O
amiable O
companion O
. O
|

| O
« O
Thank O
you O
! O
thank O
you O
a O
thousand B-CARDINAL
times O
! O
But O
, O
dear O
Sir O
Mat- O
|
| O
thew B-PERSON
, O
I O
must O
not O
lose O
my O
pines O
by O
my O
frolic O
: O
will O
you O
give O
the O
gar- O
|
| O
dener O
orders O
to O
get O
them O
without O
waiting O
for O
us O
? O
and O
perhaps O
you O
|
| O
would O
let O
him O
put O
up O
a O
bunch O
of O
grapes O
, O
and O
a O
few O
peaches O
at O
the O
|
| O
same O
time O
— O
it O
is O
no O
good O
to O
let O
him O
wait O
for O
us O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
  O
— O
when O
|
| O
you O
and O
I O
get O
into O
a O
chat O
together O
, O
we O
shall O
neither O
of O
us O
think O
of O
|
| O
the O
pines O
again O
. O
” O
|

| O
Quitting O
her O
highly O
- O
valued O
aristocratic O
arm O
for O
an O
instant O
, O
the O
|
| O
flattered O
knight O
ran O
back O
and O
gave O
the O
necessary O
orders O
  O
and O
then O
, O
|
| O
almost O
unconscious O
, O
in O
his O
full O
contentment O
, O
that O
his O
own O
gray O
head O
. O
|
| O
was O
as O
bare O
as O
that O
of O
the O
oak O
- O
crowned O
nymph O
by O
his O
side O
, O
he O
re- O
|
| O
turned O
to O
his O
bewitching O
companion O
and O
led O
her O
gently O
onward O
over O
|
| O
the O
mossy O
turf O
that O
bordered O
the O
road O
. O
|

| O
The O
gardener O
and O
his O
wife O
stood O
together O
for O
a O
moment O
looking O
|
| O
after O
them O
. O
‘ O
Who O
would O
think O
now O
that O
she O
was O
one O
of O
the O
true O
|
| O
old O
gentlefolks O
, O
and O
Scotch B-NORP
to O
boot O
, O
to O
see O
her O
pair O
off O
that O
way O
with O
|
| O
our O
rogue O
of O
a O
spinner O
there O
? O
How O
, O
in O
God O
’s O
name O
, O
can O
she O
choose O
to O
|
| O
be O
so O
free O
and O
friendly O
with O
such O
as O
he O
? O
” O
said O
the O
gardener O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Just O
for O
the O
same O
reason O
’ O
as O
yourself O
, O
Sawny O
, O
” O
replied O
his O
wife O
  O
|
| O
* O
€ O
to O
get O
all O
she O
can O
out O
of O
him O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
And O
that O
’s O
true O
, O
” O
replied O
Sawny O
, O
setting O
off O
upon O
his O
businéss O
. O
|
| O
“ O
Thad B-PERSON
like O
to O
forget O
the O
pines O
, O
and O
the O
grapes O
, O
and O
the O
peaches O
. O
|
| O
She O
's O
not O
so O
far O
wrong O
after O
all O
  O
and O
yet O
“ O
tis O
a O
pity O
, O
too O
. O
” O
|

| O
* O
* O
. O
* O
|

| O
The O
evening O
was O
stil O
] O
oppressively O
sultry O
, O
and O
hardly O
a O
breath O
of O
|
| O
air O
disturbed O
either O
the O
leaves O
on O
the O
oaks O
beside O
the O
road O
, O
or O
those O
|
| O
that O
mimicked O
them O
so O
abominably O
on O
the O
lady O
’s O
brow O
  O
but O
, O
never- O
|
| O
theless O
, O
there O
was O
a O
freshness O
in O
the O
smell O
of O
the O
hedges O
and O
the O
grass O
, O
|
| O
which O
could O
not O
fail O
to O
be O
agreeable O
to O
any O
nerves O
that O
had O
endured O
|
| O
the O
steaming O
dinner O
, O
and O
the O
irksome O
drawing O
- O
room O
of O
Dowling B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
. O
|

| O
The O
shady O
lane O
in O
which O
the O
knight O
and O
the O
lady O
were O
thus O
re- O
|
| O
creatirig O
themselves O
, O
after O
skirting O
the O
extensive O
and O
lofty O
walls O
of O
|
| O
the O
garden O
, O
turned O
at O
right O
angles O
both O
to O
the O
right O
and O
the O
left O
at O
|
| O
the O
corner O
of O
it O
. O
The O
branch O
to O
the O
left O
followed O
the O
boundary O
of O
|
| O
the O
garden O
, O
and O
led O
to O
the O
stable O
- O
yard O
and O
back O
entrance O
to O
the O
|
| O
house O
  O
that O
to O
the O
right O
conducted O
to O
the O
factory O
, O
which O
was O
the O
|
| O
source O
and O
head O
- O
spring O
of O
all O
the O
wealth O
that O
flowed O
over O
, O
and O
irri- O
|
| O
gated O
with O
its O
fructifying O
stream O
, O
meadows O
, O
parks O
, O
hot O
- O
beds O
and O
|
| O
flower O
- O
gardens O
, O
till O
it O
made O
itself O
a O
prodigious O
cistern O
in O
the O
depths O
|
| O
and O
heights O
of O
Dowling B-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
. O
” O
|

| O
When O
the O
strangely O
- O
matched O
paircame O
to O
this O
point O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| O
made O
a O
halt O
, O
till O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
came O
to O
the O
end O
of O
a O
little O
poem O
, O
|
| O
which O
the O
protegé O
whom O
she O
was O
so O
desirous O
of O
introducing O
to O
her O
|
| O
rich O
dnd O
( O
to O
use O
her O
own O
words O
) O
“ O
really O
very O
clever O
friend O
, O
” O
had O
in- O
|
| O
scribed O
in O
her O
album O
. O
|

| O
Nothing O
could O
be O
more O
agreeable O
to O
her O
ladyship O
than O
this O
pause O
. O
|

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
13 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
In O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
place O
it O
was O
the O
greatest O
possible O
relief O
to O
her O
lungs O
, O
for O
|
| O
the O
lines O
she O
was O
reciting O
were O
much O
too O
full O
of O
deep O
feeling O
to O
be O
|
| O
repeated O
without O
a O
painful O
effort O
, O
while O
walking O
  O
and O
in O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
, O
|
| O
the O
halt O
, O
accompanied O
as O
it O
was O
by O
a O
look O
of O
earnest O
attention O
from O
|
| O
her O
apparently O
- O
delighted O
companion O
, O
furnished O
the O
most O
agreeable O
|
| O
commentary O
in O
the O
world O
upon O
the O
poem O
itself O
, O
as O
well O
as O
on O
her O
|
| O
manner O
of O
reciting O
it O
, O
|

| O
It O
said O
so O
plainly O
, O
« O
Stay O
! O
— O
move O
not O
! O
— O
lest O
a O
word O
, O
an O
intona- O
|
| O
tion O
, O
a O
cadence O
, O
be O
lost O
to O
me O
! O
” O
|

| O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
was O
’ O
really O
touched O
by O
it O
  O
and O
let O
Sawny O
the O
gar- O
|
| O
dener O
, O
and O
his O
wife O
Janet B-PERSON
, O
say O
or O
think O
what O
they O
‘ O
would O
, O
neither O
|
| O
peaches O
nor O
pines O
had O
any O
thing O
to O
do O
with O
the O
gratification O
she O
at O
|
| O
this O
moment O
experienced O
in O
the O
society O
of O
the O
great O
manufacturer O
. O
|

| O
His O
eyes O
were O
fixed O
on O
her O
face O
, O
and O
she O
bore O
the O
gaze O
, O
and O
|
| O
returned O
it O
with O
that O
sort O
of O
courage O
and O
confidence O
, O
which O
genuine O
|
| O
enthusiasm O
alone O
can O
give O
. O
|

| O
She O
had O
just O
finished O
a O
stanza O
when O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
ceased O
to O
move O
, O
|
| O
and O
feeling O
that O
he O
did O
so O
under O
the O
influence O
of O
a O
spell O
, O
which O
she O
|
| O
well O
knew O
would O
be O
more O
powerful O
still O
were O
it O
spoken O
when O
she O
|
| O
were O
at O
rest O
— O
for O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
was O
aware O
that O
she O
was O
exceedingly O
|
| O
short O
- O
breathed O
— O
she O
repeated O
the O
last O
eight B-CARDINAL
lines O
in O
a O
manner O
that O
|
| O
showed O
she O
felt O
the O
pleasure O
she O
was O
producing O
— O
a O
pleasure O
, O
as O
she O
|
| O
thought O
, O
like O
that O
occasionally O
caused O
by O
the O
repetition O
of O
some O
|
| O
delicious O
phrase O
in O
a O
musical O
composition O
, O
reiterated O
as O
if O
to O
fill O
the O
|
| O
soul O
with O
its O
sweetness O
. O
|

 

 

| O
“ O
And O
should O
the O
eye O
for O
which O
I O
write O
|

| O
By O
sun O
- O
lit O
morn O
, O
or O
moon O
- O
lit O
night O
, O
|
| O
Drop O
on O
this O
record O
of O
my O
soul O
, O
|
| O
Which O
tells O
a O
part O
— O
ah O
! O
not O
the O
whole O
, O
|
| O
Of O
hopes O
that O
trembling O
, O
faltering O
, O
timid O
, O
|
| O
Now O
fire O
my O
cheek O
, O
now O
turn O
it O
livid O
, O
— O
|
| O
Should O
that O
soft O
eye O
but O
drop O
one B-CARDINAL
tear O
, O
|
| O
I O
'd O
hug O
my O
chain O
, O
and O
call O
it O
dear O
! O
” O
|

| O
The O
tear O
asked O
for O
, O
almost O
came O
as O
she O
ceased O
. O
|

| O
“ O
You O
feel O
it O
, O
dear O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
! O
” O
she O
said O
, O
in O
a O
voice O
of O
consider- O
|
| O
able O
emotion O
. O
: O
|

| O
“ O
I O
'd O
hug O
my O
chain O
, O
and O
call O
it O
dear!”—she O
again O
murmured O
, O
|
| O
hanging O
on O
his O
arm O
with O
such O
an O
evident O
degree O
of O
weakness O
, O
as O
|
| O
showed O
the O
slender O
form O
to O
be O
less O
powerful O
than O
’ O
the O
ardent O
spirit O
|
| O
it O
enshrined O
. O
: O
|

| O
“ O
Tet O
us O
turn O
back O
, O
” O
said O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
. O
“ O
My O
dear O
friend O
, O
” O
|
| O
faintly O
ejaculated O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
, O
“ O
you O
are O
moved O
too O
strongly O
. O
— O
|
| O
But O
— O
no O
, O
no O
! O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
! O
Believe O
me O
, O
it O
were O
far O
better O
for O
both O
|
| O
of O
us O
that O
we O
should O
proceed.—Are O
we O
, O
either O
of O
us O
, O
my O
dear O
friend O
, O
|
| O
in O
a O
state O
at O
this O
moment O
to O
meet O
the O
curious O
stare O
of O
idle O
eyes O
? O
— O
|
| O
Come O
on O
, O
dear O
Sir O
Matthew!”—and B-PERSON
she O
géntly O
pulled O
him O
forward O
|
| O
as O
she O
spoke O
— O
* O
this O
soft O
glade O
invites O
us O
. O
” O
|

| O
Though O
perfectly O
determined O
to O
find O
some O
excuse O
for O
not O
leading O
|
| O
his O
fascinating O
companion O
within O
sight O
of O
his O
grim O
- O
looking O
factory O
, O
|
| O
which O
another O
turn O
in O
the O
lane O
at O
no O
great O
distance O
would O
have O
|
| O
made O
very O
unpicturesquely O
visible O
, O
it O
was O
impossible O
at O
that O
moment O
|

 

| O
4 B-CARDINAL
THE B-ORG
LIFE I-ORG
AND O
ADVENTURES O
|

| O
not O
to O
yield O
to O
the O
gentle O
violence O
which O
carried O
him O
forward O
  O
and O
, O
|
| O
in O
what O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
felt O
to O
be O
very O
eloquent O
silence O
, O
he O
proceeded O
|
| O
for O
a O
few O
steps O
farther O
. O
Considerably O
, O
however O
, O
before O
they O
had O
|
| O
reached O
the O
dreaded O
turning O
, O
his O
good O
star O
shot O
a O
ray O
upon O
him O
in O
|
| O
the O
shape O
of O
a O
very O
large O
cow O
, O
with O
a O
pair O
of O
enormous O
horns O
, O
that O
|
| O
slowly O
turned O
the O
corner O
, O
and O
fronted O
them O
. O
|

| O
‘ O
Good O
heaven O
! O
” O
he O
exclaimed O
in O
an O
accent O
of O
great O
alarm O
. O
— O
|
| O
“ O
There O
is O
that O
horrid O
spotted O
cow O
! O
she O
is O
the O
worst O
beast O
in O
|
| O
the O
whole O
parish O
. O
Turn O
back O
, O
dearest O
Lady O
Clarissa B-PERSON
! O
turn O
back O
|
| O
instantly O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
How O
kindly O
considerate O
! O
” O
returned O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
. O
“ O
But O
you O
|
| O
little O
know O
the O
strength O
of O
your O
friend O
’s O
mind O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
. O
Were O
|
| O
alone O
, O
indeed O
, O
I O
might O
tremble O
and O
turn O
as O
pale O
as O
the O
veriest O
|
| O
child O
that O
ever O
hid O
its O
face O
on O
a O
nurse O
’s O
lap O
  O
but O
with O
you!”—and O
|
| O
here O
the O
lady O
turned O
a O
very O
flattering O
glance O
on O
the O
athletic O
form O
|
| O
of O
her O
protector O
— O
|

| O
« O
Heaven O
knows O
, O
” O
replied O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
once O
more O
pressing O
her O
|
| O
Jean B-PERSON
arm I-PERSON
, O
‘ O
Heaven O
knows O
that O
all O
which O
the O
strength O
of O
man O
could O
|
| O
do O
to O
protect O
you O
, O
would O
not O
be O
left O
undone O
by O
me O
— O
but O
consider O
|
| O
the O
dog O
! O
” O
he O
added O
, O
pointing O
to O
a O
little O
cur O
that O
always O
followed O
|
| O
him O
  O
* O
its O
power O
of O
irritating O
an O
animal O
of O
this O
kind O
is O
quite O
|
| O
extraordinary O
. O
” O
And O
as O
he O
spoke O
, O
he O
whistled O
in O
a O
note O
which O
meant O
, O
|
| O
as O
his O
dog O
Spite O
knew O
as O
well O
as O
he O
did O
, O
neither O
more O
nor O
less O
than O
|
| O
— O
* O
At O
her O
, O
Spite O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
If O
any O
thing O
can O
keep O
Spite O
quiet O
, O
” O
resumed O
the O
knight O
, O
“ O
it O
is O
|
| O
whistling O
to O
him O
. O
” O
|

| O
Obedient O
to O
the O
true O
meaning O
of O
the O
signal O
, O
however O
, O
the O
dog O
|
| O
sprang O
forward O
, O
and O
of O
course O
there O
ensued O
the O
scene O
which O
always O
|
| O
follows O
on O
such O
occasions O
. O
The O
dog O
yelped O
, O
and O
affected O
to O
spring O
|
| O
at O
the O
nose O
of O
the O
cow O
, O
while O
she O
, O
somewhat O
accelerating O
her O
stately O
|
| O
pace O
, O
threw O
up O
her O
tail O
, O
and O
bent O
down O
her O
head O
till O
her O
horns O
|
| O
nearly O
touched O
the O
ground O
, O
offering O
so O
exact O
an O
image O
of O
“ O
the O
cow O
|
| O
with O
the O
crumpled O
horn O
, O
” O
with O
whose O
portrait O
her O
ladyship O
’s O
early O
|
| O
studies O
had O
made O
her O
familiar O
, O
that O
her O
confidence O
in O
the O
prowess O
|
| O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
could O
sustain O
her O
no O
longer O
, O
and O
she O
rapidly O
uttered O
|
| O
a O
succession O
of O
tremendous O
screams O
. O
|

| O
The O
purpose O
of O
the O
knight O
was O
accomplished O
, O
and O
he O
therefore O
|
| O
indulged O
the O
fair O
lady O
by O
letting O
her O
scream O
on O
for O
at B-TIME
least I-TIME
a I-TIME
minute I-TIME
|
| O
and O
a B-CARDINAL
half I-CARDINAL
, O
while O
he O
supported O
her O
with O
every O
appearance O
of O
the O
|
| O
most O
pitying O
tenderness O
. O
Meanwhile O
, O
two B-CARDINAL
little O
boys O
, O
who O
were O
|
| O
making O
their O
way O
from O
the O
factory O
homewards O
, O
across O
a O
field O
by O
the O
|
| O
side O
of O
the O
lane O
, O
ran O
with O
terrified O
curiosity O
, O
and O
all O
the O
strength O
|
| O
they O
had O
, O
to O
a O
gate O
, O
through O
which O
they O
could O
see O
the O
interesting O
|
| O
spectacle O
of O
a O
fine O
full O
- O
dressed O
lady O
, O
screaming O
with O
all O
her O
might O
|
| O
from O
between O
the O
sheltering O
arms O
of O
the O
magnificent O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
and O
a O
little O
dog O
worrying O
an O
old O
half O
- O
starved O
cow O
. O
|

| O
« O
Come O
here O
, O
you O
young O
scamps O
! O
” O
cried O
the O
knight O
, O
on O
perceiving O
|
| O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
little O
heads O
peeping O
over O
the O
gate O
: O
‘ O
Do O
n’t O
you O
see O
what O
’s O
|
| O
going O
on O
? O
Clamber B-PERSON
over O
the O
gate O
, O
ca O
n’t O
you O
, O
and O
drive O
back O
that O
devil O
|
| O
of O
a O
beast O
. O
” O
|

| O
OF O
MICHAEL B-PERSON
ARMSTRONG I-PERSON
. O
15 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
The O
youngest O
, O
but O
by O
far O
the O
stoutest O
and O
tallest O
of O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
boys O
, O
|
| O
instantly O
obeyed O
this O
command O
, O
and O
placing O
himself O
midway O
be- O
|
| O
tween O
the O
tormented O
cow O
and O
the O
fair O
creature O
, O
whose O
nerves O
her O
|
| O
menacing O
attitude O
had O
so O
cruelly O
shaken O
, O
he O
stood O
manfully O
astride O
|
| O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
lane O
, O
flourished O
his O
ragged O
hat O
on O
high O
, O
and O
|
| O
with O
a O
few O
lusty O
“ O
wough O
! O
woughs B-ORG
! O
” O
repeated O
at O
the O
top O
of O
his O
|
| O
young O
voice O
, O
succeeded O
in O
turning O
the O
front O
of O
the O
enemy O
, O
which O
|
| O
was O
presently O
seen O
to O
wheel O
round O
, O
and O
, O
by O
a O
sort O
of O
feeble O
, O
ambling O
|
| O
little O
trot O
, O
speedily O
got O
out O
of O
sight O
round O
the O
corner O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Now O
, O
then O
, O
” O
said O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
“ O
let O
me O
lead O
you O
home O
, O
my O
dear O
|
| O
lady O
! O
” O
|

| O
Not O
till O
I O
have O
thanked O
my O
little O
deliverer O
, O
” O
exclaimed O
Lady B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
with O
very O
sentimental O
fervour O
. O
‘ O
Good O
heaven O
! O
what O
|
| O
might O
have O
been O
my O
fate O
without O
him O
! O
I O
know O
— O
l O
feel O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
that O
you O
never O
could O
have O
borne O
to O
leave O
me O
, O
and O
what O
then O
could O
|
| O
have O
stopped O
the O
fearful O
approach O
of O
that O
most O
vicious O
animal O
? O
— O
|
| O
Death O
, O
or O
worse O
than O
death O
— O
dislocation O
of O
limb O
, O
disfigurement O
of O
|
| O
feature O
! O
Oh O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
your O
heart O
, O
I O
know O
, O
will O
go O
side O
by O
side O
|
| O
with O
mine O
. O
Tell O
me O
, O
what O
can O
I O
do O
— O
what O
can O
we O
both O
do O
, O
to O
reward O
|
| O
the O
astonishing O
bravery O
of O
that O
noble O
little O
fellow O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Depend O
upon O
it O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
he O
will O
be O
delighted O
if O
you O
will O
give O
|
| O
him O
sixpence O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Sixpence B-WORK_OF_ART
! O
” O
cried O
her O
ladyship O
, O
turning O
extremely O
red,—but O
in O
a O
|
| O
moment O
she O
recovered O
herself O
and O
said O
: O
“ O
Oh O
! O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
! O
do O
I O
not O
|
| O
know O
how O
dearly O
you O
love O
a O
jest O
? O
Men O
of O
witand O
humour O
can O
rarely O
|
| O
be O
grave O
for O
long O
together O
, O
even O
under O
circumstances O
that O
most O
keenly O
|
| O
touch O
their O
feelings O
  O
did O
I O
not O
know O
you O
well O
, O
my O
friend O
, O
what O
|
| O
should O
I O
not O
think O
of O
your O
proposal O
? O
But O
come O
, O
come O
— O
be O
serious O
|
| O
for O
a O
moment O
longer O
: O
we O
have O
, O
it O
is O
true O
, O
escaped O
a O
tremendous O
|
| O
danger O
, O
and O
it O
may O
well O
make O
us O
feel O
light O
at O
heart O
  O
but O
we O
will O
not O
|
| O
laugh O
over O
it O
, O
till O
we O
have O
settled O
in O
what O
way O
that O
heroic O
child O
|
| O
shall O
receive O
the O
meed O
he O
has O
earned O
. O
I O
shall O
not O
rest O
in O
peace O
, O
my O
|
| O
friend O
, O
unless O
his O
destiny O
be O
as O
favourably O
influenced O
by O
me O
, O
as O
|
| O
mine O
has O
probably O
been O
by O
him O
. O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
you O
have O
great O
|
| O
power O
, O
enormous O
wealth O
, O
a O
generous O
heart O
, O
a O
noble O
nature O
, O
and O
in- O
|
| O
tellect O
, O
before O
which O
, O
if O
I O
mistake O
not O
, O
all O
difficulties O
will O
melt O
away O
|
| O
like O
a O
mist O
before O
the O
sun O
. O
Of O
allthis O
1 B-CARDINAL
am O
quite O
certain O
. O
There O
|
| O
is O
but O
one B-CARDINAL
1F I-CARDINAL
in O
the O
business O
. O
Ir O
you O
value O
me O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
as O
much O
|
| O
as O
I O
think O
you O
do O
, O
that O
little O
boy O
now O
getting O
over O
the O
gate O
will O
be O
|
| O
clothed O
, O
educated O
, O
fed B-ORG
, O
lodged O
by O
you O
. O
Do O
I O
deceive O
myself O
? O
or O
will O
|
| O
the O
daily B-DATE
sight O
of O
him O
, O
by O
renewing O
the O
memory O
of O
this B-TIME
evening I-TIME
, O
|
| O
rather O
cause O
you O
pleasure O
than O
pain O
? O
” O
|
