11 O
] O
laia O
H O
U O
U1 O
Clalll O
U O
NIV O
E O
R O
S O
IT O
Y O
Libraries O
oOF O
OX O
F O
O O
RD O
This O
book O
is O
part O
of O
the O
collection O
held O
by O
the B-ORG
Bodleian I-ORG
Libraries E-ORG
and O
scanned O
by O
Google B-ORG
, I-ORG
Inc. E-ORG
for O
the B-ORG
Google I-ORG
Books I-ORG
Library I-ORG
Project E-ORG
For O
more O
information O
see O
: O
http:l/www.bodleian.ox.ac.ukdbooks O
a2 O
This O
work O
is O
licensed O
under O
a O
Creative O
Commons O
Attribution O
- O
NonCommercial O
- O
ShareAlike O
2.0 O
UK S-GPE
: O
England B-ORG
& I-ORG
Wales E-ORG
( O
CC O
BY O
- O
NC O
- O
SA O
2.0 O
) O
licence O
. O
N O
a O
P. O
) O
. O
P O
( O
4 S-CARDINAL
- O
E O
-- O
i O
. O
a O
t O
.s O
( O
3R O
i O
i3 O
y O
W O
.... O
.- O
ru O
. O
I' O
F O
, O
. O
ye O
. O
': O
L O
z O
I O
.. O
II O
rr O
t' O
e O
-e O
-'g O
, O
k O
, O
. O
s O
r O
Il O
, O
R O
--, O
c O
e. O
.n O
. O
/ O
AO O
11-.A O
. O
v O
, O
gr O
. O
. O
- O
.2 O
. O
ef O
a O
P. O
=s O
Rk O
' O
.- O
. O
I O
' O
M O
7 O
n O
, O
, O
' O
-- O
. O
t-. O
.,5 O
4 O
r O
' O
, O
A'. O
|. .| O
. O
- O
. O
a O
- O
A O
--- O
l O
4 O
t. O
A O
, O
I O
, O
, O
.- O
- O
x O
t- O
. O
AN O
, O
, O
. O
b O
I O
a O
r O
a O
Kh O
( O
-: O
Y O
Z O
-: O
is O
I O
.IM O
5 O
? O
1 S-CARDINAL
" O
. O
4 S-CARDINAL
I O
3 S-CARDINAL
nh O
n O
g O
- O
w O
. O
u O
P O
t O
m O
t' O
M O
N O
) O
N O
. O
. O
ne O
' O
a O
l O
-- O
I O
G O
J O
) O
..A O
5 S-CARDINAL
| | O
: O
p- O
MI O
. O
I O
4 S-CARDINAL
- O
-4 O
t O
1 O
.M O
II O
- O
1l O
I1 O
Z O
, O
, O
- O
M O
- O
Zl O
3 S-CARDINAL
, O
. O
- O
L O
P O
Ptl O
'.1 O
-. O
t O
. O
, O
, O
k O
rPk O
t O
. O
y O
Aa O
1 O
N O
-c O
. O
A O
- O
w'a O
M O
. O
t O
e' O
. O
e O
G1 O
e O
: O
4 S-CARDINAL
L O
t O
rz O
1 S-CARDINAL
M( O
w O
. O
IW O
LLi O
t O
L O
= O
.- O
:r O
' O
. O
Al B-PERSON
L E-PERSON
2 S-CARDINAL
, O
Per O
. O
N O
h-L. O
r4 O
vI O
r35- O
: O
s O
. O
S O
L'l O
Y O
r- O
, O
ga O
-- O
N' O
, O
f' O
-. O
sA5 O
. O
tf O
the O
-- O
- O
' O
3 O
' O
.2 O
XI O
i O
- O
e O
, O
Y O
. O
1LT O
1 O
n O
. O
p O
i O
' O
h O
-i O
-r O
" O
s O
L. O
: O
I O
F O
.E. O
1 O
( O
| | O
t O
:uaa O
iE O
Lc'. O
-W O
: O
U O
7 S-CARDINAL
. O
I O
. O
E O
2 O
la O
: O
Alt O
-.s O
A O
.y O
Ci-' O
. O
. O
f- O
y'evi O
5 O
. O
, O
G O
zit O
.. O
e.. O
i O
k O
. O
.s1 O
, O
2 S-CARDINAL
, O
V O
fE O
. O
L O
ti O
e O
: O
. O
i O
1 O
ri O
. O
I O
A O
1 O
i O
ett O
af O
r O
t O
A O
. O
7 S-CARDINAL
e O
. O
1 S-CARDINAL
. O
pi O
e O
i O
1 S-CARDINAL
- O
eee O
e-===== O
Eae=er O
'] O
-- O
s O
] O
] O
l O
-==-= O
-- O
3l O
a O
( O
1 O
1 O
'-=-- O
J2oel O
wnthont O
a O
5 S-CARDINAL
eo O
I O
n O
R O
ih O
- O
Iil' O
I O
..- O
I O
2-s O
AV O
L O
7 O
:E- O
R-S O
- O
wTLLLA3I O
NIAKEP1A O
T::A O
E O
IAY O
. O
RIt. O
lek O
rea O
. O
aII O
Lc O
1LA O
VU O
E O
] O
E O
- O
I1 O
rI O
VEE O
-----] O
El. O
I1 O
. O
: O
M O
I O
E O
4 O
UINW O
Ni O
aNL O
' O
h O
x- O
i O
ks O
' O
-- O
LI O
-gPFF O
Il O
3 S-CARDINAL
5 S-CARDINAL
L- O
-- O
2 S-CARDINAL
1 O
. O
-E O
a O
U O
- O
A O
1 O
yW O
i- O
mA O
" O
1 S-CARDINAL
| | O
= O
I O
- O
2 O
-- O
- O
----= O
=, O
wI.L1A O
M O
M1AEA O
TAC O
I O
E O
I O
AY O
. O
---- O
Wr' O
r O
2 O
lsporl O
witlut O
a O
l O
a O
1U O
t O
=. O
Ii O
I O
A O
---. O
I- O
1 O
- O
EE O
I'XA O
- O
I. O
c2l O
lLl O
.-.- O
z O
E O
. O
15 S-CARDINAL
NLLG O
. O
. O
:N O
NL O
W O
[ O
xP O
- O
L O
e O
LE2 O
eg O
- O
r.--- O
v1 O
I O
I O
r O
] O
. O
' O
az O
R O
h O
n O
rs. O
ht O
t O
LJ O
= O
Yp-s O
v O
, O
A.N O
ei O
. O
,.-Y O
t O
.- O
e1& O
' O
a O
- O
: O
--- O
L O
. O
==-x----- O
.-' O
G O
anlA O
T- O
K- O
c1 O
-- O
2 O
1y O
--== O
--=- O
7 O
Jlpol O
witlat O
a O
ll O
TL1IAI O
M1AEPIEA O
TAC O
E O
R1Y O
. O
- O
--l O
1AL O
I4ai O
o O
U O
- O
iI2 O
-- O
V1. O
t O
H O
L-. O
- O
[ O
E O
. O
zL O
. O
. O
WY O
: O
ER O
1 S-CARDINAL
--1l O
a O
-- O
] O
] O
aRiI O
ieCE O
Y O
V O
1 O
.N O
N O
. O
| | O
L O
4 O
N O
N- O
L-P O
E O
rE O
e O
=L O
x=- O
5 O
e- O
g O
:'EHE O
IHLT O
LI O
. O
1 O
. O
h. O
tk O
M4 O
M O
. O
Lr. O
1 O
1 O
L O
a O
I1 O
nY O
K B-PERSON
- I-PERSON
L E-PERSON
... O
se O
A O
r O
. O
tn O
k O
r O
W O
) O
L-- O
ef O
7 O
R.a. O
J O
. O
1a O
El O
2 O
. O
ssN O
-n O
' O
A O
- O
. O
. O
- O
--: O
P O
yw O
. O
t O
i O
+ O
( O
L O
sWN O
YL O
nm O
I` O
e' O
s' O
n O
M O
1y O
r O
x O
., O
. O
d O
- O
3 O
. O
.P O
. O
- O
. O
s O
M O
.. O
.. O
i O
. O
i O
R O
X O
'o O
, O
4 S-CARDINAL
. O
' O
os O
--.L O
L O
. O
3 S-CARDINAL
t O
s-t O
, O
aer O
I O
: O
h O
:. O
A O
a O
-- O
i O
: O
, O
, O
ei O
y O
, O
' O
xt O
, O
- O
i O
v O
t O
t O
.aii O
' O
f O
r O
l O
. O
i- O
: O
E O
I. O
1.gA O
- O
i. O
Mi O
e- O
if O
I O
I1 O
. O
l O
gz=== O
z O
:---- O
E O
g O
A- O
9 O
i O
g O
2 S-CARDINAL
- O
es-- O
ai O
T O
F.l O
141Lx O
----- O
AN O
7 O
-. O
d- O
=. O
L O
- O
i O
I O
] O
> O
A O
. O
M--- O
I1g O
z=i O
FZE O
WEl O
tea O
% O
N O
kIN O
4 S-CARDINAL
3 O
1- O
--- O
tl O
I O
a O
: O
iI O
2 O
EM O
' O
La O
u O
t O
- O
a- O
A2zs O
:f O
h1 O
x- O
3w1LILAI O
SIALKEPEAE O
TLEA O
E O
AY O
RII4a O
' O
L O
Jspoel O
itthut O
a O
L O
: O
rr. O
- O
1S O
ELE O
r O
N1 O
- O
U O
=. O
II O
s2 O
e='Lz O
x=- O
- O
gF O
A O
yge O
hl O
II1 O
az O
. O
' O
I O
g O
A O
a' O
: O
t O
i O
.: O
. O
. O
. O
i O
. O
2 O
, O
. O
s O
i. O
4 O
' O
[ O
' O
z1 O
Ire= O
3 S-CARDINAL
-s O
n O
. O
A O
, O
a O
f O
, O
. O
fa O
. O
, O
Se O
: O
: O
it O
, O
. O
tkH O
-s O
t O
v O
' O
P'M O
- O
-t O
, O
d O
2 O
VANITY B-ORG
FAIR E-ORG
. O
Aoiel O
mitlout O
a O
ero. O
ea O
o O
e O
+ O
wA O
( O
o- O
' O
A O
D O
. O
PR0CIBR O
IIIIS O
8I0BI O
Is O
AFCII0 O
NAIEIL O
DEDICAIED O
. O
: O
fNL O
- O
eA O
se O
o O
BEFORE O
THE O
CURTAIN O
. O
As O
the O
MIanager O
of O
the O
Performance O
sits O
before O
the O
eurtain O
on O
the O
bonrds O
, O
and O
looks O
into O
the O
Fuir O
, O
a O
feeling O
of O
profound O
melancholy O
comes O
over O
him O
in O
his O
survey O
of O
the O
bustling O
place O
. O
There O
is O
a O
great O
quantity O
of O
eating O
' O
and O
drink O
- O
ing O
, O
making O
love O
and O
jilting O
, O
langhing O
and O
the O
contrary O
, O
smoking O
, O
cheating O
, O
fighting O
, O
dancing O
, O
and O
fiddling O
: O
there O
are O
bullies O
pushing O
about O
, O
bucks O
ogling O
the O
women O
, O
knaves O
picking O
pockets O
, O
policemen O
on O
the O
look O
- O
out O
, O
quacks O
( O
other O
quacks O
, O
plague O
take O
them O
l O
) O
bawling O
in O
front O
of O
their O
booths O
, O
and O
yokels O
looking O
up O
at O
the O
tinselled O
dancers O
and O
poor O
old O
rouged O
tumblers O
, O
while O
the O
light O
- O
fingered O
folk O
are O
operating O
upon O
their O
pockets O
behind O
. O
Yes O
, O
this O
is O
VIrY O
FAIn O
| | O
not O
a O
moral O
place O
certainly O
| | O
nor O
a O
merry O
one O
, O
though O
very O
noisy O
. O
Look O
at O
the O
faces O
of O
the O
nctors O
nnd O
buffoons O
when O
they O
come O
off O
from O
their O
business O
| | O
and O
Tom B-PERSON
Fool E-PERSON
washing O
the O
paint O
off O
his O
chceks O
before O
le O
sits O
down O
to O
dinner O
with O
his O
wife O
and O
the O
little O
Jack B-PERSON
Puddings E-PERSON
behind O
the O
canvass O
. O
The O
curtain O
will O
be O
up O
presently O
, O
nnd O
he O
will O
be O
turning O
over O
head O
and O
heels O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
How O
are O
you O
f O
'' O
A O
man O
with O
a O
reflective O
turn O
of O
mind O
, O
wnlking O
through O
viii O
BEFORE O
THE O
CURTAIN O
. O
an O
exshibition O
of O
tis O
sort O
, O
will O
not O
be O
oppressed O
, O
I O
take O
it O
, O
by O
his O
own O
or O
other O
people's O
hilarity O
. O
An O
episode O
of O
humour O
or O
kindncss O
touches O
and O
amuses O
him O
here O
and O
there O
| | O
- O
a O
pretty O
child O
looking O
at O
a O
gingerbread O
stall O
| | O
a O
pretty O
girl O
blushing O
whilst O
her O
loer O
talks O
to O
her O
and O
chooses O
her O
fairing O
| | O
poor O
Tom B-PERSON
Fool E-PERSON
, O
yonder O
behind O
the O
waggon O
, O
mumbling O
his O
bone O
with O
the O
honest O
family O
which O
lives O
by O
his O
tumbling O
| -| O
but O
the O
general O
impression O
is O
one O
more O
melancholy O
than O
mirthful O
. O
When O
you O
come O
home O
, O
you O
sit O
down O
, O
in O
a O
sober O
, O
contemplative O
, O
not O
unchnaritable O
frame O
of O
mind O
, O
and O
apply O
yourself O
to O
your O
books O
or O
your O
business O
. O
I O
have O
no O
other O
moral O
thnn O
this O
to O
tag O
to O
thc O
present O
story O
of O
Vanity B-WORK_OF_ART
Fair E-WORK_OF_ART
'' O
Some O
people O
consider O
Fairs O
immoral O
altogether O
, O
mnd O
eschew O
such O
, O
with O
their O
servants O
and O
families O
: O
perhaps O
they O
are O
right O
. O
But O
persons O
who O
think O
otherwise O
and O
are O
of O
a O
lay O
, O
or O
a O
benevolent O
, O
or O
a O
sarcastie O
mood O
, O
may O
perhaps O
like O
to O
step O
in O
for O
half B-TIME
an I-TIME
hour E-TIME
and O
look O
at O
the O
performauces O
. O
There O
are O
scenes O
of O
nll O
sorts O
| | O
some O
dreadful O
combats O
, O
some O
grand O
and O
lofty O
horse O
- O
riding O
, O
some O
scenes O
of O
high O
life O
, O
nnd O
some O
of O
very O
middling O
indeed O
| | O
some O
love O
making O
for O
the O
sentimental O
, O
and O
some O
light O
comic O
business O
: O
the O
whole O
accompanied O
by O
appropriate O
scenery O
, O
and O
brilliantly O
illuminated O
with O
the O
Author's O
own O
candles O
. O
What O
more O
has O
the O
Manager O
of O
the O
Performance O
to O
say O
?'- O
To O
acknowledge O
the O
kindness O
witli O
which O
it O
has O
been O
received O
in O
all O
the O
principal O
towns O
of O
England S-GPE
through O
which O
the O
Show O
has O
passed O
, O
and O
where O
it O
has O
been O
most O
favourably O
noticed O
by O
the O
respected O
conductors O
of O
the B-ORG
Public I-ORG
Press E-ORG
, O
and O
by O
the B-ORG
Nobility I-ORG
and I-ORG
Gentry E-ORG
. O
He O
is O
proud O
to O
think O
that O
his O
Puppets O
have O
given O
satisfaction O
to O
the O
very O
best O
company O
in O
this O
empire O
. O
BEORE O
THRE O
CURTAIN O
. O
The O
famons O
little O
Becky O
Puppet O
kas O
bcen O
pronouncei O
to O
be O
uncommonly O
flexible O
in O
the O
joints O
and O
lively O
on O
the O
wire O
: O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Amelia I-WORK_OF_ART
Doll E-WORK_OF_ART
, O
though O
it O
has O
had O
a O
smaller O
circle O
of O
admirers O
, O
has O
yct O
been O
cared O
and O
dressed O
with O
the O
greatest O
care O
by O
the O
artist O
: O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Dobbin I-WORK_OF_ART
Figure E-WORK_OF_ART
, O
though O
apparently O
clumsy O
, O
yet O
dances O
in O
a O
very O
amusing O
and O
natural O
manner O
: O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Little I-WORK_OF_ART
Boys' I-WORK_OF_ART
Dance E-WORK_OF_ART
has O
becn O
liked O
by O
some O
| | O
and O
please O
to O
remurk O
the O
richly O
dressed O
figure O
of O
the B-PERSON
Wicked I-PERSON
Nobleman E-PERSON
, O
on O
which O
no O
expense O
has O
been O
spared O
, O
and O
which O
Old O
Nick S-PERSON
will O
fetch O
away O
at O
th O
end O
of O
this O
singular O
performance O
. O
And O
with O
this O
, O
and O
a O
profound O
bow O
to O
his O
patrons O
, O
the O
MIanager S-ORG
retires O
, O
and O
the O
curtain O
rises O
. O
Losos. O
une O
28 O
, O
14d S-CARDINAL
. O
L. B-PERSON
A I-PERSON
eA E-PERSON
3 S-CARDINAL
l.-uWIc O
IALa O
coIEITS O
. O
2--t O
WRICI O
III O
RAIP O
AxD O
MI O
SEDL O
PPA O
rO O
OPEY O
TE O
.-mca O
1 O
1 O
IXIC O
O O
TE O
IIIIT O
. O
4.-II O
IIt O
IL O
UIE O
5-noIEn O
O O
0 O
6 O
.-AYIL O
7.-- O
cAWLT O
O O
D's O
cAWLI O
. O
-PIVMfk O
MD O
COIIDMTtAD O
--IIIYr O
HOAI O
10 O
, O
-ii3 O
ARP O
EIM O
T0 O
IIAKIE O
HIIND6 O
11.-- O
aCADLAI O
IIIIPLICITY O
. O
12.- O
rn O
A O
IIITAL O
. O
CAI B-PERSON
13 I-PERSON
- I-PERSON
nrnnanra E-PERSON
. O
aD O
OIWIE O
lL O
- O
I O
cnAWY O
A O
0 O
. O
2A O
33 S-CARDINAL
B O
| | O
6 S-CARDINAL
71 O
o7 O
97 O
.I04 O
. O
114 S-CARDINAL
ii O
coNTENT O
. O
I.- O
wIc O
CCA'5 O
SAD O
APPEA3 O
O O
1 O
OI O
TIME O
l6 O
, O
- O
TE O
LRTE O
ON O
TB O
PIMCEIOM O
. O
17.-OW O
CTAI O
DOIN O
B0UGn O
A O
HIAO O
10 O
, O
- O
wO O
PLAYED O
O O
TEI O
IAKO O
CTIN O
DOI O
BOGT1 O
. O
19 O
-- O
I O
cCWL O
R O
KUS O
. O
20 O
, O
- O
i O
wIC O
CPTAI O
DOnDI O
ACT3 O
A O
TE O
MESRGRR O
OF O
IFIY O
2l.-A O
AREIL O
1OU O
A O
IEIRBE.o O
22.- O
1AR1AE O
AND O
PARI O
O O
A1 O
HONNOON O
23 O
, O
--cAFAIR O
DOBII O
POCEDE O
0N O
MYI O
CANYA8a O
2A O
, O
-mx O
wIcR O
, O
uO O
TAR O
Dow O
IE O
AIILYT O
IIL O
129 O
2a---m O
wIICII O
AL O
E O
PIkCIAL O
PR3ONA O
TIIIK O
IT O
TO O
IE O
26 O
, O
-TWY O
L0ND0N O
AFD O
CHAIIHAII O
27 O
, O
-IN O
WIC O
ANEIIA O
OII O
I O
GIIIIT O
28 O
.- O
I O
wmICI O
AIELIA O
IIAD O
TE O
LOW O
COUMI O
29 O
, O
- O
UII O
50 O
, O
-' O
rE O
GIEL O
1 O
T O
ID O
' O
1l--i O
wIGI O
E O
DLIT O
TAS O
CA O
OF O
I O
I O
82 O
, O
-IR O
WIICHR O
0 O
AE O
LII O
, O
AAD O
TE O
WAY O
I O
OUT O
TO O
1 O
CLO O
. O
, O
-i O
wIIC O
MII O
CAWLT O
' O
ELATIOMI O
A O
YY O
IMI1OI O
OUr O
I. O
M4.-- O
aiH O
) O
CAWLIYs O
IF O
IB O
T O
0n O
3f O
, O
-wIDOW O
ND O
M0HRs O
,--nW O
T0 O
IE O
WELL O
OI O
IOTI O
A-YEAAl O
187 O
1l44 O
1sI O
16I O
1r0 O
171 O
18 O
19s O
1se O
20s O
a2s O
s O
2s1 O
2e O
2s7 O
26s O
a7s O
2ts O
9 O
si O
saI O
coNTENTS O
. O
-- O
raILr O
I O
A O
EH O
IALL O
A O
V.-A O
CrIICL O
CArr O
4l.- O
ra O
wIIC O
CIY O
IFIII0 O
E O
IALI O
O O
IE O
ACESIO8a O
42.-nar O
wICE O
IE O
IDMI O
HA O
T0 O
DOLE O
nE O
CPE O
. O
xiii O
. O
M29 O
M1 O
379 O
W.-A O
Omn-AOI O
CAFIE O
WI O
OMD0 O
AIID O
IAIIIa O
. O
3 O
45.- O
TWE O
IANIH1 O
AID O
oDO O
. O
4., O
--rh O
IID O
TIAI O
47-oAUYT O
0UE O
402 O
4I0 O
. O
4171 O
423 O
434 O
4Il O
Bl. O
- O
i O
WIIcCR O
1 O
CIIARD O
1 O
AcCD O
wIIC O
MAYF O
O O
0T O
PUEELR O
I O
449 O
-n O
rIcn O
LoD O
HIYT O
II O
RIMRLF O
IR O
A O
MIOS O
AXIALE O
LI0OmTT. O
4f64 O
.M-A O
CE O
AD O
A O
AILTOPE O
. O
M4 O
, O
- O
saa O
AIT O
TR O
A. O
.- O
ms O
wICI O
TE O
IE O
hC O
I O
PUUD O
M0d O
, O
- O
ooY O
I3 O
aDR O
1 O
0HIILEYN O
. O
8 O
.- O
oI O
4T3 O
xis O
9- O
nI O
OLD O
FIAIO0 O
coNrENTS O
. O
6 S-CARDINAL
, O
--- O
IUIU O
T0 O
TEE O
ML O
WOI. O
8l O
, O
- O
nn O
wI O
0 O
LIIII O
AIE O
U O
62---II O
IIo O
8 O
, O
-I O
wEIC O
W O
III O
AI O
0LD O
MAIITAICE O
6 O
, O
-ULL O
OF O
IIIII O
lYD O
LAt O
66 O
- O
aIAIIT O
ILB O
6--wIc O
0AIIf O
II O
1nAR O
AXD O
DIAT3 O
. O
iM2I O
. O
0 O
.. O
6 O
.M5 O
. O
57 S-CARDINAL
. O
M62 O
. O
S7 O
. O
391 O
. O
598 O
a. O
811 O
LISI O
OF O
PLAIES O
Trs O
Lmrrzn O
nronR O
WIOo O
icxrE O
TirLA O
Racc's O
FanEwELL O
. O
Mn. O
, O
atstI O
rAOLED O
Mn. O
aossr O
IR O
A O
Sra O
o O
ExrRI O
ROCA O
IIK O
AcalraCR O
w O
1 O
LIY O
BONI O
. O
Mns O
Sanr O
In O
E O
ScIooL O
- O
Roo O
Mnss O
CnwL's O
acIOa O
RLTIES O
Ms. O
Ossonx B-PERSON
WLco E-PERSON
o O
ABLIA O
LI O
OsBOE O
D O
II O
ADE O
LOYR O
- O
LrrES O
TE O
Norm O
on O
PIxcUsuIo S-GPE
. O
Ax O
rmmr O
ron O
Sr. O
Mn. O
Spsr O
Ar O
ru O
CoFE- O
Hos O
Mt O
SwTE O
ARI O
FO O
TE O
DAWI O
- O
Roo O
Eaio O
BrBLE O
rACrII6 O
TE O
An O
O O
W.. O
A O
FLr O
Panrr O
r O
Banro O
Mins O
. O
ODowp O
ruE O
FLows O
MnT O
M. O
Osotss O
CnA O
rrINa O
rE O
W O
. O
Prontispleee O
. O
. O
10 S-CARDINAL
. O
140 S-CARDINAL
. O
145 S-CARDINAL
. O
17 S-CARDINAL
. O
2335 S-CARDINAL
xi O
LIBT O
OP O
PLATES O
. O
WEE O
EPARIN O
T O
AO O
O O
M. O
MIn. O
os O
saYs O
OF O
I O
MscnIos O
Mn. O
Jais's O
Pr O
P O
oOR O
Mion O
SvonPLs O
MIns O
. O
RwDo's O
DFAR O
RO O
PaIs O
Gonar O
akES O
Acaxrcr O
wI O
A O
Woo O
M O
T O
RIos O
Dscorxnxn O
m O
Facr. O
Sm O
Pis O
asr O
Srao O
GonNa O
TnIE O
Ith O
FscIArIo O
o O
TnIE O
MroR. O
Tn O
AnIA O
r O
QnEN's O
CWLF O
. O
Bcsr O
Ix O
LonaD O
- O
SrE. O
GORGT O
0 O
H0 O
CURCII O
GRIFLL O
. O
Tu O
TarR O
oP O
CLrIEIISrA O
. O
CoLoEL O
CnAWLEY O
I O
WAMD O
Sm O
Ps O
Srnr O
Cm O
GsoRG O
GITLRXIAH O
A O
MrIao O
. O
Mn. O
Ios's O
HooaDAR O
. O
A O
FI O
SR O
EvIG O
. O
os O
rEOR O
I O
PooI8 O
Bck's O
Scoro O
APiRNc O
I O
TRE O
CC O
O O
CLTA O
. O
Vars O
RxwAD O
| | O
A O
Boor O
In O
VaIrr O
FI O
. O
. O
237 O
r9 O
s07 O
s19 O
szz O
30 O
339 O
3621 O
87 O
400 O
433 O
44 O
SB O
46s O
481 O
302 O
s2s O
sss O
360 B-QUANTITY
56s I-QUANTITY
ezs E-QUANTITY
s24 O
- O
e O
f O
.I O
eR O
! O
- O
i. O
T O
I O
v O
A O
NITY O
FA O
I O
R. O
VHA O
Nl O
iitfout O
a O
ter O
. O
ae O
cI O
APTER O
I. O
cIISWICK O
MALL O
. O
NN O
g- O
7'A O
ft O
- O
. O
Nay S-PERSON
, O
the O
acute O
observer O
might O
have O
recognised O
the O
little O
red O
nose O
of O
good O
- O
naturel O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
Pinkerton E-PERSON
herself O
, O
rising O
oer O
some O
geranium O
- O
pots O
in O
the O
window O
of O
that O
lady's O
own O
drawing O
- O
room O
. O
' O
It O
is O
Mrs. O
Sedley's S-PERSON
coaeh O
, O
sister O
, O
'' O
said O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
. O
The O
girls O
were O
up O
at O
four B-TIME
this I-TIME
morning E-TIME
, O
packing O
her O
trnks O
, O
sister O
, O
'i O
repliel O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
| | O
'` O
we O
have O
made O
her O
a O
bow O
- O
pot O
. O
'' O
vAITY O
FAIR O
. O
'' O
'' O
And O
I O
trust O
, O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
, O
you O
have O
made O
a O
copy O
of O
Miss O
Sedley's S-PERSON
1 O
l O
. O
l O
. O
5L O
HI O
. O
11N O
, O
I O
:IM O
. O
I1 O
I O
1.I O
I O
I O
I1 O
. O
II1 O
ILL O
III O
IC O
IIHi O
1u. O
1 S-CARDINAL
. O
Ke O
:. O
==== O
sg O
-':- O
d O
----'------ O
-1 O
1 S-CARDINAL
siiF O
. O
s=-E-- O
aceount O
. O
This O
is O
it O
, O
is O
it O
Very O
gool O
- O
ninety B-QUANTITY
- I-QUANTITY
three I-QUANTITY
pounds E-QUANTITY
, O
four S-CARDINAL
shil- O
lings O
. O
Be O
kind O
enough O
to O
address O
it O
to O
John B-PERSON
Sedlcy E-PERSON
, O
Esquire S-ORG
, O
and O
to O
sel O
this O
billet O
which O
I O
hae O
written O
to O
his O
lsdy O
. O
In O
the O
present O
instance O
Miss O
Pinkerton's S-PERSON
`` O
illet'' O
was O
to O
the O
following O
efect O
:- O
7he B-PERSON
Mall E-PERSON
, O
Oliseick S-GPE
, O
Juns B-DATE
15 E-DATE
, O
168 S-CARDINAL
- O
. O
as O
a O
young O
lady O
not O
nworthy O
to O
occwupy O
a O
fitting O
position O
in O
their O
polished O
nnd O
refined O
circle O
. O
Those O
virtues O
which O
charucterise O
the O
young O
English S-LANGUAGE
gentlewoman O
, O
those O
accomplishments O
which O
bceome O
her O
birth O
nnd O
station O
, O
wiill O
not O
be O
found O
wanting O
in O
the O
aiable O
Miss O
Selley S-PERSON
, O
whose O
induaftry O
nnd O
ohedience O
hae O
endeared O
her O
to O
her O
instructors O
, O
and O
whose O
delightful O
sweetness O
of O
tempcr O
has O
charmed O
her O
aged O
and O
her O
youlfl O
companions O
. O
In O
the O
principles O
of O
religion O
und O
norality O
, O
Miss O
edley O
will O
be O
founl O
worthy O
of O
an O
establishnent O
whichi O
has O
been O
honoured O
by O
the O
presenee O
o1 O
Tle O
Great O
Leicograpler O
, O
and O
the O
patronage O
of O
the O
ndmirnbhle O
Mrs. O
Cha- S-PERSON
one O
. O
'' O
eP.S. O
Miss O
Slarp S-PERSON
aceompanies O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
. O
It O
is O
partieularly O
re- O
quested O
that O
Miss O
Sharp's S-PERSON
stay O
in O
lussell B-FAC
Square E-FAC
may O
not O
exccl O
ten S-CARDINAL
duys O
. O
On O
the O
cover O
wns O
inserted O
a O
copy O
of O
`` O
Lines O
ddressed O
to O
a O
young O
lnty O
on O
quitting O
Miss O
Pinkerton's S-PERSON
sclool O
, O
at O
thc B-FAC
Mall E-FAC
| | O
by O
the O
late O
revered O
Doctor O
Sumucl B-PERSON
Johnson E-PERSON
. O
'' O
In O
fact O
, O
the O
Lcxi- O
cographer's O
nme O
wns O
always O
on O
the O
lips O
of O
this O
majestic O
woman O
, O
and O
a O
visit O
he O
had O
paid O
to O
her O
was O
the O
cause O
of O
her O
reputation O
nnd O
her O
fortune O
. O
Being O
commnndel O
by O
her O
elder O
sister O
to O
get O
`` O
the O
Dictionary O
'' O
fromn O
the O
cupboard O
, O
Miss O
Jemims S-PERSON
hd O
extractcd O
two S-CARDINAL
copies O
of O
the O
hook O
fromn O
thc O
receptale O
in O
qnestion O
. O
When O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
had O
finished O
the O
inscrip- O
tion O
in O
thoe O
first S-ORDINAL
, O
Jemima S-PERSON
, O
with O
rather O
a O
dubious O
and O
timid O
air O
, O
handed O
ler O
the O
seeond O
. O
or O
whom O
is O
this O
, O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
? O
'' O
snid O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
with O
awful O
zoldness O
. O
or O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp E-PERSON
, O
'' O
mnswered O
Jemima S-PERSON
, O
trembiing O
very O
mnch O
, O
and O
blushing O
over O
her O
witherel O
face O
and O
ueck O
, O
as O
she O
turned O
her O
back O
on O
her O
sister O
. O
For O
Bccky B-PERSON
Sharp E-PERSON
: O
she's O
going O
too O
. O
'' O
MISS O
JEMIMA O
.'' O
exelsimcd O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
in O
tlo O
largest O
eapitals O
. O
`` O
Are O
you O
in O
your O
senses O
? O
Replace O
the O
Dixonary O
in O
the O
closet O
, O
and O
neer O
ventnre O
to O
take O
such O
a O
liberty O
in O
future O
. O
'' O
WII O
, O
sister O
, O
it's O
only O
two S-CARDINAL
- O
and O
- O
ninepence O
, O
aund O
poor O
Becky S-PERSON
will O
be O
nisernble O
if O
she O
lon't O
get O
one O
. O
'' O
n O
2 S-CARDINAL
VANITY O
AIIl O
. O
Send O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
instantly O
to O
me O
, O
'' O
said O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
. O
Aud O
so O
vcuturing O
not O
to O
say O
another O
word O
, O
poor O
Jemima S-PERSON
trotted O
off O
, O
exceedingly O
tlurried O
aud O
nervous O
. O
Although O
Schoolmistresses' O
letters O
are O
to O
be O
trusted O
no O
more O
nor O
less O
than O
clurchyard O
epitaphs O
| | O
yet O
, O
as O
it O
sometimcs O
happens O
that O
n O
person O
lepurts O
this O
life O
, O
who O
is O
really O
dcserving O
of O
all O
thc O
prises O
the O
stone O
- O
cutter O
carvcs O
over O
his O
bones O
| | O
who O
is O
a O
gool O
Christian S-NORP
, O
a O
good O
parent O
, O
child O
, O
wife O
or O
husbnud O
| | O
who O
actually O
does O
leave O
a O
disconsolute O
family O
to O
mourn O
his O
loss O
| | O
so O
in O
academies O
of O
thc O
male O
and O
female O
sex O
it O
oecurs O
eery O
now O
and O
then O
, O
thut O
the O
pupil O
is O
fully O
worthy O
of O
the O
praises O
bcstowed O
by O
the O
disinterested O
instructor O
. O
For O
shc O
couldl O
not O
only O
sing O
like O
a O
lark O
, O
or O
a O
Mrs. O
Billington S-PERSON
, O
nnd O
dance O
like O
Hillisberg S-PERSON
or O
' O
urisot O
| | O
and O
enibroider O
beauntifully O
| | O
and O
spcll O
as O
well O
as O
the O
Dixonary O
itselt O
| | O
but O
sle O
had O
sucl O
a O
kindly O
, O
smiling O
, O
tender O
, O
gentle O
, O
gcnerous O
heart O
of O
her O
own O
, O
ns O
won O
thc O
love O
of O
everybody O
who O
cme O
near O
er O
, O
from O
Minerva S-PERSON
herself O
down O
to O
the O
poor O
girl O
in O
the O
scullery O
, O
anl O
the O
onc O
- O
cyed O
tartwoman's O
duaughtecr O
, O
who O
wus O
permitted O
to O
vend O
her O
wares O
once O
a O
week O
to O
the O
young O
laudies O
in O
the O
Mall O
. O
Even O
envious O
Miss O
Briggs S-PERSON
never O
spoke O
ill O
of O
ler O
: O
higl O
and O
mighty O
Miss O
Sultire S-PERSON
( O
Lord O
Dexster's S-PERSON
grand O
- O
dauglter O
) O
allowel O
thiat O
her O
figure O
was O
genteel O
: O
and O
as O
for O
MIiss O
nrtz O
, O
the O
rich O
woolly O
- O
haired O
mulatto O
from O
S5t O
. O
Kitt's S-PERSON
, O
on O
the O
dny O
Ameclia O
went O
away O
, O
she O
was O
in O
such O
a O
passion O
of O
tenrs O
, O
thnt O
they O
were O
obligel O
to O
send O
for O
Dr. O
TFloss S-PERSON
, O
and O
half O
tipsify O
her O
with O
salvolatile O
. O
Miss O
Pinkerton's S-PERSON
uttachcnt O
was O
, O
as O
may O
be O
supposed O
, O
from O
the O
high O
position O
and O
eminent O
virtues O
of O
that O
lady O
, O
calm O
nud O
liguified O
| | O
but O
Mliss B-PERSON
Jemima E-PERSON
had O
already O
blubberecl O
several O
times O
at O
the O
idea O
of O
Amelia's S-PERSON
departure O
| | O
and O
, O
but O
for O
fear O
of O
her O
sister O
, O
would O
hve O
gone O
off O
in O
downright O
hysterics O
, O
like O
the O
heiress O
( O
who O
pail O
donble O
) O
of O
St. B-GPE
Kitt's E-GPE
. O
Such O
luxury O
of O
grief O
, O
however O
, O
is O
only O
allowed O
to O
parlour O
- O
boarders O
. O
Honest O
Jemima S-PERSON
lad O
ull O
te O
bills O
, O
and O
the O
washing O
, O
and O
the O
mendiug O
, O
and O
the O
puddings O
, O
and O
the O
plate O
and O
crockery O
, O
nnd O
the O
servants O
to O
superintend O
. O
But O
why O
speak O
about O
hcr O
It O
is O
probable O
that O
we O
shall O
not O
hear O
of O
her O
again O
from O
tlis O
moment O
to O
the O
end O
of O
time O
, O
and O
that O
whcn O
the O
great O
filligrec O
iron O
gates O
are O
once O
closed O
on O
her O
, O
sle O
and O
her O
awful O
sister O
will O
never O
issue O
tlerefrom O
into O
this O
little O
world O
of O
history O
. O
But O
as O
we O
are O
to O
see O
a O
great O
denl O
of O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
tlcre O
is O
no O
harm O
in O
saying O
at O
the O
outset O
of O
our O
aequaintancc O
, O
that O
she O
was O
one O
of O
the O
best O
and O
denrest O
creatures O
that O
evcr O
lived O
| | O
and O
a O
great O
mercy O
it O
is O
, O
both O
in O
life O
and O
in O
novcls O
, O
which O
( O
and O
the O
luatter O
especially O
) O
abound O
in O
villains O
of O
the O
most O
somhre O
sort O
, O
that O
we O
nre O
to O
have O
for O
n O
constant O
companion O
, O
so O
guilelcss O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
IIERO O
. O
and O
good O
- O
naturel O
a O
person O
. O
As O
she O
is O
not O
a O
heroine O
, O
there O
is O
no O
neod O
to O
lescribe O
her O
person O
| | O
indeed O
I O
am O
afraid O
thut O
her O
nose O
was O
rather O
short O
than O
otherwise O
, O
and O
her O
cheeks O
a O
great O
deal O
too O
round O
and O
red O
for O
a O
eroine O
| | O
but O
her O
face O
blushed O
with O
rosy O
health O
, O
and O
her O
lips O
with O
the O
freshest O
of O
smiles O
, O
and O
sle O
had O
a O
pair O
of O
eyes O
, O
which O
sparkled O
with O
tho O
brightest O
and O
honestest O
good O
- O
humour O
, O
except O
indeed O
when O
they O
filled O
with O
tears O
, O
and O
that O
was O
a O
great O
deal O
too O
often O
| | O
for O
the O
silly O
thing O
would O
cry O
over O
a O
dead O
canary O
- O
bird O
, O
or O
over O
a O
mouse O
, O
that O
the O
cat O
haply O
had O
seized O
upon O
, O
or O
over O
the O
end O
of O
n O
novl O
, O
were O
it O
ever O
so O
stupid O
| | O
and O
ns O
for O
saying O
an O
unkind O
word O
to O
her O
, O
were O
any O
one O
hard O
- O
hearted O
enough O
to O
do O
so O
, O
- O
why O
, O
so O
much O
the O
worse O
for O
them O
. O
So O
that O
when O
the O
dny O
of O
departure O
cme O
, O
betwecn O
her O
two S-CARDINAL
customs O
of O
laugluing O
and O
crying O
, O
Mliss B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
was O
greatly O
puzled O
how O
toact O
. O
She O
was O
glad O
to O
go O
home O
, O
and O
yet O
most O
wofully O
sad O
at O
leaving O
school O
. O
For O
tlurce O
days O
before O
, O
little O
Lnura B-PERSON
Martin E-PERSON
, O
the O
orphan O
, O
followedl O
her O
about O
, O
likc O
a O
little O
dog O
. O
'' O
Al O
, O
--- O
5 O
:=K O
I. O
1L O
- O
- O
I O
-- O
I O
, O
I O
E O
1 O
- O
r O
Al O
l- O
I-== O
L=t O
Y O
zz O
= O
- O
2 O
( O
. O
LS O
: O
LA O
CMM O
I O
--. O
rlich O
details O
, O
I O
have O
no O
doubt O
, O
JoxEs S-PERSON
, O
who O
reas O
this O
book O
at O
his O
Club S-ORG
, O
ANIIY O
FAIR O
. O
Well O
, O
then O
. O
The O
flowers O
, O
and O
the O
presents O
, O
and O
the O
trunks O
, O
nnd O
bonuet- O
boxes O
of O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
laving O
been O
arranged O
by O
Mr. O
Sambo S-PERSON
in O
the O
carriage O
, O
together O
with O
a O
very O
small O
and O
weuther O
- O
beaten O
old O
cow's O
- O
skin O
trunk O
with O
Miss O
Sharp's S-PERSON
cnrd O
neatly O
niled O
upon O
it O
, O
which O
was O
delivered O
by O
ambo O
with O
a O
grin O
, O
and O
pcked O
by O
the O
coachman O
with O
n O
corresponding O
sneer O
- O
tho O
hour O
for O
parting O
cnme O
| | O
and O
the O
griof O
of O
that O
moment O
was O
econsiderably O
lessened O
by O
the O
admirable O
discourse O
which O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
nddressel O
to O
her O
pupil O
. O
Not O
thnt O
the O
parting O
speech O
caused O
Amelia S-PERSON
to O
philosophise O
, O
or O
that O
it O
nrmed O
her O
in O
any O
way O
with O
a O
calmness O
, O
the O
result O
of O
argument O
| | O
but O
it O
was O
intolerably O
dull O
, O
popous O
, O
and O
tedious O
| | O
and O
having O
the O
fear O
of O
ler O
schoolmistress O
gretly O
before O
her O
eyes O
, O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
did O
not O
venture O
, O
in O
her O
presence O
, O
to O
give O
wuy O
to O
any O
ebullitions O
of O
private O
grief O
. O
A O
seed O
- O
cake O
and O
a O
bottle O
of O
wine O
were O
producel O
in O
the O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
as O
on O
the O
solemn O
oceasions O
of O
the O
visit O
of O
parents O
, O
and O
these O
refresh O
- O
ments O
being O
partaken O
of O
, O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
was O
at O
liberty O
to O
dcpart O
. O
You O
'll O
go O
in O
and O
say O
good O
by O
to O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
Becky S-PERSON
'' O
said O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
to O
a O
young O
lady O
of O
wlom O
nobody O
took O
any O
notice O
, O
and O
who O
was O
coming O
down O
stairs O
with O
her O
own O
handboxs O
. O
I O
suppose O
I O
must O
, O
'' O
said O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
calmly O
, O
and O
much O
to O
the O
wonler O
of O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
| | O
and O
the O
latter O
having O
knocked O
at O
the O
door O
, O
and O
reeciving O
permission O
to O
come O
in O
, O
Miss O
Shnrp S-PERSON
udvanced O
in O
a O
very O
uneoncerned O
man- O
ner O
, O
and O
suid O
in O
French S-LANGUAGE
, O
and O
with O
a O
perfect O
accent O
, O
`` O
Mademoiselle S-PERSON
, O
je O
viens O
vous O
faire O
mes O
adieux O
. O
'' O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
did O
not O
understand O
French S-LANGUAGE
| | O
she O
only O
lireetel O
those O
who O
did O
: O
but O
biting O
her O
lips O
and O
tlrowing O
up O
her O
venerable O
and O
Roman- S-NORP
osed O
head O
, O
( O
on O
the O
to O
of O
which O
figured O
a O
large O
and O
solemn O
turban O
, O
) O
she O
said O
, O
`` O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
I O
wish O
yo O
a O
good O
morning O
. O
'' O
As O
the O
llammersmitl O
Semiramis O
spokc O
, O
she O
waved O
one O
hnnd O
both O
by O
wny O
of O
adieu O
, O
and O
to O
givc O
Miss O
Bhnrp S-PERSON
an O
opportunity O
of O
shaking O
ono O
of O
the O
fingers O
of O
the O
land O
wlieh O
was O
left O
out O
for O
thst O
purpose O
. O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
only O
folded O
her O
own O
hands O
with O
a O
vcry O
frigil O
smile O
nnd O
bow O
, O
and O
quite O
declined O
to O
accept O
the O
proffered O
honour O
| | O
on O
whicl O
Semirmis S-PERSON
tossed O
up O
ler O
turban O
more O
indignantly O
thmn O
ever O
. O
In O
faet O
, O
it O
was O
a O
little O
battle O
between O
the O
young O
lady O
and O
the O
old O
one O
, O
and O
the O
latter O
was O
worsted O
. O
Heaven O
bless O
you O
, O
my O
child O
, O
'' O
ssid O
she O
, O
embracing O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
and O
scowling O
the O
while O
over O
the O
girl's O
shoulder O
at O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
. O
` O
Come O
away O
, O
Becky S-PERSON
, O
'' O
said O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
, O
pulling O
the O
young O
woman O
away O
in O
great O
alarm O
, O
and O
the O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
closed O
upon O
them O
for O
ever O
. O
Then O
came O
the O
struggle O
and O
parting O
below O
. O
Words O
refuee O
to O
tell O
it O
. O
All O
the O
serants O
were O
there O
in O
the O
hall O
- O
all O
the O
dcar O
friends O
- O
nll O
the O
young O
ladies O
- O
the O
dancing O
- O
master O
who O
had O
just O
arrived O
| | O
and O
there O
was O
such O
a O
scuffling O
, O
and O
hugging O
, O
and O
kissing O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
with O
the O
hysterical O
yoeps O
i O
t O
a O
:- O
2 S-CARDINAL
. O
aiEcE O
wZ. O
- O
' O
.2 O
- O
Ese- O
i O
. O
1L O
11 S-CARDINAL
: O
::. O
RLLL O
I O
.1l O
I O
y1 O
1IlI O
1 O
I:3 O
. O
2 S-CARDINAL
IL O
.I1 O
sd O
- O
I O
.:1I O
- O
aJ O
1 O
7 O
`. O
a O
JI O
4 O
.l O
2 O
I O
- O
a5 O
| | O
Sl O
s O
LL O
:11 O
, O
- O
A O
< O
:,3 O
EE O
Yak O
: O
.A O
- O
N O
, O
1 S-CARDINAL
, O
. O
.A O
, O
, O
. O
. O
, O
' O
M O
:. O
, O
. O
.r. O
'.. O
1 S-CARDINAL
: O
it O
. O
:7I O
: O
( O
: O
i O
. O
- O
. O
I O
N. O
" O
: O
e-- O
1 S-CARDINAL
r O
- O
I O
E O
. O
: O
e1-'' O
= O
.. O
g O
c O
, O
L O
NF O
5 O
-. O
ie O
H O
a O
, O
r O
z O
L O
t O
.sk O
' O
1T O
W. O
- O
h- O
I O
R O
, O
3 O
. O
r O
. O
ri-. O
iix O
: O
A O
- O
:zaRG O
, O
Z. O
c O
. O
. O
. O
A O
NOYIEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HEO. O
of O
Miss O
Swartz S-PERSON
, O
the O
parlour O
- O
boarder O
, O
from O
her O
room O
, O
as O
no O
pen O
cn O
depiet O
, O
and O
ns O
the O
tender O
henrt O
would O
fain O
psss O
over O
. O
The O
embracing O
was O
over O
| | O
they O
parted O
- O
that O
is O
, O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
parted O
from O
her O
friends O
. O
Miss O
Shar S-PERSON
lad O
demurely O
entered O
the O
carriage O
some B-TIME
minutes I-TIME
before E-TIME
. O
Nobody O
cried O
for O
leaving O
er. O
Sambo B-PERSON
of I-PERSON
the I-PERSON
bnndy I-PERSON
- I-PERSON
legs E-PERSON
slammed O
the O
cuarriage O
- O
door O
on O
his O
young O
wcep O
- O
ing O
mistress O
. O
He O
spraug O
up O
beliud O
the O
cariuge O
. O
' O
Stop O
l'' O
cried O
Mliss B-PERSON
Jemia E-PERSON
, O
rushing O
to O
the O
gate O
with O
a O
pareel O
. O
ii O
iia O
o O
A. O
: O
xass O
e O
huugry O
, O
you O
know O
| | O
and O
Bccky S-PERSON
, O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp E-PERSON
, O
here's O
a O
iok O
for O
you O
that O
y O
sistr O
- O
that O
is O
, O
I O
, O
- O
Johnson's O
Dixonary O
, O
you O
know O
| :| O
you O
mustn't O
lcae O
us O
without O
that O
. O
Good O
by O
. O
Drive O
on O
, O
coachman O
. O
Go O
blcss O
youl O
' O
' O
And O
the O
kind O
oreature O
retreated O
into O
the O
garden O
, O
overcome O
with O
emotions O
. O
lut O
, O
lol O
and O
just O
as O
the O
coaeh O
drove O
off O
, O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
put O
her O
pale O
face O
out O
of O
the O
window O
, O
and O
atlly O
flung O
the O
book O
baik O
into O
the O
garden O
. O
This O
almost O
caused O
Jemima S-PERSON
to O
faint O
with O
terror O
. O
: O
Well O
, O
I O
neer O
, O
''-- O
said O
she O
-`` O
what O
an O
audacious O
''- O
Emotion O
prevented O
her O
from O
completing O
cither O
sentence O
. O
1he O
crriage O
relled O
away O
| | O
g O
the O
great O
gates O
were O
closed O
| | O
the O
bell O
ang O
for O
the O
dancing O
lesson O
. O
The O
workd O
is O
before O
the O
two S-CARDINAL
young O
lsdies O
| | O
and O
so O
, O
fsrewell O
to O
Chiswick B-FAC
Mall E-FAC
. O
N- O
A. O
Il O
: O
s O
-t O
1- O
) O
1 O
-. O
- O
1 O
- O
9 O
7 O
1 O
- O
A O
, O
:- O
-.I O
. O
| | O
- O
- O
-. O
. O
L.--' O
cIAPTER O
II O
. O
IN O
WIIICR O
IS8 O
SIIABP O
AND O
MIsSs O
sEDLEY O
PEPAE O
TO O
OPEN O
r O
TIIE O
CAMPAIGN O
. O
r O
nN O
Miss O
Sharp O
lad O
performed O
the O
leroical O
act O
mentionecd O
9 S-CARDINAL
in O
tle O
lust O
chapter O
, O
and O
had O
seen O
the O
Dixonary O
flying O
ILEEE: O
C O
countenance O
, O
whiceh O
had O
before O
worn O
an O
nlmost O
livid O
look O
tA O
f-' O
f O
hatrcd O
, O
assumed O
a O
smile O
that O
perhaps O
was O
scarcely O
more O
agreeable O
, O
and O
she O
sank O
back O
in O
the O
carriage O
in O
n O
csy O
fme O
of O
minl O
, O
saying O
, O
-`` O
So O
much O
for O
the O
Dixonary O
| | O
and O
, O
thank O
God O
, O
I'm O
out O
of O
Chiswick S-GPE
. O
'' O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
was O
almost O
as O
flurried O
at O
the O
act O
of O
defiance O
as O
Miss O
Jemima S-PERSON
had O
been O
| | O
for O
, O
consider O
, O
it O
was O
but O
one B-TIME
minute E-TIME
that O
she O
hal O
left O
school O
, O
and O
the O
impressions O
of O
six S-CARDINAL
ycars O
are O
not O
got O
over O
in O
that O
space O
of O
time O
. O
Nay S-PERSON
, O
with O
some O
persons O
those O
awes O
and O
terrors O
of O
youth O
last O
for O
ever O
and O
evcr O
. O
I O
know O
, O
for O
instance O
, O
an O
old O
gcntleman O
of O
sixty B-DATE
- I-DATE
eight E-DATE
, O
who O
said O
to O
me O
one O
moring O
at O
brekfast O
, O
will O
n O
very O
gitted O
countennce O
, O
I O
dreamed O
last O
night O
that O
I O
was O
flogged O
by O
Dr. O
ine O
. O
Dr. O
Raine S-PERSON
and O
his O
rod O
were O
just O
as O
awful O
to O
him O
in O
his O
heart O
, O
then O
, O
at O
sixty B-DATE
- I-DATE
eight E-DATE
, O
as O
they O
had O
been O
at O
thirteen S-DATE
. O
How O
could O
you O
do O
so O
, O
RebeccaP S-PERSON
'' O
at O
lset O
she O
said O
, O
ufter O
a O
pause O
. O
Why O
, O
do O
you O
think O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
will O
come O
out O
and O
order O
me O
back O
to O
the O
black O
- O
hole O
'' O
snid O
Rebecca S-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
No O
: O
but O
--'' O
I O
hate O
the O
whole O
house O
, O
'' O
continued O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
in O
a O
fury O
. O
`` O
I O
hope O
I O
may O
never O
set O
eycs O
on O
it O
again O
. O
I O
wish O
it O
were O
in O
the O
bottom O
of O
the O
Thames S-LOC
, O
I O
do O
| | O
and O
if O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
were O
there O
, O
I O
wouldn O
't O
pick O
her O
out O
, O
that O
I O
wouldn't O
. O
O O
how O
I O
should O
like O
to O
see O
her O
floating O
in O
the O
water O
yonder O
, O
turban O
and O
all O
, O
with O
her O
train O
atreaming O
after O
her O
, O
and O
her O
nos O
like O
the O
bek O
of O
a O
wherry O
, O
'' O
Hush O
I'' O
cried O
Miss O
Sedley S-PERSON
. O
e O
Why O
, O
wil O
the O
black O
footman O
tell O
tales2 O
'' O
cried O
Miss O
Rebeeca S-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
He O
may O
go O
back O
and O
tell O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
that O
I O
hute O
her O
with O
all O
my O
soul O
| | O
and O
I O
wish O
he O
would O
| | O
and O
I O
wish O
I O
had O
a O
means O
of O
proving O
it O
too O
. O
For O
two B-DATE
years E-DATE
I O
have O
only O
had O
insults O
and O
outrage O
from O
her O
. O
I O
have O
been O
treated O
worse O
than O
any O
serant O
in O
the O
kitchen O
. O
I O
have O
never O
had O
n O
friend O
or O
a O
kind O
word O
, O
except O
from O
you O
. O
I O
have O
been O
made O
to O
tend O
the O
little O
girls O
A O
NOYEL O
WITEODT O
A O
HER0 O
. O
in O
the O
lower O
schoolroom O
, O
and O
to O
talk O
French S-LANGUAGE
to O
the O
Misses O
, O
until O
I O
grew O
sick O
of O
my O
mother O
- O
tongue O
. O
But O
that O
talking O
Freuch S-PERSON
to O
Miss O
linkerton O
was O
capital O
fun O
, O
wasn't O
itP O
She O
docsn't O
know O
a O
word O
of O
French S-LANGUAGE
, O
anl O
was O
too O
proud O
to O
confess O
it O
. O
I O
believe O
it O
was O
that O
which O
made O
her O
purt O
with O
ne O
| | O
and O
so O
thunk O
Heaven O
for O
French S-LANGUAGE
. O
ie O
la O
France S-GPE
1 O
ioe O
l'lwpereur O
l O
ise O
BonaparteI O
'' O
O O
Rebecca O
, O
Rebecn S-PERSON
, O
for O
shamel'' O
cried O
Miss O
Seley S-PERSON
| | O
for O
tlis O
was O
the O
greatest O
blasphemy O
Rebccca S-PERSON
had O
ns O
yet O
uttered O
| | O
and O
in O
those O
dys O
, O
in O
England S-GPE
, O
to O
say O
`` O
Long B-WORK_OF_ART
live I-WORK_OF_ART
Bonaparte I-WORK_OF_ART
I'' E-WORK_OF_ART
was O
as O
much O
as O
to O
say O
`` O
Loug B-WORK_OF_ART
live I-WORK_OF_ART
Lucifer1 E-WORK_OF_ART
' O
' O
IIow O
can O
you O
- O
how O
dure O
you O
have O
such O
wickcd O
, O
revengeful O
thoughts O
'' O
` O
Revenge O
may O
be O
wicked O
, O
but O
it O
's O
nutural O
, O
'' O
answered O
Miss O
ebecca S-PERSON
. O
I O
'm O
no O
angel O
. O
'' O
And O
, O
to O
say O
the O
truth O
, O
she O
eertainly O
was O
not O
. O
Miss O
Rebeccen S-PERSON
was O
not O
, O
tlen O
, O
in O
the O
least O
kind O
or O
placable O
. O
All O
the O
world O
used O
her O
ill O
, O
said O
this O
young O
misanthropist O
( O
or O
nisogynuist O
, O
for O
of O
the O
world O
of O
men O
she O
can O
be O
pronouuced O
as O
yet O
to O
have O
had O
but O
little O
experience O
) O
, O
and O
we O
may O
be O
pretty O
certain O
that O
the O
persons O
of O
either O
sex O
wlom O
nll O
the O
world O
treats O
ill O
, O
deserve O
entirely O
the O
trcntment O
they O
get O
. O
The O
world O
is O
a O
looking O
- O
gluss O
, O
and O
gives O
buek O
to O
every O
mun O
the O
reflection O
of O
his O
own O
face O
. O
lFrow O
at O
it O
, O
and O
it O
will O
in O
turmn O
look O
sourly O
pon O
you O
: O
luangh O
at O
it O
and O
with O
it O
, O
and O
it O
is O
a O
jolly O
kind O
companion O
| | O
and O
so O
let O
all O
young O
persons O
take O
their O
choice O
. O
) O
it O
could O
not O
bo O
expectel O
that O
every O
one O
should O
be O
of O
the O
humble O
and O
gentlc O
temper O
of O
Miss O
Amelia B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
| | O
should O
take O
every O
opportunity O
to O
vanquish O
lehecca's O
hard O
- O
heartedness O
and O
ill O
- O
humour O
| | O
and O
, O
by O
a O
thousand S-CARDINAL
kind O
worls O
and O
offiees O
, O
overcome O
, O
for O
once O
at O
least O
, O
her O
lostility O
to O
her O
kind O
. O
Miss O
Sharp's S-PERSON
fther O
was O
an O
artist O
, O
and O
in O
that O
qunlity O
had O
given O
lessons O
of O
drawing O
at O
Miss B-ORG
Pinkerton's I-ORG
school E-ORG
. O
He O
was O
a O
clever O
man O
| | O
a O
pleasant O
companion O
| | O
a O
careless O
student O
| | O
with O
a O
great O
propensity O
for O
running O
into O
lebt O
, O
and O
a O
partiality O
for O
the O
tavern O
. O
When O
he O
was O
drunk O
, O
he O
used O
tc O
eat O
his O
wife O
and O
daughter O
| | O
and O
the O
next O
moruing O
, O
with O
a O
hcndache O
, O
he O
used O
to O
ril O
at O
the O
world O
Ior O
its O
neglect O
of O
his O
genius O
, O
and O
abuse O
, O
with O
a O
good O
deal O
of O
cleverness O
, O
and O
eometimes O
wth O
perfect O
reason O
, O
the O
fools O
, O
his O
hrother O
painters O
. O
And O
curious O
it O
is O
, O
that O
as O
she O
advanced O
in O
life O
this O
young O
lady's O
ancestors O
inereased O
in O
rank O
and O
splendour O
. O
Rebecca's S-PERSON
mother O
had O
had O
some O
education O
somewhere O
, O
and O
her O
dughter O
spoke O
French S-LANGUAGE
with O
purity O
and O
a O
Parisian S-NORP
aceent O
. O
It O
was O
in O
those B-DATE
days E-DATE
rather O
a O
rare O
accomplishment O
, O
anl O
led O
to O
her O
engagement O
with O
the O
orthodox O
Miss O
Pinkertou S-PERSON
. O
For O
her O
mother O
being O
dead O
, O
her O
father O
, O
finding O
him O
- O
self O
not O
likely O
to O
recover O
, O
after O
his O
third S-ORDINAL
attack O
of O
delirium O
tremess O
, O
wrote O
a O
manly O
and O
pathietic O
letter O
to O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
recommending O
the O
orphan O
child O
to O
her O
protection O
, O
and O
so O
descended O
to O
the O
grave O
, O
after O
two S-CARDINAL
bailiffs O
had O
quarrelled O
over O
his O
corpse O
. O
Rebecca S-PERSON
was O
seventeen S-DATE
when O
she O
came O
to O
Chiswick S-GPE
, O
and O
was O
bound O
over O
as O
an O
articlel O
pnpil O
| | O
her O
duties O
being O
to O
talk O
French S-LANGUAGE
, O
as O
we O
have O
seen O
, O
and O
her O
privileges O
to O
live O
cost O
free O
, O
and O
, O
wth O
a O
few O
guineas O
a O
year O
, O
to O
gather O
scraps O
of O
kowledge O
from O
the O
professors O
who O
attended O
the O
school O
. O
This O
infatnated O
young O
man O
used O
sometimes O
to O
take O
tes O
with O
MIss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
to O
whom O
he O
had O
been O
presented O
by O
his O
mamma O
, O
and O
aetually O
proposed O
something O
like O
marriage O
in O
an O
intereepted O
note O
, O
which O
the O
one S-CARDINAL
- O
eyed O
applewoman O
was O
charged O
to O
deliver O
. O
But O
she O
had O
the O
dismal O
precocity O
of O
overty O
. O
Many O
a O
dun O
had O
she O
talked O
to O
, O
and O
turned O
away O
from O
her O
father's O
door O
| | O
many O
a O
tradesman O
had O
shc O
conxed O
and O
wheedled O
into O
good O
- O
humour O
, O
and O
into O
the O
granting O
of O
one S-CARDINAL
meal O
more O
. O
She O
sate O
commonly O
with O
her O
father O
, O
who O
was O
very O
proud O
of O
her O
wit O
, O
nnd O
heard O
tle O
talk O
of O
many O
of O
his O
wild O
companions O
- O
often O
but O
ill O
suited O
for O
a O
girl O
to O
hear O
. O
But O
she O
neer O
had O
been O
a O
girl O
, O
she O
said O
| | O
she O
had O
been O
a O
woman O
since O
she O
was O
eight B-DATE
years I-DATE
old E-DATE
. O
O O
why O
did O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
let O
such O
a O
dangerous O
bird O
into O
her O
cage O
The O
fact O
is O
, O
the O
old O
lady O
thought O
Rebecca S-PERSON
to O
be O
the O
meekest O
ereature O
in O
the O
world O
, O
so O
admirably O
, O
on O
the O
occnsions O
when O
her O
father O
brought O
her O
to O
Chiswick S-GPE
, O
used O
Rebeccu S-PERSON
to O
perform O
the O
part O
of O
the O
ingenae O
. O
She O
thought O
her O
n O
modest O
and O
innocent O
little O
ehild O
| | O
and O
only B-DATE
a I-DATE
year E-DATE
before O
the O
arrange O
- O
A O
N0YREL O
WITHOUT O
A O
H0 O
. O
How O
the O
father O
and O
daughter O
laughed O
ass O
they O
trudged O
home O
together O
after O
the O
evening O
party O
, O
( O
it O
was O
on O
the O
oecasion O
of O
the O
speeches O
, O
when O
all O
the O
professors O
were O
invited O
, O
) O
and O
how O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
would O
have O
raged O
had O
she O
seen O
the O
caricature O
of O
herself O
which O
the O
little O
mimic O
, O
Rebecca S-PERSON
, O
managed O
to O
make O
out O
of O
her O
dolll O
She O
used O
to O
go O
through O
dilogues O
with O
it O
it O
formed O
the O
delight O
of O
Newman B-FAC
Street E-FAC
, O
Gerard B-FAC
Street E-FAC
, O
and O
the O
artista O
' O
quarter O
: O
and O
the O
young O
painters O
, O
when O
they O
came O
to O
take O
their O
gin-and O
- O
water O
with O
their O
lay O
, O
dissolute O
, O
clever O
, O
jovial O
senior O
, O
used O
regularly O
--- O
= O
3 B-CARDINAL
1 E-CARDINAL
. O
ll O
rF O
. O
/ O
tM O
L O
N O
, O
. O
3 O
77 O
2I O
W2tR O
RE O
m O
1 O
- O
AL O
l O
4 O
1 O
h O
1et,1 O
LJI O
r O
A O
- O
11 O
I O
I7 O
CL O
.3 O
NL O
( O
. O
g O
g O
-L O
- O
2. O
-===. O
, O
EE O
--- O
to O
ask O
Rebeeea S-PERSON
if O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
was O
at O
home O
: O
she O
was O
well O
known O
to O
them O
, O
poor O
soulI O
as O
Mr. O
Lawrenee S-PERSON
or O
President O
Wast S-PERSON
. O
stronger O
thnn O
her O
gratitude O
, O
and O
se O
saerificed O
Mss O
Jemy S-PERSON
quite O
a O
pitilessly O
as O
her O
sister O
. O
he O
cntastrophe O
cnme O
, O
and O
she O
was O
brought O
to O
tle O
Mall O
as O
to O
her O
home O
. O
She O
hnad O
a O
little O
room O
in O
the O
garret O
, O
where O
the O
maids O
heard O
her O
walking O
and O
sobbing O
at O
night O
| | O
but O
it O
was O
with O
rage O
, O
and O
not O
with O
grief O
. O
She O
had O
not O
been O
much O
of O
a O
dissembler O
, O
until O
now O
her O
loneli- O
ness O
taught O
her O
to O
feign O
. O
She O
hd O
never O
mingled O
in O
the O
society O
of O
women O
: O
her O
father O
, O
reprobate O
as O
he O
was O
, O
was O
n O
man O
of O
talent O
| | O
his O
conversation O
was O
a B-CARDINAL
thousand E-CARDINAL
times O
more O
agreeable O
to O
her O
than O
the O
talk O
of O
such O
of O
her O
own O
sex O
as O
she O
now O
encountered O
. O
The O
pompous O
vauity O
of O
the O
old O
school O
- O
mistress O
, O
the O
foolish O
good O
- O
humour O
of O
her O
sister O
, O
the O
silly O
chat O
and O
scandal O
of O
the O
elder O
girls O
, O
and O
the O
frigil O
correcetness O
of O
the O
goverucsses O
equally O
annoyed O
her O
| | O
and O
she O
kad O
no O
soft O
maternal O
henrt O
, O
this O
unlucky O
girl O
, O
other O
- O
wise O
the O
prattle O
and O
talk O
of O
the O
younger O
children O
, O
with O
whose O
care O
she O
was O
chiefly O
intrusted O
, O
might O
have O
soothed O
nnd O
interestel O
her O
| | O
but O
she O
lived O
among O
them O
two S-CARDINAL
yeurs O
, O
and O
not O
one O
was O
sorry O
that O
she O
went O
away O
. O
he O
gentle O
tender O
- O
hearted O
Amelin B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
was O
the O
only O
person O
to O
whom O
she O
could O
uttach O
hersclf O
in O
the O
least O
| | O
and O
who O
could O
hclp O
attaching O
herself O
to O
Amelia S-PERSON
? O
The O
happiness O
- O
the O
superior O
advantages O
of O
the O
young O
women O
round O
about O
her O
, O
guave O
lebeccu O
inexpressible O
pangs O
of O
envy O
. O
What O
airs O
that O
girl O
gives O
herself O
, O
because O
she O
is O
nn O
Enrl's O
grandlaughter O
, O
'' O
she O
sunid O
of O
one O
. O
How O
they O
cringe O
and O
bow O
to O
thnt O
Creole S-LANGUAGE
, O
because O
of O
her O
hundred B-CARDINAL
thousand E-CARDINAL
poundsl O
I O
am O
a B-CARDINAL
thousand E-CARDINAL
times O
cleverer O
and O
more O
charming O
than O
that O
creature O
, O
for O
all O
her O
wealth O
. O
I O
am O
as O
well O
bred O
as O
the O
Euarl's S-PERSON
granddaughter O
, O
for O
all O
her O
fine O
pedigree O
| | O
and O
yet O
every O
one O
passes O
me O
by O
here O
. O
'' O
She O
determined O
nt O
any O
rate O
to O
get O
free O
from O
the O
prison O
in O
which O
she O
found O
herself O
, O
and O
now O
began O
to O
act O
for O
hcrself O
, O
and O
for O
the O
first S-ORDINAL
timo O
to O
make O
connected O
plans O
for O
the O
future O
. O
She O
took O
advantage O
, O
therefore O
, O
of O
the O
means O
of O
study O
the O
place O
offored O
her O
| | O
and O
as O
she O
was O
alrcady O
a O
msician O
anl O
a O
good O
linguist O
, O
she O
spceedily O
went O
through O
the O
little O
coursc O
of O
study O
which O
was O
considered O
necessary O
for O
ladies O
in O
those B-DATE
days E-DATE
. O
IIer O
music O
she O
practisel O
iucessantly O
, O
and O
one O
ay O
, O
when O
the O
girls O
wcre O
out O
, O
nnd O
she O
had O
remained O
at O
home O
, O
she O
wns O
ovcr O
- O
heard O
to O
play O
a O
piece O
so O
well O
, O
that O
Minerva S-PERSON
thought O
wisely O
, O
she O
coull O
spare O
herself O
the O
expense O
of O
a O
master O
for O
the O
juniors O
, O
and O
intimated O
to O
Miss O
Slarp S-PERSON
that O
she O
was O
to O
instruet O
them O
in O
music O
for O
the O
future O
. O
` O
I O
am O
here O
to O
spcak O
French S-LANGUAGE
with O
the O
children O
, O
'' O
Rebeccn S-PERSON
said O
abruptly O
, O
`` O
not O
to O
teach O
them O
music O
, O
and O
save O
money O
for O
you O
. O
Give O
mo O
money O
, O
and O
I O
will O
teach O
them O
. O
'' O
Minerva S-PERSON
was O
obliged O
to O
yield O
, O
and O
, O
of O
course O
, O
disliked O
her O
from O
that O
dny O
. O
For O
fie O
- O
and O
- O
thirty B-DATE
years E-DATE
, O
'' O
she O
said O
, O
and O
with O
great O
justice O
, O
I O
never O
A O
NOVEL O
WIHOUT O
IHEB0 O
. O
13 S-CARDINAL
ave O
seen O
the O
individual O
who O
has O
dared O
in O
my O
own O
house O
to O
question O
my O
nuthority O
. O
I O
have O
nourished O
a O
viper O
in O
my O
bosom O
. O
'' O
A O
viper O
- O
a O
fiddlestick O
, O
'' O
said O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
to O
the O
old O
luly O
, O
almost O
fint O
- O
iug O
with O
astonishment O
. O
`` O
You O
took O
me O
because O
I O
was O
useful O
. O
There O
is O
no O
question O
of O
gratitude O
between O
us O
. O
I O
hnte O
this O
place O
, O
and O
want O
to O
lenve O
it O
, O
I O
will O
do O
nothing O
here O
, O
but O
what O
I O
am O
obliged O
to O
do O
. O
'' O
It O
wus O
in O
vain O
that O
the O
old O
laly O
asked O
her O
if O
she O
ws O
aware O
she O
was O
speaking O
to O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
lebeccas O
lasughed O
in O
her O
face O
, O
with O
n O
lorrid O
uarcastic O
demoniacal O
laughter O
, O
that O
almost O
sent O
the O
schoolmistress O
into O
fits O
. O
Give O
me O
a O
sum O
of O
money O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
girl O
, O
`` O
nnd O
get O
rid O
of O
me O
- O
or O
, O
if O
you O
like O
better O
, O
get O
me O
a O
gool O
place O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
nobleman's O
family O
- O
you O
can O
do O
so O
if O
you O
please O
. O
'' O
And O
in O
their O
further O
disputes O
she O
alwuays O
returned O
to O
this O
point O
, O
` O
Gct O
me O
a O
situation O
- O
we O
hute O
each O
other O
, O
and O
I O
um O
ready O
to O
go O
. O
'' O
Worthy O
Miss O
Pinkerton S-PERSON
, O
although O
she O
had O
a O
Ronan S-PERSON
nose O
and O
a O
turbnn O
, O
and O
was O
ns O
tall O
as O
a O
grenadier O
, O
and O
hd O
been O
up O
to O
this O
time O
an O
irresistible O
princess O
, O
had O
no O
will O
or O
strength O
likc O
that O
of O
er O
little O
apprentice O
, O
and O
in O
vauin O
did O
battle O
agninst O
her O
, O
and O
tried O
to O
overawe O
her O
. O
Attempting O
once O
to O
seold O
her O
in O
public O
, O
Rebecca S-PERSON
hit O
upon O
the O
before O
- O
mentioued O
plan O
of O
answering O
hcr O
in O
French S-LANGUAGE
, O
which O
quite O
routed O
the O
old O
woman O
. O
'' O
I O
cannot O
, O
certninly O
, O
'' O
she O
said O
, O
'' O
find O
fault O
witl O
Miss O
Shrp's S-PERSON
con- O
duct O
, O
except O
to O
myself O
| | O
and O
must O
allow O
thnt O
her O
talents O
and O
accom- O
plishments O
are O
of O
a O
high O
orler O
. O
As O
fnr O
ans O
the O
head O
goes O
, O
nt O
least O
, O
she O
does O
credit O
to O
the O
educutional O
system O
pursuoel O
at O
y O
cstablishmcnt O
. O
'' O
And O
so O
the O
schoolmistress O
rcconciled O
the O
recommendation O
to O
her O
con- O
science O
, O
and O
the O
indentures O
were O
cnneelled O
, O
and O
the O
apprenticc O
wns O
free O
. O
The O
battle O
here O
deseribed O
in O
a O
few O
lines O
, O
of O
coursc O
, O
lasted O
for O
some B-DATE
months E-DATE
. O
And O
as O
MIiss B-PERSON
Selley E-PERSON
, O
bcing O
now O
seventcen B-DATE
years I-DATE
of I-DATE
age E-DATE
, O
was O
ubout O
to O
lcavc O
school O
, O
and O
hnd O
a O
friendship O
for O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
( O
`` O
' O
tis O
the O
only O
point O
in O
Amelia's O
behaviour O
, O
'' O
snid O
Minerva S-PERSON
, O
'` O
which O
hns O
not O
been O
satisfuctory O
to O
her O
mistress O
, O
'' O
) O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
was O
invited O
by O
her O
friend O
to O
pass O
a O
week O
with O
her O
at O
home O
, O
before O
she O
entered O
upon O
her O
duties O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
private O
Iamily O
. O
Thus O
the O
world O
begnn O
for O
these O
two S-CARDINAL
young O
ladies O
. O
But O
who O
ean O
tell O
you O
thc O
rcnl O
truth O
of O
the O
matter O
At O
all O
events O
, O
if O
cbecca O
was O
not O
beginning O
the O
world O
, O
she O
was O
bcginning O
it O
over O
again O
. O
By O
the O
time O
the O
young O
ladies O
renched O
Kensington B-FAC
turnpike E-FAC
, O
Amelin S-PERSON
hnd O
not O
forgotten O
her O
compunions O
, O
but O
had O
driel O
her O
tears O
, O
and O
hud O
blushel O
very O
much O
nd O
been O
dcligghted O
at O
a O
young O
officer O
of O
the B-ORG
Life I-ORG
Guards E-ORG
, O
who O
vANITFY B-ORG
AIR E-ORG
. O
And O
when O
at O
length O
home O
was O
reached O
, O
Miss O
Amelia B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
skipped O
out O
on O
Sambo's S-PERSON
arm O
, O
as O
happy O
and O
as O
handsome O
a O
girl O
as O
any O
in O
the O
whole O
big O
city O
of O
London S-GPE
. O
Both O
he O
and O
coachman O
agreed O
on O
this O
point O
, O
and O
so O
did O
her O
futher O
and O
mother O
, O
and O
so O
did O
every O
one S-CARDINAL
of O
the O
servants O
in O
the O
house O
, O
as O
they O
stood O
bobbing O
, O
and O
curteeying O
, O
and O
smiling O
, O
in O
the O
hall O
, O
to O
welcomc O
their O
young O
mistress O
. O
You O
may O
be O
sure O
tht O
she O
showed O
Rebecca S-PERSON
oer O
every O
room O
of O
the O
house O
, O
and O
everything O
in O
every O
one O
of O
her O
drawers O
| | O
and O
her O
books O
, O
and O
her O
piano O
, O
and O
her O
uresses O
, O
and O
all O
her O
necklaces O
, O
brooches O
, O
laces O
, O
and O
gimcracks O
. O
She O
insisted O
upon O
Rebecca S-PERSON
accepting O
the O
white O
cornelian O
and O
the O
turquoise O
rings O
, O
and O
a O
sweet O
sprigged O
muslin O
, O
which O
was O
too O
small O
for O
her O
now O
, O
though O
it O
would O
fit O
her O
friend O
to O
a O
nieety O
| | O
and O
she O
determined O
in O
her O
heart O
to O
ask O
her O
mother's O
permission O
to O
present O
her O
wlite O
Cashmerc O
shawl O
to O
her O
friend O
. O
Could O
she O
not O
spare O
it O
? O
When O
Rebecca S-PERSON
saw O
the O
two S-CARDINAL
agnificent O
Cashmere S-ORG
shawls O
which O
Joseph B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
had O
brought O
, O
home O
to O
his O
sister O
, O
she O
said O
, O
with O
perfect O
truth O
, O
`` O
thut O
it O
must O
be O
delightful O
to O
have O
a O
brother O
, O
'' O
and O
easily O
got O
the O
pity O
of O
thc O
tender O
- O
henrted O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
for O
being O
alone O
in O
the O
world O
, O
an O
orphan O
without O
frienls O
or O
kindred O
. O
: O
Not O
alone O
, O
'' O
said O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
``' O
you O
know O
, O
Rebecca S-PERSON
, O
I O
shll O
always O
be O
your O
friend O
, O
and O
love O
you O
as O
a O
sister O
- O
indeed O
I O
will O
. O
'' O
`' O
Ah O
, O
but O
to O
have O
parents O
, O
as O
you O
lave O
- O
kind O
, O
rich O
, O
affectionate O
parents O
, O
who O
give O
you O
everything O
you O
ask O
for O
| | O
and O
their O
love O
, O
which O
is O
more O
pre- O
cious O
than O
all1 O
My O
poor O
papa O
could O
give O
me O
nothing O
, O
and O
I O
had O
but O
twa O
frocks O
in O
all O
the O
worldl O
Aud O
then O
, O
to O
have O
a O
brother O
, O
a O
dear O
brotler O
l O
Oh O
how O
you O
must O
love O
himl'' O
Amelia S-PERSON
laughed O
. O
What O
l O
dos't O
you O
love O
him O
' O
you O
, O
vlo O
say O
you O
love O
everybody O
'' O
Yes O
, O
of O
course O
, O
I O
do O
-only O
- O
'' O
Only O
what O
P'' O
" O
" O
Only O
Joseph S-PERSON
doesn't O
seem O
to O
cnre O
much O
whether O
I O
loe O
him O
or O
not O
. O
He O
gave O
me O
two S-CARDINAL
fingers O
to O
shake O
when O
he O
arrived O
after O
ten O
years' O
abseneel O
IIe O
is O
very O
kind O
and O
good O
, O
but O
he O
scarecly O
eser O
speaks O
to O
me O
| | O
I O
think O
h O
loves O
his O
pipe O
a O
great O
deal O
better O
thnn O
his''s O
e O
but O
here O
Amelia S-PERSON
checked O
herself O
, O
for O
why O
should O
she O
spesk O
ill O
of O
her O
brothor O
He O
was O
very O
kind O
to O
me O
as O
a O
child O
, O
'' O
she O
addod O
| | O
'` O
I O
was O
but O
five S-CARDINAL
ycars O
old O
wlucn O
e O
went O
away O
, O
'' O
` O
Isn't O
he O
very O
rich O
? O
'' O
said O
Rebecca S-PERSON
. O
` O
Tley O
say O
all O
Indian S-NORP
nabobs O
nre O
enormously O
rich O
, O
'' O
I O
believe O
he O
has O
a O
very O
large O
income O
. O
'' O
`` O
And O
is O
your O
sister O
- O
in O
- O
law O
a O
nice O
pretty O
womon2 O
' O
' O
`` O
Lal B-PERSON
Joseph E-PERSON
is O
not O
married O
, O
'' O
said O
Mmelia S-PERSON
, O
laughing O
agnin O
. O
Perhaps O
shce O
had O
mentioned O
the O
fact O
alrendy O
to O
kebceca O
, O
but O
thiat O
young O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
IIERO O
. O
lady O
did O
not O
appear O
to O
have O
remembered O
it O
| | O
indeed O
, O
vowed O
and O
protested O
that O
she O
expected O
to O
see O
a O
number O
of O
Anelia's S-NORP
nephews O
and O
niceces O
. O
'' O
And O
she O
determined O
within O
herself O
to O
make O
this O
laudnble O
attempt O
. O
She O
redonbled O
her O
caresses O
to O
Amelia S-PERSON
| | O
she O
kissed O
the O
white O
cornelian O
necklace O
as O
she O
put O
it O
on O
| | O
and O
owed O
she O
would O
never O
, O
never O
port O
with O
it O
. O
When O
the O
dinner- O
bell O
rang O
she O
went O
down O
stairs O
with O
her O
arm O
round O
her O
friend's O
waist O
, O
as O
is O
the O
habit O
of O
young O
ladies O
. O
She O
was O
so O
agitated O
at O
the O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
, O
that O
she O
aould O
hardly O
find O
courage O
to O
enter O
. O
` O
Feel O
my O
heart O
, O
how O
it O
beats O
, O
dear1 O
' O
' O
nid O
she O
to O
her O
friend O
. O
No O
, O
it O
doesn't O
, O
'' O
said O
Amelia S-PERSON
. O
`' O
Come O
iu O
, O
don't O
be O
frightened O
. O
Papa S-PERSON
wont O
do O
you O
any O
harm O
. O
, O
'' O
) O
1 S-CARDINAL
| | O
1`I O
t O
.: O
n O
| | O
ai- O
nEBECCA O
IS O
IN O
PnESENCE O
OF O
TIIE O
ENEMY O
. O
Al B-PERSON
H E-PERSON
: O
L O
--- O
g O
cIAPTER O
III O
. O
vY O
stout O
, O
puffy O
man O
, O
in O
buckskins O
and O
hessian O
boots O
, O
with O
several O
immense O
neckcloths O
, O
that O
rose O
almost O
to O
his O
nose O
, O
with O
a O
red O
striped O
waistcont O
and O
an O
apple O
green O
coat O
with O
steel O
buttons O
almost O
as O
large O
as O
crown O
pieces O
, O
( O
it O
was O
the O
morning O
costume O
of O
a O
dandy O
or O
blood O
of O
those O
days O
) O
was O
reading O
the O
paper O
by O
the O
s'Ll. O
i O
i O
ciei O
. O
i O
iea O
off O
his O
arm O
- O
chair O
, O
and O
blusled O
excessively O
, O
and O
hid O
his O
entire O
face O
alnost O
in O
his O
neekcloths O
at O
tlis O
apparition O
. O
It's O
only O
your O
sister O
, O
Joseph S-PERSON
, O
'' O
sait O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
laughing O
and O
shaking O
thc O
two S-CARDINAL
fingers O
which O
he O
held O
out O
. O
: O
I O
' O
ve O
come O
hoe O
fr O
good O
yon O
know O
| | O
and O
this O
is O
my O
friend O
, O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
whom O
you O
have O
leard O
me O
mention O
, O
. O
'' O
No O
, O
neer O
, O
upon O
my O
worl O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
head O
under O
the O
neckcloth O
, O
shak O
- O
ing O
very O
mueh O
, O
-`` O
that O
is O
, O
yes O
, O
- O
what O
nbominably O
cold O
weuther O
, O
Miss O
| | O
''- O
nnd O
herewith O
he O
fell O
to O
poking O
the O
fire O
with O
all O
his O
might O
, O
although O
it O
was O
in O
the B-DATE
middle I-DATE
of I-DATE
June E-DATE
. O
He's O
very O
handsome O
, O
'' O
whispered O
Rebecca S-PERSON
to O
Amelia S-PERSON
, O
rather O
loudl O
. O
Do O
you O
think O
so O
: O
'' O
said O
the O
latter O
, O
I O
' O
lI O
tell O
lim O
. O
'' O
Drling S-PERSON
l O
not O
for O
worlds O
, O
'' O
sail O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
starting O
back O
us O
timid O
as O
a O
fuwn O
. O
She O
hnd O
previously O
made O
a O
respecetful O
virgin O
- O
like O
curtsey O
tao O
the O
gentlemnn O
, O
and O
her O
nodest O
eyes O
gazed O
so O
perseveringly O
on O
the O
carpet O
thrat O
it O
was O
a O
wonder O
how O
she O
should O
have O
found O
an O
opportunity O
to O
see O
him O
. O
Thank O
you O
for O
the O
beautiful O
shawls O
, O
brotler O
, O
'' O
said O
Amelia S-PERSON
to O
the O
fire- O
poker O
. O
`` O
Are O
thcy O
not O
beautiful O
, O
Rebereu S-PERSON
? O
'' O
O O
heavenly'' O
said O
Miss O
Shnrp S-PERSON
, O
and O
her O
eycs O
went O
from O
thc O
carpet O
straight O
to O
the O
chandelier O
. O
oseph O
still O
continued O
a O
huge O
elattering O
at O
the O
poker O
and O
tongs O
, O
puffing O
and O
blowing O
the O
while O
, O
and O
turuing O
as O
red O
as O
his O
yellow O
face O
would O
allow O
him O
. O
I O
can't O
mkc O
you O
such O
handsome O
prcsents O
, O
Joseph S-PERSON
, O
'' O
continucd O
his O
sister O
, O
`` O
but O
while O
I O
wus O
at O
school O
, O
I O
have O
cbroidered O
for O
you O
a O
very O
beautiful O
pair O
of O
braces O
, O
'' O
Good O
Gnd O
l O
Amelia O
, O
'' O
eriel O
the O
brother O
, O
in O
serious O
alarm O
, O
`` O
what O
do O
yo O
mean O
? O
'' O
nnd O
plunging O
with O
all O
his O
might O
at O
the O
bcll O
- O
rope O
, O
that O
article O
of O
furniture O
came O
away O
in O
his O
hand O
, O
and O
inereased O
the O
honest O
fcllow's O
con- O
fusion O
. O
For O
heaveu's O
sakec O
sce O
if O
my O
buggy O
's O
at O
the O
door O
. O
I O
ean't O
wait O
. O
I O
must O
go O
. O
D- O
that O
groom O
of O
mine O
. O
I O
must O
go O
. O
'' O
At O
this O
minute O
te O
fathcer O
of O
the O
family O
walked O
in O
, O
rattling O
lis O
seals O
like O
a O
true O
British S-NORP
merchant O
. O
What's O
the O
mattcr O
, O
Emnfh S-PERSON
'' O
says O
he O
. O
` O
Joseph S-PERSON
wauts O
me O
to O
see O
if O
his O
- O
his O
ggy O
is O
at O
thc O
door O
. O
What O
is O
a O
bgg O
, O
papa2 O
' O
A O
NOVEEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
IIERO O
. O
17 S-CARDINAL
It O
is O
ua O
one O
- O
horse O
palanquin O
, O
'' O
snid O
the O
old O
gentleman O
, O
who O
wus O
a O
ag O
in O
his O
wy O
. O
Joscph S-PERSON
nt O
this O
burst O
out O
into O
a O
wild O
fit O
of O
laughter O
| | O
in O
which O
, O
encounter O
- O
ing O
thc O
cye O
of O
MIiss O
Slnrp O
, O
he O
stoppcd O
all O
of O
n O
sudden O
, O
as O
if O
he O
hud O
been O
shot O
. O
1his O
young O
laly O
is O
your O
friendP O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
I O
am O
very O
happy O
to O
see O
yvou O
. O
Have O
you O
nul O
lmmy O
bcen O
quarrelling O
alreudy O
with O
Jloseph S-PERSON
, O
that O
le O
wants O
to O
be O
off O
'' O
` O
I O
promisel O
Bonany O
, O
of O
our O
service O
, O
sir O
, O
''snil O
Joscph O
, O
`` O
to O
dine O
with O
hin O
. O
'' O
O O
fe1 O
lidn't O
yon O
tell O
your O
mother O
you O
woull O
dine O
here O
'' O
But O
in O
this O
dress O
it O
's O
impossible O
. O
'' O
Look O
at O
him O
, O
isn't O
he O
lnlsome O
enough O
to O
dine O
anywhere O
, O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
? O
'' O
On O
which O
, O
of O
coursc O
, O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
looked O
at O
her O
friend O
, O
and O
they O
both O
scet O
off O
in O
a O
fit O
of O
laughter O
, O
highly O
agreeable O
to O
the O
oll O
gentleman O
. O
Did O
you O
ever O
see O
a O
pair O
of O
buckskins O
like O
those O
at O
Miss O
Pinkerton's S-PERSON
'' O
continued O
he O
, O
following O
up O
his O
audvantnge O
. O
Gracious O
heavensI O
Father O
, O
'' O
ceried O
Joseph S-PERSON
. O
e O
There O
now O
, O
I O
have O
hurt O
his O
feelings O
. O
Mra. O
Selley S-PERSON
, O
y O
dear O
, O
I O
have O
hurt O
your O
son's O
feelings O
. O
I O
hmave O
alludel O
to O
his O
buckskins O
. O
Ask O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
if O
I O
haven't O
Come O
, O
Joseph S-PERSON
, O
be O
friends O
with O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
and O
let O
us O
all O
go O
to O
dinner O
. O
'' O
There's O
a O
pillau O
, O
Joseph S-PERSON
, O
just O
as O
you O
like O
it O
, O
andl O
Papa S-PERSON
has O
brought O
home O
the O
best O
turlot O
in O
Billingsgate S-LOC
. O
'' O
Come O
, O
come O
, O
sir O
, O
walk O
down O
stairs O
with O
Miss O
Sharp S-PERSON
, O
and O
I O
will O
follaw O
with O
these O
two S-CARDINAL
young O
women O
, O
'' O
sil O
the O
ftler O
, O
and O
le O
took O
an O
arm O
of O
wife O
nud O
dauglter O
and O
walked O
merrily O
off O
. O
If O
MIiss B-PERSON
Rebecca I-PERSON
Sharp E-PERSON
hl O
deterined O
in O
her O
heart O
upon O
making O
thc O
conquecst O
of O
this O
big O
bcan O
, O
I O
lon't O
thiuk O
, O
ladics O
, O
we O
hae O
any O
right O
to O
blame O
her O
| | O
for O
though O
the O
task O
of O
husbnd O
- O
hunting O
is O
generally O
, O
and O
with O
bccom- O
ing O
molesty O
, O
cntrusted O
by O
young O
persons O
to O
their O
mammns O
, O
recollect O
that O
MIiss O
Shnrp S-PERSON
had O
no O
kind O
pnrent O
to O
arrange O
these O
delicate O
atters O
for O
her O
, O
and O
thnt O
if O
she O
dil O
not O
get O
a O
husband O
for O
horself O
, O
there O
wus O
no O
one O
clse O
in O
the O
wide O
world O
who O
would O
take O
the O
trouble O
off O
lcr O
hands O
. O
What O
cnuses O
yonng O
people O
to O
`` O
eome O
out O
, O
'' O
but O
the O
noble O
ambition O
of O
matrimony O
' O
What O
sends O
them O
trooping O
to O
watering O
- O
pluces O
? O
Whuat S-PERSON
keeps O
tlemn O
dancing O
till O
fve O
o'clock O
in O
the O
morning O
through O
a O
whole O
mortal O
season O
Whnt O
causes O
them O
to O
labour O
at O
piano- O
forte O
sonatas O
, O
nand O
to O
learn O
four S-CARDINAL
songs O
from O
a O
fashionuable O
master O
at O
a O
guine O
a O
lesson O
, O
and O
to O
play O
thc O
hnrp O
if O
they O
hve O
handsome O
narms O
and O
neat O
elbows O
, O
and O
to O
wear O
Lincoln B-ORG
Green E-ORG
toxepho- O
lite O
hats O
nnd O
feathers O
, O
but O
that O
thcy O
may O
bring O
down O
some O
`` O
desirable O
'' O
yonng O
man O
with O
thosc O
killing O
bows O
anl O
arrows O
of O
theirsP O
Wnt O
cnuscs O
respectable O
pnrcnts O
to O
take O
up O
their O
carpets O
, O
set O
their O
houses O
topsy O
- O
turvy O
, O
nnd O
spenl O
n O
fifth O
of O
their O
year's O
income O
in O
ball O
suppers O
nnd O
icel O
champagne O
? O
Is O
it O
shcer O
love O
of O
their O
specics O
, O
and O
an O
unadulterated O
wish O
to O
see O
young O
people O
lappy O
and O
danciug O
Pshal O
they O
want O
to O
marry O
their O
dughters O
| | O
and O
, O
as O
lioncst O
Mrs. O
Sedlcy S-PERSON
has O
, O
in O
the O
depths O
of O
her O
kind O
heart O
, O
alrealy O
arranged O
a O
score O
of O
little O
schemes O
for O
the O
settlement O
of O
her O
hmelia O
, O
so O
ualso O
had O
ou O
belovel O
bnt O
unprotectedt O
Rebecca S-PERSON
, O
determined O
ta O
18 S-CARDINAL
YANITY O
AIB S-ORG
. O
do O
her O
very O
best O
to O
secure O
the O
hsbaud O
, O
who O
was O
even O
more O
necessary O
for O
her O
than O
for O
her O
friend O
. O
She O
had O
a O
vivid O
imaginuation O
| | O
she O
had O
, O
besides O
, O
read O
the O
`` O
Arabian B-WORK_OF_ART
Nights I-WORK_OF_ART
' E-WORK_OF_ART
' O
and O
`` O
Guthrie's B-WORK_OF_ART
Geograsphy E-WORK_OF_ART
, O
'' O
and O
it O
is O
a O
fact O
, O
that O
while O
she O
was O
dressing O
for O
dinner O
, O
and O
after O
she O
had O
asked O
Amelia S-PERSON
whether O
her O
brother O
was O
very O
rich O
, O
she O
had O
built O
for O
herself O
a O
most O
magni- O
ficent O
castle O
in O
the O
air O
, O
of O
which O
she O
was O
mistress O
, O
with O
a O
husband O
some O
- O
where O
in O
the O
baekgroud O
( O
she O
had O
not O
seen O
him O
as O
yet O
, O
and O
his O
figure O
would O
not O
therefore O
be O
very O
listinct O
) O
| | O
she O
had O
arruyed O
herself O
in O
an O
infinity O
of O
shawls O
, O
turbans O
, O
and O
diamond O
necklaces O
, O
and O
had O
mounted O
upon O
an O
elephant O
to O
the O
sound O
of O
the O
march O
in O
Bluebeard S-PERSON
, O
in O
order O
to O
pay O
a O
visit O
of O
ceremony O
to O
the B-FAC
Grand I-FAC
Mogl E-FAC
. O
Charming O
Alnaschar S-PERSON
visions O
l O
it O
is O
the O
happy O
privilege O
of O
youth O
to O
construct O
you O
, O
and O
many O
a O
fanciful O
young O
creature O
besids O
Rcbecca B-PERSON
Sharp E-PERSON
, O
has O
indulged O
in O
tlese O
delightful O
dny O
- O
dreams O
cre O
now O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
Sedley E-PERSON
was O
twelve B-DATE
years E-DATE
older O
than O
his O
sister O
Mmelia S-PERSON
. O
He O
wns O
in O
the B-EVENT
Eost I-EVENT
India I-EVENT
Company's I-EVENT
Civil I-EVENT
ervice E-EVENT
, O
and O
his O
name O
appeared O
, O
at O
the O
eriod O
of O
which O
we O
write O
, O
in O
the O
Bengal S-NORP
division O
of O
the B-ORG
East I-ORG
India I-ORG
Register E-ORG
, O
as O
collector O
of O
Boggley B-PERSON
Wollnh E-PERSON
, O
an O
honourable O
and O
lucrative O
post O
, O
as O
every O
- O
body O
knows O
: O
in O
order O
to O
know O
to O
what O
higher O
posts O
Joseph S-PERSON
rose O
in O
the O
service O
, O
the O
render O
is O
referred O
to O
the O
same O
periodical O
. O
Boggley B-PERSON
Wollah E-PERSON
is O
situated O
in O
a O
fine O
, O
lonely O
, O
marshy O
, O
jungly O
district O
, O
iamous O
for O
suipe O
- O
shooting O
, O
and O
where O
not O
unfrequently O
you O
may O
flush O
a O
tiger O
. O
Ramgunge S-PERSON
, O
where O
there O
is O
a O
magistrate O
, O
is O
only B-QUANTITY
forty I-QUANTITY
miles E-QUANTITY
off O
, O
nd O
there O
is O
a O
cavalry O
station O
about B-QUANTITY
thirty I-QUANTITY
miles E-QUANTITY
farther O
| | O
so O
Joseph S-PERSON
wrote O
home O
to O
his O
parents O
, O
when O
he O
took O
possession O
of O
his O
colleetorship O
. O
lIe O
had O
lived O
for O
about B-DATE
eight I-DATE
yenrs E-DATE
of O
his O
life O
, O
quite O
alone O
, O
at O
this O
charm O
- O
iug O
place O
, O
scarcely O
seeing O
a O
Christian S-NORP
fuce O
, O
except O
twice O
a O
year O
, O
when O
the O
detachment O
arrived O
to O
carry O
off O
the O
evenues O
wlhich O
he O
had O
oollected O
, O
to O
Calcutta S-GPE
. O
Luckily O
, O
at O
this O
time O
he O
caught O
a O
liver O
complaint O
, O
for O
the O
cure O
of O
whieh O
hc O
returned O
to O
Europe S-LOC
, O
and O
which O
was O
the O
source O
of O
great O
comfort O
and O
amusement O
to O
hi O
in O
his O
native O
country O
. O
He O
did O
not O
lie O
with O
his O
family O
while O
in O
London S-GPE
, O
but O
hnd O
lodgings O
of O
his O
own O
, O
like O
a O
gay O
young O
