| 

 

| O
Presented O
to O
the O
|
| O
LIBRARY B-PERSON
Of O
the B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
UNIVERSITY I-ORG
OF I-ORG
TORONTO O
|
| O
by O
|

| O
PROFESSOR O
|

| O
B. B-PERSON
M. I-PERSON
CORRIGAN I-PERSON
|

| O
. O
|
| O
Se B-PERSON
Hae I-PERSON
. O
|

| O
_ O
|

| O
RAS O
aah O
|
| O
POO O
om O
|

 


    

| O
at O
|
| O
4 B-CARDINAL
|

  

| O
é O
ed O
|
| O
. O
“ O
MoDERN B-GPE
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

 

 

 

| O
MODERN B-PERSON
FLIRTATIONS I-PERSON
  O
|

| O
A O
MONTH O
AT O
HARROWGATE O
. O
|

| O
IN O
THREE B-CARDINAL
VOLUMES O
. O
|

| O
BY O
|

| O
CATHERINE O
SINCLAIR O
, O
|

| O
AUTHOR O
OF O
( O
MODERN O
ACCOMPLISHMENTS O
, O
” O
EIGHTH O
THOUSAND O
  O
“ O
MODERN B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
SOCIETY I-ORG
, O
” O
SIXTH O
THOUSAND O
  O
“ O
HILL B-ORG
AND O
VALLEY O
, O
” O
THIRD O
THOUSAND O
  O
|
| O
‘ O
SCOTLAND B-ORG
AND O
THE O
SCOTCH O
, O
” O
THIRD O
THOUSAND O
  O
“ O
‘ O
SHETLAND O
AND O
|
| O
‘ O
THE O
SHETLANDERS O
, O
” O
SECOND B-DATE
THOUSAND I-DATE
  O
‘ O
HOLIDAY O
HOUSE O
, O
” O
THIRD O
|
| O
THOUSAND O
  O
‘ O
CHARLIE B-PERSON
SEYMOUR I-PERSON
, O
” O
THIRD O
THOUSAND O
, O
ETC B-ORG
. O
|

 

| O
“ O
I O
clasped O
my O
hand O
close O
to O
my O
breast O
, O
|
| O
‘ O
While O
my O
heart O
wasas O
light O
as O
8 B-CARDINAL
feather O
, O
|
| O
‘ O
Yet O
nothing O
I O
said O
, O
I O
protest O
, O
|
| O
But O
, O
— O
— O
‘ O
Madam O
! O
‘ O
tis O
very O
fine O
weather O
! O
" O
” O
|
| O
Ritson O
’ O
Songe O
. O
|

| O
VOL O
. O
I. B-PERSON
|

| I-PERSON
SECOND B-DATE
THOUSAND I-DATE
. O
|

| O
EDINBURGH B-ORG
: O
|
| O
WILLIAM O
WHYTE O
AND O
CoO B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
POOKSELLERS O
TO O
THE O
QUEEN O
DOWAGER O
  O
|

| O
LONGMAN B-WORK_OF_ART
, I-WORK_OF_ART
BROWN I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
AND O
C0 O
. O
} O
SIMPKIN O
, O
MARSHALL B-ORG
, O
AND O
CO O
. O
  O
HAMILTON B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
ADAMS B-ORG
, I-ORG
AND I-ORG
CO I-ORG
. I-ORG
  O
WHITTAKER B-ORG
AND I-ORG
CO I-ORG
. I-ORG
  O
DUNCAN B-PERSON
AND O
MALCOM O
, O
LONDON B-GPE
: O
|
| O
W. B-PERSON
CURRY I-PERSON
, O
JUN B-DATE
, O
, O
AND O
CO O
. O
, O
DUBLIN B-ORG
? O
AND O
WILLIAM O
COLLINS O
, O
GLASGOW O
. O
|

| O
PR O
|
| O
ABZ O
|
| O
S O
® O
M O
& O
|

| O
v. O
|||| O
|

| O
BALFOUR O
AND O
JACK O
, O
|

| O
PRinTERs B-PERSON
, O
|

| O
NIDDRY O
ST O
. O
, O
EDINBURGH B-ORG
. O
|

 

| O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
Unper B-PERSON
Prowprer I-PERSON
. O
— O
Sir O
, O
the O
scene O
is O
set O
, O
and O
|
| O
everything O
ready O
to O
begin O
, O
if O
you O
please O
. O
” O
|
| O
Crime O
. O
|

| O
Ir B-PERSON
was O
the O
rule O
of O
a O
celebrated O
eques- O
|
| O
trian O
, O
which O
might O
be O
adapted O
to O
authors O
|
| O
as O
well O
as O
to O
horsemen O
, O
that O
every O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
should O
ride O
as O
if O
he O
expected O
to O
be O
|
| O
thrown O
, O
and O
drive O
as O
if O
he O
expected O
to O
be O
|
| O
upset O
. O
Impunity O
in O
publishing O
, O
far O
from O
|
| O
rendering O
an O
author O
presumptuous O
, O
should O
|
| O
tend O
rather O
to O
increase O
his O
timidity O
, O
the O
|
| O
danger O
being O
greater O
always O
of O
venturing O
|
| O
too O
much O
, O
than O
of O
hazarding O
too O
little O
  O
|
| O
and O
the O
more O
cause O
any O
writer O
has O
to O
|
| O
feel O
grateful O
for O
the O
lenient O
judgment O
of O
|
| O
an O
enlightened O
public O
, O
the O
more O
circum- O
|
| O
spect O
should O
he O
become O
, O
not O
to O
trespass O
|

| O
iv O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
by O
an O
obtrusive O
reappearance O
on O
that O
|
| O
notice O
which O
has O
already O
perhaps O
been O
, O
|
| O
as O
in O
respect O
to O
the O
author O
herself O
, O
be- O
|
| O
yond O
all O
expectation O
favourable O
. O
|

| O
An O
old O
proverb O
declares O
that O
“ O
a O
goose- O
|
| O
quill O
is O
more O
powerful O
than O
a O
lion O
’s O
claw O
, O
” O
|
| O
and O
authors O
have O
been O
called O
“ O
keepers O
|
| O
of O
the O
public O
conscience O
  O
” O
but O
no O
influ- O
|
| O
ence O
is O
perhaps O
so O
extensive O
as O
that O
exer- B-PERSON
|
| O
cised O
by O
what O
is O
termed O
“ O
light O
reading O
, O
” O
|
| O
which O
has O
now O
in O
a O
great O
measure O
super- O
|
| O
seded O
public O
places O
and O
theatrical O
enter- O
|
| O
tainments O
, O
affording O
a O
popular O
resource O
|
| O
with O
which O
the O
busiest O
men O
relax O
their O
|
| O
hard O
- O
working O
minds O
, O
and O
the O
idlest O
oc- O
|
| O
cupy O
their O
idleness O
. O
It O
becomes O
a O
deep O
|
| O
responsibility O
, O
therefore O
, O
of O
which O
the O
|
| O
author O
trusts O
she O
has O
ever O
felt O
duly O
sensi- O
|
| O
ble O
, O
to O
claim O
the B-TIME
leisure I-TIME
hours I-TIME
of O
so O
|
| O
many O
, O
while O
it O
is O
her O
first B-ORDINAL
desire O
that O
|
| O
whatever O
be O
the O
defects O
of O
these O
pages O
, O
|
| O
no O
actual O
evil O
may O
be O
intermingled O
, O
and O
|
| O
the O
cause O
of O
sound O
religion O
and O
morality O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
m O
|

| O
supported O
, O
for O
her O
feelings O
are O
best O
ex- O
|
| O
pressed O
in O
the O
words O
of O
the O
poet O
, O
|

| O
“ O
If O
I O
one B-CARDINAL
soul O
improve O
, O
I O
have O
not O
liv’d O
in O
vain O
. O
” O
|

| O
Novel O
- O
reading O
, O
formerly O
considered O
the O
|
| O
lowest O
resource O
of O
intellectual O
vacuity O
, O
|
| O
has O
been O
lately O
promoted O
to O
a O
new O
place O
|
| O
in O
the O
literary O
world O
, O
since O
men O
of O
the O
|
| O
brightest O
genius O
as O
well O
as O
of O
the O
highest O
|
| O
attainments O
in O
learning O
and O
philosophy O
, O
|
| O
allow O
their O
pens O
occasionally O
to O
wander O
|
| O
in O
the O
attractive O
regions O
of O
fiction O
  O
there- O
|
| O
fore O
works O
of O
imagination O
, O
no O
longer O
|
| O
merely O
a O
clandestine O
amusement O
to O
fri- O
|
| O
volous O
minds O
, O
are O
now O
avowedly O
read O
|
| O
and O
enjoyed O
, O
to O
beguile O
an B-TIME
idle I-TIME
hour I-TIME
, O
or O
|
| O
to O
cheer O
a O
gloomy O
one O
, O
by O
men O
of O
science O
, O
|
| O
of O
wisdom O
, O
and O
of O
piety O
. O
Such O
is O
the O
|
| O
general O
encouragement O
given O
now O
to O
|
| O
works O
of O
fancy O
, O
that O
, O
as O
the O
literary O
exist- O
|
| O
ence O
of O
authors O
depends O
on O
attracting O
|
| O
readers O
, O
there O
will O
scarcely O
be O
encourage- O
|
| O
ment O
enough O
soon O
to O
induce O
historians O
|

| O
vi O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
and O
biographers O
to O
dip O
the O
pen O
of O
vera- O
|
| O
city O
into O
the O
ink O
of O
retrospection O
, O
while O
|
| O
it O
is O
perhaps O
to O
be O
lamented O
that O
when O
|
| O
so O
large O
a O
proportion O
of O
the O
public O
atten- O
|
| O
tion O
is O
occupied O
by O
novelists O
, O
their O
works O
|
| O
being O
certain O
of O
instant O
circulation O
, O
for O
a O
|
| O
very O
short O
period O
and O
for O
no O
more O
, O
few O
|
| O
authors O
afford O
themselves O
time O
to O
aspire O
|
| O
at O
the O
highest O
grade O
of O
imaginary O
com- O
|
| O
position O
. O
When O
such O
volumes O
are O
really O
|
| O
true O
to O
nature O
, O
they O
convey O
very O
impor- O
|
| O
tant O
truths O
in O
a O
form O
more O
popular O
than O
|
| O
a O
dry O
sententious O
volume O
of O
moral O
pre- O
|
| O
cepts O
, O
and O
perhaps O
history O
itself O
can O
|
| O
scarcely O
afford O
so O
graphic O
a O
portrait O
of O
|
| O
human O
life O
as O
many O
of O
those O
fictitious O
|
| O
volumes O
, O
written O
under O
the O
inspiration O
|
| O
of O
genius O
, O
which O
portray O
in O
vivid O
colour- O
|
| O
ing O
, O
the O
thoughts O
and O
motives O
by O
which O
|
| O
men O
are O
internally O
influenced O
. O
|

| O
The B-WORK_OF_ART
Life I-WORK_OF_ART
of I-WORK_OF_ART
Cleopatra I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
or O
the O
Memoirs B-WORK_OF_ART
|
| O
of O
Agrippina B-PERSON
can O
afford O
scarcely O
so O
much O
|
| O
direction O
to O
young O
ladies O
respecting O
their O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
vil O
|

| O
views O
of O
life O
and O
manners O
in O
the B-DATE
present I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
as O
might O
be O
conveyed O
by O
a O
judici- O
|
| O
ously O
- O
drawn O
portrait O
of O
that O
world O
as O
it O
|
| O
is O
, O
on O
the O
stage O
of O
which O
they O
are O
about O
|
| O
to O
be O
personally O
introduced O
  O
and O
a O
large O
|
| O
proportion O
of O
those O
elaborate O
volumes O
|
| O
dignified O
with O
the O
name O
of O
history O
, O
can O
|
| O
only O
be O
considered O
in O
the O
main O
fictitious O
, O
|
| O
because O
, O
while O
biographers O
would O
confi- O
|
| O
dently O
state O
the O
private O
opinions O
, O
secret O
|
| O
intentions O
, O
and O
real O
characters O
: O
of O
illustri- O
|
| O
ous O
men O
who O
lived O
and O
acted O
several B-DATE
|
| I-DATE
hundred B-DATE
years I-DATE
ago I-DATE
, O
they O
can O
not O
justly O
|
| O
estimate O
the O
actual O
dispositions O
and O
mo- O
|
| O
tives O
of O
their O
own O
most O
intimate O
friends O
, O
|
| O
nor O
confidently O
point O
out O
what O
circum- O
|
| O
stances O
have O
influenced O
the O
greatest O
|
| O
events O
in O
their B-DATE
own I-DATE
day I-DATE
. O
If O
two B-CARDINAL
authors O
, O
|
| O
entertaining O
opposite O
political O
sentiments O
, O
|
| O
were O
to O
write O
the O
history O
of O
last B-DATE
year I-DATE
, O
|
| O
every O
fact O
recorded O
, O
and O
every O
individual O
|
| O
mentioned O
must O
inevitably O
be O
represent- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ed I-PERSON
, O
or O
misrepresented O
, O
according O
to O
the O
|

 

| O
viii O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
writer O
’s O
own O
private O
feelings O
, O
while O
each O
|
| O
would O
believe O
he O
was O
writing O
unadulte- O
|
| O
rated O
truth O
. O
|

| O
Thus O
poctry O
and O
fiction O
, O
when O
true O
to O
|
| O
the O
principles O
of O
human O
life O
, O
exhibit O
the O
|
| O
mind O
and O
soul O
of O
man O
visibly O
to O
the O
|
| O
senses O
  O
and O
history O
, O
which O
has O
been O
call- O
|
| O
ed O
“ O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Newgate I-WORK_OF_ART
Calendar I-WORK_OF_ART
of I-WORK_OF_ART
Kings I-WORK_OF_ART
and O
|
| O
Emperors O
, O
” O
supplies O
the O
facts O
of O
human O
|
| O
existence O
, O
and O
may O
be O
considered O
a O
por- O
|
| O
trait O
of O
men O
’s O
persons O
and O
external O
|
| O
actions O
. O
|

| O
In O
writing O
a O
story O
of O
domestic O
life O
, O
it O
|
| O
is O
singular O
to O
reflect O
how O
commonly O
men O
|
| O
are O
remembered O
by O
their O
eccentricities O
, O
|
| O
and O
loved O
for O
their O
very O
faults O
, O
while O
the O
|
| O
most O
difficult O
task O
in O
fiction O
is O
, O
to O
de- O
|
| O
scribe O
amiable O
persons O
so O
as O
to O
render O
|
| O
them O
at O
all O
interesting O
and O
not O
utterly O
|
| O
insipid O
. O
Probably O
it O
may O
be O
for O
this O
|
| O
reason O
that O
modern O
writers O
too O
frequent- O
|
| O
ly O
, O
instead O
of O
describing O
the O
principles O
|
| O
which O
ennoble O
human O
nature O
, O
and O
the O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
ix O
|

| O
sentiments O
which O
embellish O
life O
, O
have O
|
| O
painted O
in O
vivid O
colouring O
, O
all O
that O
is O
low O
, O
|
| O
mean O
, O
and O
vicious O
in O
society O
, O
introducing O
|
| O
their O
readers O
into O
scenes O
, O
the O
reality O
of O
|
| O
which O
would O
be O
shunned O
with O
abhor- O
|
| O
rence O
, O
and O
flinging O
over O
vice O
such O
a O
|
| O
mantle O
of O
genius O
as O
converts O
the O
defor- O
|
| O
mities O
of O
society O
into O
subjects O
of O
interest O
, O
|
| O
— O
unfortunately O
even O
of O
sympathy O
. O
|

| O
Were O
authors O
obliged O
hereafter O
, O
to O
live O
|
| O
with O
the O
characters O
they O
create O
, O
how O
few O
|
| O
would O
desire O
to O
share O
with O
them O
in O
such O
|
| O
a O
world O
! O
Even O
where O
the O
intention O
is O
to O
|
| O
represent O
an O
attractive O
character O
, O
it O
sel- O
|
| O
dom O
appears O
as O
one O
which O
could O
be O
an O
|
| O
agreeable O
acquisition O
to O
any O
family O
circle O
  O
|
| O
and O
in O
works O
of O
sentiment O
or O
feeling O
, O
no- O
|
| O
thing O
is O
less O
successfully O
pictured O
than O
a O
|
| O
generous O
and O
refined O
attachment O
, O
fitted O
|
| O
to O
survive O
every O
trial O
or O
vicissitude O
of O
|
| O
existence O
, O
between O
those O
who O
are O
to O
love O
|
| O
and O
to O
trust O
each O
other O
for O
ever O
. O
Few O
|
| O
stories O
could O
be O
written O
, O
if O
lovers O
in O
a O
|

| O
x O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
romance O
acted O
with O
the O
slightest O
degree O
|
| O
of O
mutual O
confidence O
or O
esteem O
  O
but O
such O
|
| O
narratives O
are O
generally O
founded O
on O
a O
|
| O
teazing O
succession O
of O
narrow O
- O
minded O
sus- O
|
| O
picions O
and O
unwarrantable O
concealments O
|
| O
on O
the O
part O
of O
heroes O
and O
heroines O
, O
who O
|
| O
condemn O
each O
other O
unheard O
, O
and O
go O
|
| O
through O
volumes O
of O
heart O
- O
breaking O
alie- O
|
| O
nation O
, O
enough O
to O
terminate O
life O
itself O
, O
|
| O
rather O
than O
ask O
the O
most O
simple O
explana- O
|
| O
tion O
, O
while O
the O
reader O
can O
not O
but O
feel O
a O
|
| O
certain O
conviction O
in O
closing O
the O
last O
|
| O
page O
, O
that O
an O
engagement O
begun O
with O
|
| O
cavilling O
jealousies O
and O
painful O
recrimina- O
|
| O
tions O
, O
can O
never O
become O
productive O
of O
|
| O
lasting O
peace O
. O
|

| O
The O
mothers O
and O
daughters O
in O
fashion- O
|
| O
able O
society O
have O
of O
late O
been O
so O
harshly O
|
| O
stigmatized O
by O
the O
press O
, O
that O
it O
seems O
as O
|
| O
if O
some O
authors O
had O
taken O
up O
a O
porcu- O
|
| O
pine O
’s O
quill O
dipped O
in O
gall O
, O
to O
ridicule O
|
| O
their O
conduct O
and O
motives O
, O
while O
not O
a O
|
| O
pen O
has O
yet O
been O
drawn O
from O
the O
scab- O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
xi O
|

| O
bard O
, O
nor O
a O
drop O
of O
ink O
spilled O
in O
their O
|
| O
justification O
  O
but O
the O
weight O
of O
censure O
|
| O
might O
become O
greatly O
lightened O
by O
being O
|
| O
more O
equitably O
divided O
among O
all O
who O
|
| O
are O
entitled O
to O
carry O
a O
share O
, O
and O
in O
|
| O
these O
volumes O
an O
endeavour O
is O
made O
to O
|
| O
rectify O
the O
balance O
more O
justly O
, O
though O
|
| O
with O
what O
success O
remains O
to O
be O
disco- O
|
| O
vered O
by O
the O
author O
herself O
, O
as O
not O
a O
|
| O
single O
friend O
ever O
sees O
her O
pages O
, O
or O
puts O
|
| O
on O
the O
spectacles O
of O
criticism O
till O
after O
|
| O
they O
are O
printed O
. O
The O
only O
peculiarity O
|
| O
to O
which O
she O
makes O
any O
pretension O
, O
in O
|
| O
once O
more O
presuming O
to O
publish O
, O
is O
, O
that O
|
| O
avoiding O
all O
caricature O
, O
all O
improbability O
, O
|
| O
and O
all O
personality O
, O
she O
has O
introduced O
a O
|
| O
few O
individuals O
acting O
and O
thinking O
in O
|
| O
the O
ordinary O
routine O
of O
every B-DATE
- I-DATE
day I-DATE
life O
, O
|
| O
while O
her O
highest O
ambition O
is O
to O
repre- O
|
| O
sent O
in O
natural O
colours O
, O
the O
conduct O
and O
|
| O
feelings O
of O
men O
elevated O
and O
ennobled O
by O
|
| O
the O
influence O
of O
Christianity B-NORP
. O
|

| O
When O
Dr O
Johnson B-PERSON
remarked O
once O
that O
|

| O
xii O
PREFACE O
, O
|

| O
it O
required O
a O
clever O
person O
to O
talk O
non- O
|
| O
sense O
well O
, O
Boswell B-PERSON
replied O
, O
“ O
Yes O
, O
sir O
! O
|
| O
If O
you O
were O
to O
represent O
little O
fishes O
|
| O
speaking O
, O
you O
would O
make O
them O
talk O
like O
|
| O
great O
whales O
  O
” O
and O
on O
a O
similar O
plan O
, O
|
| O
authors O
describing O
society O
, O
instead O
of O
|
| O
sketching O
the O
good O
- O
humoured O
chit O
- O
chat O
|
| O
and O
lively O
persiflage O
with O
which O
the O
busi- O
|
| O
ness O
and O
amusements O
of O
fashionable O
life O
|
| O
are O
carried O
on O
, O
too O
frequently O
fill O
up O
their O
|
| O
dialogues O
with O
set O
speeches O
, O
moral O
essays O
, O
|
| O
and O
long O
quotations O
, O
such O
as O
never O
are O
|
| O
extemporized O
in O
any O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
where O
|
| O
too O
energetic O
a O
stroke O
given O
to O
the O
shut- O
|
| O
tlecock O
of O
conversation O
, O
makes O
it O
in- O
|
| O
stantly O
fall O
to O
the O
ground O
. O
The O
fla- O
|
| O
grant O
impossibilities O
by O
which O
a O
careless- O
|
| O
ly O
- O
written O
narrative O
is O
carried O
on O
, O
de- O
|
| O
stroys O
often O
at O
once O
the O
illusion O
. O
Per- O
|
| O
sons O
are O
described O
, O
who O
may O
be O
overheard O
|
| O
speaking O
aloud O
their O
most O
seeret B-NORP
thoughts O
|
| O
when O
supposing O
themselves O
alone O
, O
solilo- O
|
| O
quizing O
audibly O
in O
the O
streets O
, O
journaliz- O
|

| O
PREFACE O
. O
xiii O
|

| O
ing O
a O
history O
of O
their O
own O
crimes O
, O
becom- O
|
| O
ing O
permanent O
guests O
in O
houses O
to O
which O
|
| O
they O
have O
no O
introduction O
, O
preserving O
the O
|
| O
noblest O
sentiments O
amidst O
the O
most O
de- O
|
| O
graded O
habits O
, O
and O
dying O
enlightened O
|
| O
Christians B-NORP
when O
they O
have O
lived O
as O
dis- O
|
| O
solute O
infidels O
. O
|

| O
A O
celebrated O
mathematician O
threw O
|
| O
aside O
a O
novel O
once O
in O
disgust O
, O
saying O
that O
|
| O
“ O
it O
proved O
nothing O
, O
” O
but O
in O
these O
pages O
|
| O
the O
author O
has O
endeavoured O
to O
prove O
|
| O
much O
. O
Amidst O
the O
bustle O
and O
business O
, O
|
| O
the O
joys O
and O
sorrows O
of O
life O
, O
she O
has O
at- O
|
| O
tempted O
to O
illustrate O
how O
truly O
“ O
wis- O
|
| O
dom O
’s O
ways O
are O
ways O
of O
pleasantness O
, O
and O
|
| O
all O
her O
paths O
are O
peace,’—how O
superior O
|
| O
is O
the O
standard O
of O
Christian B-NORP
principle O
to O
|
| O
the O
mere O
worldly O
code O
of O
honour O
or O
ex- O
|
| O
pediency O
, O
and O
how O
much O
of O
the O
happiness O
|
| O
intended O
for O
man O
by O
his O
Creator B-PERSON
is O
ruined O
|
| O
and O
forfeited O
by O
the O
perversity O
of O
his O
own O
|
| O
will O
, O
in O
neglecting O
the O
good O
of O
others O
, O
|
| O
and O
in O
yainly B-PERSON
grasping O
, O
like O
a O
spoiled O
|

| O
‘ O
|

| O
xiv O
PREFACE O
. O
|

| O
child O
, O
at O
more O
than O
is O
intended O
for O
his O
|
| O
share O
. O
While O
thus O
writing O
a O
fiction O
, O
which O
|
| O
may O
perhaps O
be O
denominated O
an O
enlarged O
|
| O
religious O
tract O
in O
high O
life O
, O
the O
author O
|
| O
humbly O
submits O
her O
pages O
to O
the O
judg- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
others O
, O
and O
can O
not O
conclude O
in O
|
| O
the O
words O
of O
a O
more O
universally O
venerat- O
|
| O
ed O
, O
or O
of O
a O
more O
generally O
popular O
ficti- O
|
| O
tious O
author O
than O
the O
excellent O
Bunyan O
: O
|

| O
« O
Thus O
I O
set O
pen O
to O
paper O
with O
delight O
, O
|
| O
‘ O
And O
quickly O
had O
my O
thoughts O
in O
black O
and O
white O
  O
|
| O
For O
having O
now O
my O
method O
by O
the O
end O
, O
. O
|
| O
Still O
as O
I O
pull’d O
it O
eame O
, O
and O
so O
I O
penned O
|

| O
It O
down O
, O
until O
at O
last O
it O
came O
to O
be O
, O
|

| O
For O
length O
and O
breadth O
, O
the O
bigness O
which O
you O
see O
. O
” O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
I. O
|

| O
I O
would O
advise O
a O
man O
to O
pause O
, O
|
| O
Before O
he O
take O
a O
wife O
  O
|

| O
Indeed O
I O
own O
F O
see O
no O
cause O
|
| O
He O
should O
not O
pause O
for O
life O
! O
|

| O
Tue O
newspapers O
have O
recently O
adopted O
a O
|
| O
strange O
habit O
of O
sometimes O
unexpectedly O
seiz- O
|
| O
ing O
an O
individual O
’s O
name O
, O
long O
since O
retired O
|
| O
from O
public O
notice O
, O
and O
gibbetting O
it O
up O
before O
|
| O
the O
world O
’s O
eye O
, O
when O
least O
anticipated O
, O
by O
|
| O
volunteering O
a O
paragraph O
to O
announce O
, O
that O
|
| O
some O
aged O
lord O
, O
or O
ex O
- O
minister O
, O
whom O
no O
one O
|
| O
has O
remembered O
to O
think O
of O
for O
half B-DATE
a I-DATE
century I-DATE
|
| O
or O
more O
, O
is O
residing O
on O
his O
estates O
, O
and O
enjoy- O
|
| O
VoL. O
I. B-ORG
A I-ORG
|

| I-ORG
2 I-ORG
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
ing O
, O
the O
editor O
is O
happy O
to O
understand O
, O
aston- O
|
| O
ishing O
health O
, O
considering O
his O
advanced O
years B-DATE
. O
|
| O
In O
observance O
of O
this O
custom O
, O
an O
exclamation O
|
| O
of O
irritability O
and O
astonishment O
, O
too O
violent O
to O
|
| O
be O
worthy O
of O
record O
, O
was O
elicited O
one B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
from O
|
| O
a O
dignified O
and O
very O
distinguished O
- O
looking O
old O
|
| O
gentleman O
, O
with O
a O
venerable O
head O
, O
such O
as O
|
| O
Titian B-NORP
might O
have O
painted O
, O
and O
a O
high O
lofty O
|
| O
forehead O
bearing O
the O
traces O
of O
deep O
thought O
|
| O
and O
feeling O
, O
when O
, O
after O
having O
seated O
himself O
|
| O
on O
his O
favourite O
arm O
chair O
at O
the O
United B-GPE
Ser- O
|
| O
vice O
Club B-ORG
in O
Edinburgh B-GPE
, O
his O
eye O
rested O
with O
a O
|
| O
look O
of O
kindling O
amazement O
on O
these O
few O
lines O
, O
|
| O
in O
large O
consequential O
- O
looking O
type O
, O
on O
a O
lead- O
|
| O
ing O
column O
of O
the O
Courant B-ORG
. O
|

| O
June B-DATE
1829 I-DATE
, O
“ O
We O
are O
happy O
to O
inform O
our O
|
| O
readers O
that O
the O
brave O
and O
noble O
veteran O
, O
once O
|
| O
a O
distinguished O
hero O
in O
many O
a O
well O
- O
fought O
|
| O
fight O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
Dunbar I-PERSON
, O
G.C.B. B-PERSON
, O
is O
yet O
alive O
, O
|
| O
reposing O
on O
his O
well O
- O
earncd O
laurels O
, O
at O
a O
retired O
|
| O
mansion O
in O
the O
marine O
village O
of O
Portobello B-GPE
. O
|
| O
Though O
frequently O
and O
most O
severely O
wounded O
|
| O
in O
battle O
, O
besides O
being O
deprived O
of O
an O
arm O
in O
|
| O
Lord O
Rodney B-PERSON
’s O
engagement O
during O
the B-DATE
year I-DATE
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
3 B-QUANTITY
|

| I-QUANTITY
° I-QUANTITY
82 B-DATE
, O
the O
Admiral B-ORG
’s O
health O
continues O
unimpaired O
|
| O
~ O
and O
his O
cheerfulness O
invariable O
, O
at O
the O
advanc- O
|
| O
ed O
age O
of O
70 B-DATE
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
“ O
Pshaw B-PERSON
! O
stuff O
and O
nonsense O
! O
Some O
enemy O
|
| O
is O
resolved O
to O
make O
a O
laughing O
- O
stock O
of O
me O
in O
|
| O
my O
old O
age O
! O
” O
exclaimed O
he O
, O
angrily O
pointing O
|
| O
out O
the O
paragraph O
to O
his O
gay O
young O
relative O
, O
|
| O
Louis B-PERSON
de I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
who O
was O
familiarly O
lean- O
|
| O
ing O
over O
the O
high O
back O
of O
his O
chair O
  O
and O
then O
|
| O
crumpling O
up O
the O
offending O
Courant B-ORG
with O
an O
|
| O
obvious O
wish O
that O
it O
might O
be O
consumed O
in O
|
| O
the O
flames O
— O
“ O
I O
hope O
this O
is O
only O
the O
work O
|
| O
of O
some O
wretched O
penny O
- O
a O
- O
liner O
  O
but O
if O
I O
even O
|
| O
suspected O
that O
my O
conceited O
, O
good O
- O
looking O
|
| O
seoundrel O
of O
a O
nephew O
had O
a O
hand O
in O
the O
jest O
, O
|
| O
I O
would O
cut O
him O
off O
with O
a O
shilling,—or O
rather O
|
| O
without O
one O
, O
for O
I O
could O
scarcely O
raise O
so O
|
| O
much O
as O
@ O
shilling O
to O
leave O
him O
, O
and O
he O
knows O
|
| O
that O
. O
This O
is O
most O
thoroughly O
ridiculous O
! O
I O
, O
|
| O
who O
have O
been O
dead O
, O
buried O
, O
and O
forgotten O
|
| O
for O
years B-DATE
, O
to O
be O
made O
as O
conspicuous O
here O
, O
as O
|
| O
a O
hair O
- O
dresser O
’s O
wig O
- O
block O
! O
The O
editor O
shall O
|
| O
be O
prosecuted,—horse O
- O
whipped,—or O
— O
or O
made O
|
| O
as O
absurd O
as O
he O
has O
made O
me O
! O
” O
|

| O
4 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
“ O
Why O
really O
, O
Admiral O
, O
I O
wish O
he O
had O
as O
|
| O
much O
good O
to O
say O
of O
us O
all O
, O
and O
then O
the O
|
| O
sooner O
he O
paragraphs O
about O
me O
the O
better O
! O
— O
|
| O
‘ O
We O
are O
happy O
to O
inform O
our O
readers O
, O
that O
|
| O
the O
agreeable O
and O
. O
fascinating O
Cornet B-ORG
De I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Crespigny I-ORG
, O
of O
the O
15th B-ORDINAL
Light B-ORG
Hussars I-ORG
, O
now O
in O
|
| O
his B-DATE
eighteenth I-DATE
year I-DATE
, O
is O
still O
alive O
! O
' O
— O
the O
public O
|
| O
likes O
to O
know O
the O
exact O
age O
of O
distinguished O
|

 

| O
men O
, O
such O
as O
you O
and O
I O
, O
Admiral O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
The O
public O
is O
an O
ass O
! O
” O
replied O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
breaking O
into O
a O
smile O
  O
“ O
and O
perhaps O
I O
am O
|
| O
another O
, O
to O
mind O
what O
is O
said O
at O
all O
, O
but O
that O
|
| O
rascal O
of O
an O
editor O
has O
made O
me O
ten B-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
older I-DATE
than O
I O
am O
  O
besides O
which O
, O
though O
a O
|
| O
grey O
- O
haired O
admiral O
of O
sixty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
four I-CARDINAL
is O
not O
proba- O
|
| O
bly O
much O
addicted O
to O
blushing O
, O
he O
really O
has O
|
| O
put O
my O
modest O
merit O
out O
of O
countenance O
. O
I O
|
| O
would O
rather O
pay O
the O
newspapers O
any O
day O
for O
|
| O
overlooking O
than O
for O
praising O
me O
. O
We O
ought O
|
| O
to O
live O
or O
die O
for O
our O
country O
  O
but O
now O
, O
when O
|
| O
Tam B-PERSON
no O
longer O
needed O
, O
let O
me O
stay O
in O
peace O
|
| O
on O
the O
shelf O
, O
like O
, O
” O
added O
he O
, O
giving O
a O
comic O
|
| O
smile O
at O
his O
empty O
sleeve O
, O
“ O
like O
a O
cracked O
tea- O
|
| O
cup O
with O
the O
handle O
off O
! O
” O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
3 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
“ O
But O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
! O
” O
replied O
the O
young O
Cor- O
|
| O
net O
warmly O
, O
“ O
you O
who O
never O
turned O
your O
back O
|
| O
on O
friend O
or O
foe O
, O
are O
not O
very O
likely O
to O
remain O
|
| O
quietly O
on O
the O
shelf O
, O
as O
long O
as O
every O
man O
who O
|
| O
lives O
must O
respect O
you O
, O
and O
every O
man O
who O
|
| O
dies O
continues O
to O
appoint O
you O
, O
as O
my O
father O
|
| O
did O
, O
his O
executor O
, O
the O
trustee O
of O
his O
estates O
, O
|
| O
and O
the O
guardian O
of O
his O
children O
, O
asking O
you O
|
| O
to O
lend O
them O
a O
hand O
, O
as O
you O
have O
done O
to O
me O
|
| O
in O
all O
the O
difficulties O
of O
life O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
T O
have O
but O
one O
hand O
to O
lend O
, O
and O
that O
is O
|
| O
much O
at O
your O
service O
, O
in O
whatever O
way O
it O
can O
|
| O
be O
useful O
! O
the O
other O
, O
though O
absent O
without O
|
| O
leave O
, O
has O
been O
my O
own O
best O
friend O
, O
as O
the O
loss O
|
| O
of O
that O
arm O
was O
the O
luckiest O
hit O
in O
the O
world O
. O
|
| O
It O
obtained O
me O
a O
step O
at O
the O
time O
, O
and O
the O
|
| O
pension O
has O
supported O
me O
ever O
since O
. O
What O
|
| O
with O
my O
nephew O
’s O
frantic O
extravagance O
, O
and O
|
| O
my O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
nieces O
being O
but O
indifferently O
|
| O
provided O
for O
, O
I O
often O
wish O
, O
like O
every O
body O
else O
, O
|
| O
for O
a O
larger O
income O
. O
Poor O
girls O
! O
” O
added O
Sir O
|
| O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
knitting O
his O
bushy O
eye O
- O
brows O
into O
a O
|
| O
portentous O
frown O
, O
which O
gave O
to O
his O
venerable O
|
| O
countenance O
a O
look O
of O
noble O
and O
manly O
sor- O
|

| O
6 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
row O
. O
“ O
No O
one O
can O
blame O
them O
! O
but O
it O
was O
|
| O
little O
short O
of O
insanity O
in O
my O
brother O
to O
leave O
|
| O
such O
young O
children O
under O
the O
sole O
guardian- O
|
| O
ship O
of O
a O
heartless O
spendthrift O
like O
your O
friend O
|
| O
and O
my O
nephew O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
, O
who O
would O
sell O
|
| O
his O
soul O
for O
sixpence O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Yes O
! O
and O
squander O
it O
the B-TIME
next I-TIME
minute I-TIME
, O
” O
|
| O
added O
young O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
“ O
I O
saw O
|
| O
Pat B-PERSON
produce O
a O
£ O
20 B-MONEY
note O
yesterday B-DATE
at O
Tait B-ORG
’s O
|
| O
auction O
- O
room O
, O
and O
a O
buzz O
of O
wonder O
ran O
all O
|
| O
through O
the O
eirele O
of O
his O
friends O
. O
Such O
a O
sight O
|
| O
had O
not O
been O
seen O
in O
his O
pocket O
for O
many B-DATE
a I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
and O
he O
threatened O
to O
put O
it O
up O
to O
auction O
, O
|
| O
saying O
, O
he O
was O
sure O
we O
would O
all O
give O
double O
|
| O
the O
value O
for O
it O
, O
as O
a O
rarity O
, O
considering O
the O
|
| O
quarter B-CARDINAL
from O
which O
it O
came O
. O
He O
really O
seems O
|
| O
to O
pique O
himself O
on O
his O
poverty O
, O
and O
has O
the O
|
| O
art O
of O
doing O
what O
another O
man O
would O
be O
cut O
|
| O
for O
, O
with O
so O
much O
grace O
and O
apparent O
uncon- O
|
| O
sciousness O
, O
that O
his O
friends O
really O
acd O
to O
|
| O
disapprove O
. O
|

| O
“ O
J O
never O
forget O
! O
” O
replied O
the O
Admiral B-ORG
, O
|
| O
slowly O
rising O
and O
adjusting O
his O
spectacles O
. O
“ O
I O
|
| O
am O
even O
told O
the O
incorrigible O
rascal O
has O
mort- O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
gaged O
the O
legacy O
he O
pretends O
to O
expect O
from O
|
| O
me O
! O
He O
would O
do O
anything O
short O
of O
a O
high- O
|
| O
way O
robbery O
for O
money O
, O
and O
has O
done O
some O
|
| O
things O
that O
seem O
to O
a O
man O
of O
honour O
quite O
as O
|
| O
bad O
. O
But O
, O
” O
added O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
growing O
more O
|
| O
and O
more O
angry O
, O
“ O
as O
long O
as O
he O
can O
give O
his O
|
| O
friends O
a O
good O
bottle O
of O
claret O
, O
they O
ask O
no O
|
| O
questions O
! O
Patrick B-PERSON
Dunbar I-PERSON
has O
caused O
me O
the O
|
| O
only O
feeling O
of O
shame O
I O
ever O
had O
occasion O
for O
, O
|
| O
and O
yet O
to O
see O
that O
proud O
snuff O
- O
the O
- O
moon O
look O
|
| O
of O
his O
, O
you O
would O
suppose O
the O
world O
scarcely O
|
| O
big O
enough O
to O
hold O
him O
! O
With O
his O
chin O
in O
the O
|
| O
air O
, O
as O
I O
saw O
him O
yesterday B-DATE
, O
he O
will O
certainly O
|
| O
knock O
his O
forehead O
some B-DATE
day I-DATE
against O
the O
sky O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
You O
can O
not O
wonder O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
that O
|
| O
Dunbar B-PERSON
is O
in O
immense O
favour O
with O
himself O
, O
|
| O
when O
he O
is O
so O
admired O
, O
and O
almost O
idolized O
in O
|
| O
society O
. O
He O
certainly O
has O
the O
handsomest O
|
| O
countenance O
in O
Scotland B-GPE
  O
— O
as O
my O
uncle O
Don- O
|
| O
easter O
says O
, O
Pat B-PERSON
is O
a O
portrait O
by O
Vandyke B-PERSON
, O
in O
|
| O
his O
best O
style O
. O
With O
that O
grand O
, O
chivalrous O
, O
|
| O
Chevalier B-ORG
- I-ORG
Bayard I-ORG
look O
, O
he O
is O
the O
best O
rider O
|
| O
who O
ever O
sat O
on O
horseback O
! O
I O
could O
not O
but O
|
| O
laugh O
when O
he O
mounted O
yesterday B-DATE
for O
a O
ride O
|

| O
‘ O
|

| O
8 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
along O
Princes B-FAC
Street I-FAC
, O
and O
turned O
to O
me O
, O
with O
|
| O
his O
lively O
, O
victorious O
laugh O
, O
saying O
, O
‘ O
Now O
I O
am O
|
| O
going O
to O
give O
tle B-ORG
ladies O
a O
treat O
” O
|

| O
“ O
The O
insufferable O
coxcomb O
! O
” O
said O
Sir O
Ar- O
|
| O
thur O
, O
relaxing O
jnto O
an O
irresistible O
smile O
of O
in- O
|
| O
dulgent O
affection O
. O
“ O
From O
the B-DATE
day I-DATE
he O
first B-ORDINAL
|
| O
came O
swaggering O
into O
this O
world O
to O
astonish O
|
| O
us O
all O
, O
he O
has O
thought O
himself O
the O
finest O
sight O
|
| O
between O
this O
and O
Whitehall B-ORG
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Of O
course O
he O
does O
! O
Pat B-PERSON
is O
asked O
for O
so O
|
| O
many O
locks O
of O
his O
hair O
, O
by O
various O
young B-PERSON
la- I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
dies I-PERSON
, O
that O
his O
valet O
keeps O
a O
wig O
to O
supply O
|
| O
them O
  O
and O
he O
might O
almost O
pay O
his O
debts O
|
| O
with O
the O
countless O
collection O
he O
has O
received O
|
| O
of O
sentimental O
rings O
, O
displaying O
forgotten O
for- B-CARDINAL
|
| O
get O
- O
me O
- O
nots O
, O
in O
turquoises O
and O
gold O
! O
Who O
, O
on O
|
| O
the O
wide O
earth O
, O
except O
yourself O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
would O
ever O
dream O
of O
finding O
fault O
with O
our O
|
| O
gay O
, O
dashing O
, O
high O
- O
spirited O
friend O
, O
Dunbar B-PERSON
, O
the O
|
| O
life O
of O
society O
, O
the O
model O
of O
dress O
, O
equipage O
. O
|
| O
and O
good O
living O
. O
Why O
! O
the O
very O
instant O
he O
|
| O
opens O
his O
lips O
, O
all O
dulness O
vanishes O
like O
a O
spec- O
|
| O
tre O
! O
I O
wish O
the O
whole O
world O
were O
peopled O
|
| O
with O
such O
men O
  O
but O
he O
promises O
to O
shoot O
him- O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
9 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
self O
as O
soon O
as O
he O
sees O
his O
own O
equal O
. O
He O
|
| O
staked O
his O
reputation O
one B-DATE
day I-DATE
that O
he O
would O
! O
” O
|

| O
‘ O
His O
reputation O
! O
! O
the O
sooner O
he O
parts O
|
| O
with O
it O
the O
better O
! O
Let O
Patrick B-PERSON
Dunbar I-PERSON
ex- O
|
| O
change O
his O
own O
with O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
man O
he O
meets O
in O
|
| O
the O
street O
, O
and O
he O
will O
gain O
by O
the O
bargain O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Pardon O
me O
, O
there O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
your O
ne- O
|
| O
phew O
is O
universally O
allowed O
to O
be O
the O
best O
fel- O
|
| O
low O
upon O
earth O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Very O
probably O
! O
the O
‘ O
best O
fellow O
upon O
|
| O
earth O
’ O
generally O
means O
a O
, O
selfish O
, O
extravagant O
, O
|
| O
seatter O
- O
brained O
roué O
  O
but O
I O
must O
be O
off O
! O
|
| O
There O
is O
a O
cold O
, O
sharp O
, O
cutting O
wind O
, O
blowing O
|
| O
in O
at O
the O
back O
of O
my O
neck O
, O
which O
makes O
me O
|
| O
feel O
like O
Charles B-PERSON
the I-PERSON
First I-PERSON
when O
the O
axe O
fell O
. O
|
| O
If O
you O
have O
any O
influence O
, O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
with O
|
| O
my O
seape O
- O
grace O
of O
a O
nephew O
— O
all O
nephews O
are O
|
| O
scape O
- O
graces O
, O
as O
far O
as O
my O
experience O
goes O
— O
|
| O
try O
to O
make O
him O
more O
like O
yourself O
, O
and O
I O
|
| O
shall O
be O
grateful O
, O
with O
all O
my O
heart O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Like O
me O
! O
! O
! O
” O
said O
the O
young O
Cornet B-PERSON
, O
turn- O
|
| O
ing O
away O
with O
a O
smile O
  O
but O
it O
was O
a O
smile O
of O
|
| O
bitterness O
, O
almost O
amounting O
to O
remorse O
, O
while O
|
| O
he O
hastily O
grasped O
a O
newspaper O
, O
and O
flung O
|

| O
10 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
himself O
into O
a O
seat O
. O
“ O
No O
! O
no O
! O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
he O
is O
not O
quite O
so O
bad O
as O
that O
. O
Dunbar B-PERSON
has O
|
| O
his O
faults O
  O
he O
wears O
them O
upon O
his O
sleeve O
, O
and O
|
| O
attempts O
no O
disguise O
  O
but O
there O
are O
many O
|
| O
worse O
men O
in O
the O
world O
, O
who O
are O
held O
up O
as O
|
| O
examples O
by O
those O
who O
know O
no O
_ O
better O
. O
|
| O
Whenever O
I O
reform O
myself O
, O
you O
may O
depend O
|
| O
upon O
my O
lecturing O
our O
friend O
, O
but O
not O
till O
then O
. O
|
| O
We O
must O
both O
sow O
all O
our O
wild O
oats O
first B-ORDINAL
. O
” O
|
| O
“ O
Yes O
! O
and O
endure O
the O
fruit O
of O
them O
after- O
|
| O
wards O
, O
” O
replied O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
with O
a O
look O
of O
|
| O
anxious O
kindness O
at O
his O
young O
relative O
. O
“ O
That O
|
| O
is O
the O
only O
crop O
where O
to O
sow O
is O
more O
agree- O
|
| O
able O
than O
to O
reap O
! O
But O
I O
waste O
words O
! O
|
| O
‘ O
Young O
men O
will O
be O
young O
men O
, O
and O
I O
might O
|
| O
as O
well O
ask O
this O
east O
wind O
not O
to O
blow O
, O
or O
try O
|
| O
to O
turn O
the O
sea O
from O
its O
course O
, O
as O
attempt O
to O
|
| O
stop O
the O
mad O
career O
of O
that O
scatter O
- O
brained O
|
| O
madcap O
! O
It O
would O
matter O
less O
if O
he O
only O
fell O
|
| O
himself O
hereafter O
, O
like O
a O
pebble O
in O
the O
stream O
  O
|
| O
but O
the O
fatal O
eddy O
extends O
in O
a O
wide O
circle O
, O
|
| O
which O
must O
reach O
the O
interests O
of O
those O
help- O
|
| O
less O
young O
girls O
, O
my O
nieces O
  O
and O
I O
can O
not O
but O
|
| O
grieve O
over O
the O
consequences O
which O
may O
, O
and O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
il O
|

| O
must O
befall O
them O
, O
after O
I O
go O
to O
that O
rest O
which O
|
| O
is O
in O
the O
grave O
, O
and O
to O
that O
hope O
which O
is O
be- O
|
| O
yond O
it O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Never O
trouble O
your O
head O
about O
what O
shall O
|
| O
occur O
then O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
! O
‘ O
Too O
much O
care O
|
| O
once O
made O
an O
old O
man O
grey B-PERSON
. O
’ O
My O
motto O
is O
, O
|
| O
“ O
apres O
moi O
le O
deluge O
! O
This O
little O
world O
of O
ours O
|
| O
got O
on O
wonderfully O
well O
before O
we O
came O
into O
|
| O
it O
, O
and O
will O
do O
astonishingly O
well O
again O
, O
after O
|
| O
we O
make O
our O
exit O
, O
” O
said O
young O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
|
| O
with O
a O
strange O
medley O
in O
his O
tone O
, O
of O
melancho- O
|
| O
ly O
thought O
, O
and O
contemptuous O
derision O
. O
“ O
Pat B-PERSON
|
| O
tells O
me O
that O
both O
my O
young O
cousins O
promise O
|
| O
to O
turn O
out O
a O
perfect O
blaze O
of O
beauty O
, O
with O
long O
|
| O
shining O
ringlets O
that O
they O
almost O
tread O
upon O
|
| O
in O
walking O
, O
teeth O
that O
would O
make O
the O
fortune O
|
| O
of O
a O
dentist O
, O
and O
complexions O
that O
Rowland B-ORG
’s O
|
| O
kalydor B-GPE
could O
not O
improve O
. O
Ten B-DATE
years I-DATE
hence O
, O
|
| O
I O
shall O
propose O
to O
one B-CARDINAL
or O
both O
of O
them O
, O
myself O
, O
|
| O
if O
that O
will O
give O
you O
satisfaction O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Perfect B-WORK_OF_ART
! O
but O
as O
marrying O
two B-CARDINAL
sisters O
at O
|
| O
once O
is O
not O
quite O
customary O
, O
let O
your O
inten- O
|
| O
tions O
be O
limited O
to O
Agnes- O
She O
is O
several B-DATE
|
| I-DATE
years I-DATE
the O
eldest O
  O
and O
I O
like O
the O
good O
old O
pa- O
|

| O
12 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
triarchal O
rule O
of O
marrying O
by O
seniority O
  O
be- O
|
| O
sides O
which O
, O
she O
is O
quite O
a O
little O
flirt O
already O
, O
|
| O
though O
scarcely O
yet O
in O
her O
teens O
. O
She O
will O
be O
|
| O
a O
young O
lady O
, O
entirely O
suited O
for O
the O
ordinary O
|
| O
marrying O
and O
giving O
in O
marriage O
of O
every B-DATE
- I-DATE
day I-DATE
|
| O
life O
  O
‘ O
but O
little O
Marion B-PERSON
is O
the O
very O
light O
of O
my O
|
| O
eyes O
, O
and O
I O
must O
match O
her O
by O
a O
very O
high O
|
| O
standard O
indeed O
. O
It O
will O
be O
a O
dark O
day O
for O
|
| O
me O
, O
if O
Iam O
ever O
obliged O
to O
part O
with O
her O
at O
|
| O
all O
  O
and O
being O
now O
only O
in O
her B-DATE
sixth I-DATE
year I-DATE
, O
1 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
may O
, O
without O
selfishness O
, O
hope O
to O
keep O
her O
be- O
|
| O
side O
me O
for O
my B-DATE
few I-DATE
remaining I-DATE
days I-DATE
. O
I O
must O
|
| O
begin O
match O
- O
making O
for O
Agnes B-ORG
, O
however O
, O
di- O
|
| O
rectly O
, O
and O
your O
offer O
shall O
be O
duly O
considered O
. O
|
| O
A O
future O
peer O
, O
with O
countless O
thousands B-CARDINAL
in O
|
| O
expectancy O
, O
and O
not O
particularly O
ill O
- O
looking O
, O
|
| O
does O
not O
fall O
in O
our O
way O
every O
morning O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
So O
all O
the O
young O
ladies O
seem O
to O
think O
! O
” O
|
| O
replied O
the O
young O
Cornet B-PERSON
, O
in O
his O
most O
conceited O
|
| O
tone O
. O
“ O
Girls O
dislike O
nothing O
so O
much O
as O
to O
|
| O
marry O
on O
a O
competence O
  O
there O
is O
a O
great O
deal O
|
| O
of O
romance O
in O
marrying O
on O
nothing O
, O
and O
a O
|
| O
great O
deal O
of O
comfort O
in O
marrying O
on O
wealth O
  O
|
| O
but O
a O
mere O
vulgar O
competence O
has O
neither O
ro- O
|

| O
— O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
13 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
mance O
nor O
reality O
. O
Now O
I O
can O
offer O
both O
! O
|
| O
First B-ORDINAL
, O
actual O
starvation O
on O
a O
Cornet B-ORG
’s O
pay O
  O
|
| O
and O
then O
, O
with O
my O
uncle O
’s O
leave O
, O
the O
pumpkin O
|
| O
will O
turn O
to O
a O
carriage O
, O
and O
the O
mice O
into O
|
| O
horses O
  O
but O
in O
the O
mean O
time O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
Pat B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
tells O
me O
you O
keep O
a O
capital O
chop O
- O
house O
at O
Por- O
|

| O
“ O
tobello O
, O
so O
pray O
invite O
me O
to O
drop O
in O
some B-DATE
day I-DATE
|

| O
at O
six B-CARDINAL
, O
to O
begin O
my O
siege O
of O
your O
pretty O
niece O
. O
|
| O
I O
must O
come O
and O
‘ O
see O
, O
before O
I O
can O
conquer O
, O
” O
|
| O
added O
Mr O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
in O
a O
tone O
of O
peculiar O
|
| O
conceit O
, O
with O
which O
he O
always O
spoke O
either O
to O
|
| O
ladies O
or O
of O
them O
. O
“ O
Probably O
next B-DATE
week I-DATE
I O
|
| O
may O
find O
my O
way O
to O
this O
terra O
incognita O
of O
|
| O
yours O
. O
Is O
it O
across O
the O
Queensferry B-GPE
, O
or O
where O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
My O
good O
friend O
! O
you O
are O
not O
so O
pre O
- O
emi- O
|
| O
nently O
ignorant O
of O
geography O
as O
you O
would O
|
| O
appear O
  O
for O
did O
I O
not O
see O
you O
honouring O
that O
|
| O
dullest O
of O
all O
dull O
places O
, O
the O
little O
obscure O
vil- O
|
| O
lage O
of O
Portobello B-GPE
, O
with O
your O
august B-DATE
presence O
, O
|
| O
only B-DATE
yesterday I-DATE
. O
I O
nearly O
spitted O
you O
on O
the O
|
| O
point O
of O
my O
umbrella O
, O
you O
hurried O
so O
rapidly O
|
| O
Rast B-PRODUCT
, O
evidently O
wishing O
to O
escape O
from O
that O
girl O
|
| O
iia O
cloak O
, O
who O
seemed O
to O
beset O
your O
footsteps O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Impossible O
! O
! O
! O
” O
exclaimed O
young O
De B-ORG
Cres- I-ORG
|

| I-ORG
14 I-ORG
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
pigny O
, O
colouring O
violently O
, O
and O
starting O
from O
|
| O
his O
seat O
. O
“ O
Could O
it O
be O
in O
the O
nature O
of O
things O
|
| O
that O
I O
should O
cut O
you O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
True O
enough O
! O
I O
might O
have O
said O
, O
like O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Towereliffe I-PERSON
to O
Prince O
Meimkoff B-ORG
, O
‘ O
cous O
|
| O
a O
avez O
coupe O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Indeed O
! O
” O
continued O
the O
cornet O
, O
trying O
to O
|
| O
conceal O
his O
countenance O
. O
“ O
I O
wish O
you O
had O
|
| O
eut O
my O
throat O
in O
return O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Tf O
it O
is O
to O
be O
done O
, O
I O
would O
rather O
some- O
|
| O
body O
else O
did O
! O
Why O
, O
De B-PERSON
Orespigny I-PERSON
! O
you O
will O
|
| O
set O
the O
house O
on O
fire O
with O
that O
violent O
poker O
|
| O
exercise O
! O
Your O
own O
face O
is O
on O
fire O
already O
! O
|
| O
Have O
more O
regard O
for O
your O
complexion O
! O
Ah O
! O
|
| O
now O
it O
is O
pale O
enough O
! O
Are O
you O
ill O
? O
My O
|
| O
dear O
fellow O
! O
what O
is O
the O
matter O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Nothing O
! O
I O
am O
merely O
looking O
at O
the O
|
| O
beautiful O
sun O
- O
set O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
What O
! O
does O
the O
sun O
set O
in O
the O
east O
to- O
|
| O
night O
? O
” O
asked O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
, O
jestingly O
  O
“ O
that O
|
| O
is O
worth O
looking O
at O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
T O
am O
annoyed O
with O
a O
spasm O
of O
tooth- O
|
| O
ache O
! O
” O
said O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
putting O
a O
handker- O
|
| O
chief O
to O
his O
face O
, O
which O
nearly O
covered O
it O
  O
and O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
15 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
then O
suddenly O
throwing O
opal O
the O
window O
, O
he O
|
| O
looked O
far O
out O
, O
as O
if O
in O
search O
of O
his O
groom O
. O
|
| O
He O
leaned O
forward O
so O
long O
, O
however O
, O
that O
Sir O
|
| O
Arthur B-PERSON
kindly O
but O
vehemently O
remonstrated O
|
| O
on O
the O
danger O
of O
exposing O
himself O
, O
while O
in O
so O
|
| O
much O
pain O
, O
to O
the O
cold O
air O
  O
enumerated O
a O
|
| O
whole O
host O
of O
remedies O
for O
decayed O
teeth O
  O
|
| O
suggested O
the O
great O
comfort O
and O
convenience O
|
| O
of O
having O
the O
offender O
extracted O
by O
Hutchins B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
and O
ended O
by O
hoping O
his O
young O
friend O
would O
|
| O
still O
have O
a O
tooth O
left O
for O
his O
proposed O
dinner O
|
| O
at O
Portobello B-GPE
. O
|

| O
“ O
Depend O
upon O
me O
for O
that O
, O
” O
replied O
Mr O
|
| O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
with O
forced O
vivacity O
. O
“ O
I O
shall O
|
| O
ferret O
you O
out O
next B-DATE
week I-DATE
. O
I O
have O
little O
doubt O
|
| O
your O
pasture O
is O
excellent O
in O
that B-DATE
quarter I-DATE
, O
and O
|
| O
there O
is O
no O
one O
from O
whom O
I O
should O
be O
half B-CARDINAL
|
| O
so O
happy O
to O
receive O
a O
soup O
ticket O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Keep O
your O
flattery O
for O
the O
ladies O
, O
where O
it O
|
| O
will O
always O
be O
acceptable O
, O
and O
where O
I O
hear O
, O
|
| O
you O
are O
already O
an O
experienced O
practitioner O
|
| O
in O
the O
arts O
of O
captivation O
. O
As O
for O
my O
dinner O
, O
|
| O
I O
consider O
it’an B-ORG
imposition O
to O
ask O
any O
friend O
, O
|
| O
and O
not O
give O
him O
the O
best O
my O
cook O
and O
cellar O
|

| O
16 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
can O
furnish O
  O
and O
you O
may O
expect O
whenever O
|
| O
you O
do O
come O
, O
to O
find O
a O
notice O
over O
my O
door O
, O
|
| O
“ O
hot O
joints O
every O
day O
! O
’ O
” O
|

| O
“ O
But O
it O
was O
the O
society O
of O
your O
house O
, O
and O
|
| O
not O
the O
dinner O
, O
to O
which O
my O
agreeable O
antici- O
|
| O
pations O
were O
directed O
  O
and O
there O
, O
you O
know O
, O
|
| O
Tcannot O
be O
disappointed O
! O
as O
somebody O
wise- O
|
| O
ly O
said O
, O
when O
shewn O
a O
tempting O
bill O
of O
fare O
, O
|
| O
‘ O
shew O
me O
a O
bill O
of O
the O
company O
! O
’ O
” O
|

| O
“ O
That O
reminds O
me O
to O
say O
, O
you O
must O
not O
ex- O
|
| O
pect O
my O
pretty O
niece O
to O
be O
at O
my O
little O
bath- O
|
| O
ing O
machine O
of O
a O
house O
! O
Tt O
would O
not O
be O
fair O
|
| O
to O
inveigle O
you O
under O
such O
false O
pretences O
  O
but O
|
| O
T O
promise O
you O
an O
old O
man O
’s O
welcome O
, O
and O
the O
|
| O
best O
that O
my O
cottage O
can O
produce O
  O
aged O
as O
|
| O
this O
newspaper O
makes O
me O
, O
I O
enjoy O
every O
inch O
|
| O
of O
life O
, O
and O
hope O
you O
, O
at O
the O
same O
age O
, O
will O
do O
|
| O
the O
same O
. O
I O
may O
almost O
apply O
to O
my O
little O
|
| O
villa O
that O
favourite O
saying O
in O
Spain B-GPE
, O
|

| O
« O
My O
home O
, O
my O
home O
! O
though O
thou O
’ O
rt O
but O
small O
, O
|
| O
‘ O
Thou O
art O
to O
me O
th O
’ O
Escurial O
. O
’ O
” O
|

| O
With O
a O
cordial O
shake O
of O
the O
hand O
, O
and O
w O
|
| O
smile O
of O
cheerful O
benignity O
, O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
with- O
|
| O
drew O
, O
and O
as O
his O
firm O
and O
stately O
step O
receded O
, O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
17 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
Mr O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
watched O
him O
with O
a O
look O
of O
|
| O
respectful O
interest O
, O
which O
ended O
in O
his O
turning O
|
| O
away O
after O
the O
admiral O
had O
disappeared O
, O
and O
|
| O
heaving O
a O
deep O
sigh O
, O
while O
a O
cloud O
of O
care O
|
| O
darkened O
on O
his O
forehead O
, O
and O
a O
look O
of O
angry O
|
| O
yexation O
shaded O
his O
previously O
animated O
eyes O
. O
|

| O
Day B-DATE
after I-DATE
day I-DATE
passed O
on O
, O
subsequent O
to O
|
| O
the O
preceding O
conversation O
, O
during O
’ O
which O
Sir O
|
| O
Arthur B-PERSON
frequently O
postponed O
his O
chop O
, O
to O
what O
|
| O
he O
considered O
an O
atrociously O
late B-TIME
hour I-TIME
, O
in O
|
| O
hopes O
of O
his O
promised O
guest O
appearing O
. O
Once O
|
| O
the O
admiral O
felt O
positively O
convinced O
that O
he O
|
| O
had O
seen O
him O
enter O
a O
Portobello B-ORG
omnibus O
at O
|
| O
four B-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
, O
but O
still O
he O
appeared O
not O
. O
Week B-DATE
|
| I-DATE
after I-DATE
week I-DATE
elapsed O
, O
and O
still O
Sir O
Arthur B-PERSON
ate O
|
| O
his O
dinner O
alone O
, O
in O
long O
- O
surviving O
expectation O
, O
|
| O
that O
either O
his O
own O
not O
very O
dutiful O
nephew O
, O
|
| O
or O
young O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
would O
“ O
cast O
up O
  O
” O
but O
|
| O
at O
last O
these O
hopes O
and O
wishes O
were O
ended O
by O
|
| O
his O
hearing O
that O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
’s O
embarrassments O
|
| O
had O
caused O
him O
to O
leave O
Edinburgh B-GPE
by O
moon- O
|
| O
light O
, O
and O
that O
, O
soon O
after O
, O
Mr O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
|
| O
as O
suddenly O
departed O
, O
no O
one O
knew O
why O
, O
when O
, O
|
| O
or O
wherefore O
. O
|

| O
18 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
II O
. O
|

 

| O
“ O
The O
child O
is O
father O
of O
the O
man O
. O
” O
|
| O
Worpswormut O
, O
|

| O
‘ O
Tue B-CARDINAL
two I-CARDINAL
most O
dashing O
, O
bold O
, O
and O
mischievous O
|
| O
boys O
at O
Eton B-ORG
during O
their B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
had O
formerly O
|
| O
been O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
Dunbar I-PERSON
and O
Louis B-PERSON
de I-PERSON
Cres- I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
pigny I-PERSON
, O
who O
astonished O
the O
weak O
minds O
of O
|
| O
masters O
and O
pupils O
, O
by O
the O
strange O
and O
start- O
|
| O
ling O
invention O
displayed O
in O
their O
exploits O
, O
as O
|
| O
well O
as O
by O
the O
ingenuity O
with O
which O
both O
got O
|
| O
safely O
out O
of O
every O
threatening O
predicament O
, O
|
| O
and O
the O
sly O
humour O
or O
cunning O
with O
which O
|
| O
they O
frequently O
shifted O
the O
disgrace O
, O
or O
even O
|
| O
the O
punishment O
, O
of O
their O
offences O
, O
on O
others O
|
| O
who O
deserved O
it O
less O
, O
or O
perhaps O
not O
at O
all O
. O
|
| O
Invariably O
at O
the O
head O
of O
every O
mad O
exploit O
, O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
19 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
or O
at O
the O
bottom O
of O
every O
secret O
design O
, O
how O
|
| O
they O
could O
possibly O
have O
eseaped O
being O
ex- O
|
| O
pelled O
was O
a O
frequent O
topic O
of O
subsequent O
|
| O
wonder O
among O
their O
contemporaries O
in O
the O
|
| O
classes O
  O
but O
their O
delight O
was O
to O
run O
as O
near O
|
| O
the O
wind O
as O
possible O
, O
and O
still O
to O
display O
their O
|
| O
skilful O
pilotage O
by O
baffling O
justice O
, O
and O
evading O
|
| O
the O
utmost O
rigour O
of O
the O
law O
, O
while O
always O
|
| O
ready O
rather O
to O
do O
harm O
than O
to O
do O
nothing O
. O
|
| O
When O
very O
young O
, O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
enterprising O
|
| O
friends O
, O
both O
since O
gazetted O
into O
the O
15th B-ORDINAL
|
| O
Light O
Huzzars O
, O
had O
shewn O
an O
early O
predilection O
|
| O
for O
military O
life O
, O
by O
frequently O
escaping O
to O
the O
|
| O
neighbouring O
barracks O
, O
assisted O
by O
a O
ladder O
|
| O
of O
rope O
on O
which O
they O
descended O
every O
night O
|
| O
from O
the O
windows O
. O
A O
gay O
joyous O
reception O
|
| O
invariably O
awaited O
these O
lively O
boys O
at O
the O
|
| O
mess O
- O
table O
, O
where O
they O
sung O
many O
a O
jovial O
|
| O
song O
, O
and O
cracked O
many O
a O
merry O
jest O
over O
|
| O
their O
claret O
, O
till O
, O
after O
some B-TIME
hours I-TIME
spent O
in O
|
| O
rapturous O
festivity O
, O
they O
stole O
silently O
back O
|
| O
within O
bounds O
, O
and O
were O
re O
- O
admitted O
at O
the O
|
| O
window O
, O
by O
their O
respective O
fags O
, O
who O
had O
re- O
|
| O
ceived O
orders O
, O
under O
pain O
of O
death O
, O
to O
keep O
|

| O
20 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
awake O
and O
answer O
their O
signals O
for O
the O
ladder O
|
| O
by O
instantly O
lowering O
it O
. O
The O
spirits O
of O
both O
|
| O
these O
young O
companions O
were O
more O
like O
the O
|
| O
effect O
of O
intoxication O
, O
than O
mere O
sober O
enjoy- O
|
| O
ment O
  O
and O
, O
on O
one B-CARDINAL
occasion O
, O
they O
set O
the O
|
| O
table O
in O
a O
roar O
, O
by O
having O
a O
rivalship O
which O
|
| O
would O
best O
imitate O
the O
gradual O
progress O
of O
|
| O
becoming O
tipsy O
, O
though O
drinking O
nothing O
but O
|
| O
cold O
water O
  O
in O
which O
exhibition O
they O
showed O
so O
|
| O
much O
talent O
for O
mimicry O
, O
taking O
off O
the O
sur- O
|
| O
rounding O
officers O
before O
their O
faces O
, O
and O
mak- O
|
| O
ing O
so O
many O
home O
- O
thrusts O
and O
personal O
re- O
|
| O
marks O
, O
that O
the O
scene O
was O
never O
afterwards O
|
| O
forgotten O
in O
the O
regiment O
. O
On O
another O
occa- O
|
| O
sion O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
caused O
himself O
to O
be O
placed O
|
| O
in O
a O
coffin O
, O
stolen O
from O
the O
undertakers O
, O
and O
|
| O
was O
carried O
through O
the O
barracks O
by O
his O
com- O
|
| O
panions O
, O
who O
made O
paper O
trumpets O
with O
which O
|
| O
they O
played O
the O
dead O
march O
in O
Saul B-PERSON
, O
while O
all O
|
| O
the O
sentries O
saluted O
as O
they O
passed O
. O
Such O
|
| O
juvenile O
exploits O
in O
the O
dawn O
of O
life O
were O
now O
|
| O
the O
subject O
of O
many O
a O
laughing O
reminiscence O
, O
|
| O
“ O
and O
had O
been O
followed O
by O
others O
on O
a O
more O
|
| O
extended O
scale O
and O
of O
more O
matured O
enter- O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
21 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
prise O
, O
at O
Mr O
Brownlow B-PERSON
’s O
, O
a O
private O
tutor O
, O
|
| O
where O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
men O
afterwards O
distin- O
|
| O
guished O
themselves O
in O
a O
way O
not O
easily O
to O
be O
|
| O
forgotten O
, O
causing O
their O
better O
disciplined O
|
| O
companions O
to O
wonder O
, O
though O
in O
very O
few O
in- O
|
| O
stances O
to O
admire O
. O
|

| O
In O
the O
favourite O
aristocratic O
achievements O
|
| O
of O
driving O
stage O
coaches O
, O
breaking O
lamps O
, O
|
| O
wringing O
off O
knockers O
, O
assaulting O
watchmen O
, O
|
| O
with O
other O
fistic O
and O
pugilistic O
exploits O
, O
they O
|
| O
were O
nearly O
unrivalled O
  O
and O
occasionally O
their O
|
| O
genius O
had O
soared O
into O
an O
extraordinary O
dis- O
|
| O
play O
of O
dexterity O
, O
in O
transposing O
the O
signs O
sus- O
|
| O
pended O
over O
shops O
, O
and O
in O
filehing O
silk O
hand- O
|
| O
kerchiefs O
from O
the O
pockets O
of O
their O
friends O
, O
|
| O
merely O
as O
amateurs O
, O
but O
still O
the O
deed O
was O
|
| O
done O
, O
and O
the O
laugh O
raised O
literally O
at O
the O
ex- O
|
| O
pense O
of O
the O
sufferer O
, O
as O
the O
plunder O
was O
re- O
|
| O
tained O
to O
be O
a O
future O
trophy O
of O
success O
. O
Each O
|
| O
successive O
stage O
of O
their O
youth O
, O
in O
short O
, O
sup- O
|
| O
plied O
an O
inexhaustible O
fund O
of O
standing O
jests O
|
| O
and O
lively O
anecdotes O
, O
the O
wit O
of O
which O
mainly O
|
| O
consisted O
in O
their O
mischief O
, O
while O
they O
betray- O
|
| O
ed O
an O
utter O
recklessness O
about O
the O
opinions O
or O
|

| O
22 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
the O
feelings O
of O
others O
, O
till O
at O
length O
the O
pati- O
|
| O
ence O
of O
their O
unfortunate O
private O
tutor O
was O
so O
|
| O
completely O
exhausted O
that O
he O
gave O
them O
a O
|
| O
secret O
hint O
to O
withdraw O
, O
which O
they O
accord- O
|
| O
ingly O
lost O
no O
time O
in O
preparing O
to O
do O
, O
but O
not O
|
| O
till O
they O
had O
enjoyed O
a O
very O
characteristic O
|
| O
revenge O
. O
When O
Mr O
Brownlow B-PERSON
had O
taken O
a O
|
| O
party O
of O
friends O
with O
him O
one B-TIME
evening I-TIME
to O
the O
|
| O
theatre O
, O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
suddenly O
discharged O
from O
|
| O
the O
gallery O
the O
whole O
contents O
of O
a O
prodigious O
|
| O
bag O
of O
flour O
, O
which O
powdered O
all O
the O
heads O
, O
|
| O
faces O
, O
and O
coats O
, O
in O
the O
pit O
, O
perfectly O
white O
, O
|
| O
and O
caused O
an O
uproar O
of O
anger O
and O
of O
irresis- O
|
| O
tible O
laughter O
throughout O
the O
house O
  O
and O
the O
|
| O
same O
evening O
Louis B-PERSON
de I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
as O
a O
fare- O
|
| O
well O
frolic O
, O
abstracted O
a O
stuffed O
bear O
from O
the O
|
| O
neighbouring O
hair O
- O
dresser O
’s O
, O
and O
having O
equip- O
|
| O
ped O
it O
in O
the O
costume O
of O
Mr O
Brownlow B-PERSON
, O
hung O
it O
|
| O
from O
the O
lamp O
- O
post O
, O
where O
a O
panic O
- O
struck O
crowd O
|
| O
was O
speedily O
assembled O
by O
the O
alarming O
report O
|
| O
that O
the O
reverend O
gentleman O
had O
committed O
|
| O
suicide O
. O
A O
strict O
investigation O
took O
place O
re- O
|
| O
specting O
the O
authors O
of O
these O
unpardonable O
|
| O
tricks O
, O
but O
, O
though O
suspicion O
fell O
at O
once O
upon O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
23 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
the O
real O
culprits O
, O
and O
the O
circumstantial O
evi- O
|
| O
dence O
against O
them O
seemed O
irresistibly O
strong O
, O
|
| O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
argued O
his O
own O
cause O
with O
so O
|
| O
much O
skill O
and O
vivaeity O
, O
while O
De B-ORG
Crespigny I-ORG
|
| O
looked O
so O
innocently O
unconscious O
of O
the O
whole O
|
| O
affair O
, O
that O
, O
with O
a O
silent O
frown O
from O
the B-TIME
mas- I-TIME
|
| I-TIME
ter I-TIME
, O
of O
stern O
reproof O
and O
suspicion O
, O
they O
were O
, O
|
| O
not O
honourably O
acquitted O
, O
but O
allowed O
to O
re- O
|
| O
turn O
home O
without O
any O
public O
mark O
of O
cen- O
|
| O
sure O
or O
disgrace O
  O
and O
soon O
after O
both O
joined O
|
| O
their O
regiment O
at O
Dublin B-GPE
. O
|

| O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
and O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
had O
but O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
companion O
whom O
they O
acknowledged O
as O
their O
|
| O
equal O
at O
Eton B-ORG
, O
in O
all O
the O
spirit O
, O
enterprise O
, O
and O
|
| O
vivacity O
of O
their O
characters O
, O
but O
who O
was O
, O
in O
a O
|
| O
thousand B-CARDINAL
other O
respects O
, O
their O
superior O
, O
for O
|
| O
seldom O
, O
indeed O
, O
has O
there O
been O
known O
, O
in O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
so O
young O
, O
a O
character O
of O
as O
much O
intensity O
, O
or O
|
| O
which O
displayed O
a O
combination O
so O
singular O
, O
of O
|
| O
superb O
talents O
, O
rare O
judgment O
, O
sound O
prin- O
|
| O
ciple O
, O
deep O
piety O
, O
and O
energetic O
feeling O
, O
as O
|
| O
in O
Richard B-PERSON
Granville I-PERSON
, O
an O
object O
of O
admira- O
|
| O
tion O
to O
all O
, O
and O
of O
envy O
to O
many O
  O
though O
|
| O
jealousy O
lost O
half B-CARDINAL
of O
its O
bitterness O
in O
asso- O
|

| O
24 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
ciation O
with O
one O
so O
eloquent O
and O
single O
- O
heart- O
|
| O
ed O
in O
conversation O
, O
so O
courteously O
amiable O
|
| O
and O
conciliatory O
in O
manner O
, O
and O
with O
so O
|
| O
fine O
a O
principle O
of O
tact O
, O
ready O
as B-TIME
far I-TIME
as I-TIME
pos- I-TIME
|
| O
sible O
to O
enhance O
the O
pleasures O
, O
to O
palliate O
the O
|
| O
faults O
, O
and O
to O
share O
the O
sorrows O
of O
all O
his O
com- O
|
| O
panions O
. O
Cultivated O
in O
all O
that O
could O
adorn O
|
| O
the O
heart O
, O
as O
well O
as O
the O
head O
, O
in O
whatever O
|
| O
was O
amiable O
, O
high O
- O
spirited O
, O
and O
generous O
, O
Rich- O
|
| O
ard O
Granville O
had O
but O
to O
follow O
the O
impulse O
of O
|
| O
natural O
feeling O
as O
well O
as O
of O
principle O
, O
and O
he O
|
| O
out O
- O
did O
the O
very O
wishes O
of O
his O
friends O
, O
while O
no O
|
| O
one O
excelled O
him O
in O
all O
the O
manly O
exercises O
|
| O
suited O
to O
his O
early B-DATE
years I-DATE
. O
His O
countenance O
|
| O
was O
illuminated O
with O
an O
expression O
of O
intellec- O
|
| O
tual O
energy O
, O
at O
times O
almost O
sublime O
, O
while O
|
| O
there O
was O
a O
living O
grace O
and O
amiability O
in O
his O
|
| O
manner O
irresistibly O
attractive O
. O
Brave O
, O
liberal O
, O
|
| O
and O
resolute O
, O
he O
entered O
with O
eagerness O
into O
|
| O
all O
the O
inoffensive O
recreations O
of O
his O
compa- O
|
| O
nions O
, O
and O
no O
one O
excelled O
him O
in O
riding O
, O
|
| O
fencing O
, O
and O
cricket O
, O
while O
he O
was O
the O
best O
|
| O
shot O
in O
his O
own O
county O
  O
but O
he O
firmly O
de- O
|

| O
clined O
ever O
to O
squander O
his O
time O
or O
money O
on O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
25 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
any O
games O
of O
chance O
, O
cards O
, O
billiards O
, O
or O
gam- O
|
| O
bling O
in O
any O
form O
. O
While O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
’s O
bet- O
|
| O
ting O
- O
book O
was O
from O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
a O
model O
of O
skill O
, O
|
| O
in O
hedging O
bets O
, O
and O
all O
the O
mancuvres O
of O
|
| O
jockey O
- O
ology O
, O
young O
Granville B-PERSON
said O
all O
that O
|
| O
eloquence O
and O
affection O
could O
dictate O
, O
to O
point O
|
| O
out O
how O
dangerous O
and O
dishonourable O
was O
the O
|
| O
course O
on O
which O
he O
seemed O
about O
to O
enter O
, O
|
| O
but O
in O
vain O
, O
for O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
finished O
the O
dis- O
|
| O
cussion O
by O
offering O
to O
bet O
him O
L.5 B-LOC
he O
would O
|
| O
not O
be O
ruined O
in O
less B-DATE
than I-DATE
ten I-DATE
years I-DATE
. O
“ O
I O
have O
|
| O
a O
fortune O
and O
constitution O
which O
will O
last O
me O
|
| O
till O
thirty B-DATE
, O
” O
said O
the O
young O
baronet O
  O
“ O
and O
I O
|
| O
do O
not O
wish O
to O
live O
a O
day O
longer O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Tt O
is O
easy O
, O
” O
said O
Prince B-PERSON
Eugene I-PERSON
, O
“ O
to O
be O
|
| O
modest O
when O
one O
is O
successful O
, O
but O
it O
is O
difficult O
|
| O
not O
to O
be O
envied O
. O
” O
While O
the O
very O
presence O
of O
|
| O
young O
Granville B-GPE
in O
the O
room O
with O
’ O
his O
riotous O
|
| O
young O
associates O
, O
seemed O
as O
if O
it O
held O
up O
a O
|
| O
glass O
to O
their O
mind O
’s O
eye O
, O
testifying O
the O
folly O
|
| O
and O
evil O
of O
their O
course O
, O
yet O
Richard B-PERSON
Granville I-PERSON
|
| O
abhorred O
display O
, O
while O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
and O
De B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
frequently O
declared O
he O
was O
“ O
too O
|

| O
clever O
and O
too O
good O
for O
them O
  O
” O
and O
unavoid- O
|
| O
VoL B-CARDINAL
, O
1 B-CARDINAL
. O
B O
|

| O
26 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
able O
circumstances O
afterwards O
combined O
to O
|
| O
estrange O
the O
young O
men O
still O
more O
. O
A O
law- O
|
| O
suit O
had O
been O
going O
on O
almost O
since O
the O
period O
|
| O
of O
their O
birth O
, O
conducted O
in O
an O
amicable O
way O
|
| O
by O
their O
guardians O
, O
in O
which O
the O
interests O
of O
|
| O
all B-CARDINAL
three I-CARDINAL
were O
so O
deeply O
concerned O
, O
and O
the O
|
| O
ease O
so O
exceedingly O
complicated O
, O
that O
years B-DATE
|
| O
passed O
on O
, O
during O
which O
the O
youths O
had O
all O
|
| O
grown O
to O
manhood O
, O
and O
the O
case O
remained O
|
| O
still O
undecided O
  O
while O
the O
one B-CARDINAL
- O
sided O
view O
|
| O
which O
was O
given O
to O
Dunbar B-ORG
and O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
|
| O
on O
the O
subject O
caused O
in O
them O
an O
angry O
feel- O
|
| O
ing O
of O
rancour O
and O
hostility O
against O
their O
ami- O
|
| O
able O
and O
high O
- O
minded O
young O
relative O
, O
who O
was O
|
| O
so O
enthusiastically O
desirous O
to O
enter O
the O
Eng- O
|
| O
lish O
church O
, O
and O
devote O
himself O
to O
those O
sacred O
|
| O
duties O
, O
that O
he O
scarcely O
wished O
a O
favourable O
|
| O
decree O
, O
which O
would O
prevent O
the O
necessity O
for O
|
| O
his O
pursuing O
a O
profession O
at O
all O
. O
|

| O
A O
Scotch O
law O
- O
suit O
may O
be O
compared O
to O
a O
|
| O
game O
at O
battle B-ORG
- I-ORG
dore I-ORG
between O
the O
tribunals O
|
| O
of O
England B-GPE
and O
Scotland B-GPE
, O
while O
the O
gaping O
|
| O
client O
sees O
the O
shuttle O
- O
cock O
for O
ever O
flying O
|
| O
over O
his O
head O
, O
higher O
and O
higher O
out O
of O
reach O
, O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
27 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
and O
sent O
backwards O
and O
forwards O
with O
cease- O
|
| O
less O
diligence O
, O
but O
no O
apparent O
progress O
  O
or O
|
| O
it O
is O
like O
a O
kitten O
playing O
with O
a O
ball O
of O
|
| O
worsted O
, O
which O
is O
allowed O
to O
come O
often O
ap- O
|
| O
parently O
within O
her O
grasp O
, O
and O
is O
then O
, O
when O
|
| O
she O
least O
expects O
, O
twitched O
away O
farther O
than O
|
| O
before O
. O
The O
Granville B-PERSON
case O
had O
been O
decided O
|
| O
by O
the B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
Session I-ORG
, O
against O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
cou- O
|
| O
sins O
, O
Dunbar B-PERSON
and O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
but O
being O
ap- O
|
| O
pealed O
to O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Lords I-ORG
, O
was O
recom- O
|
| O
mended O
for O
consideration O
, O
re O
- O
argued O
, O
re O
- O
consi- O
|
| O
dered O
, O
and O
nearly O
reversed O
, O
while O
replies O
and O
|
| O
duplies O
, O
remits O
and O
re O
- O
revisals O
, O
commissions O
of O
|
| O
inquiry O
, O
and O
new O
cases O
, O
followed O
each O
other O
in O
|
| O
ceaseless O
succession O
, O
and O
many.of B-CARDINAL
the O
lawyers O
|
| O
who O
were O
young O
men O
when O
the O
case O
began O
, O
|
| O
grew O
grey O
in O
the O
service O
, O
while O
yet O
it O
remained O
|
| O
in O
suspense O
. O
A O
grand O
- O
uncle O
of O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
’s O
|
| O
had O
fifty B-DATE
years I-DATE
before O
bought O
an O
estate O
of O
|
| O
L.12,000 O
a B-DATE
- I-DATE
year I-DATE
from O
the O
Marquis B-PERSON
of O
Doncas- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ter I-PERSON
, O
to O
whom O
young O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
was O
now O
|
| O
heir O
- O
presumptive O
  O
but O
Mr O
Dunbar B-PERSON
having O
, O
it O
|
| O
was O
conjectured O
, O
entertained O
some O
suspicion O
|
| O
that O
the O
title O
- O
deeds O
were O
not O
perfectly O
valid O
, O
|

| O
28 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
as O
an O
entail O
had O
been O
discovered O
afterwards O
, O
|
| O
by O
which O
it O
was O
generally O
thought O
that O
the O
|
| O
land O
must O
be O
restored O
to O
the O
original O
owner O
, O
|
| O
he O
hastily O
and O
most O
unfairly O
sold O
the O
property O
|
| O
to O
the O
late O
Mr O
Granville B-PERSON
for O
L.350,000 O
, O
and O
|
| O
dying O
intestate O
, O
after O
having O
lost O
nearly O
the O
|
| O
whole O
sum O
in O
a O
mining O
speculation O
, O
it O
could O
|
| O
not O
be O
proved O
whether O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
’s O
father O
|
| O
had O
acted O
as O
executor O
for O
the O
deceased O
or O
not O
, O
|
| O
so O
as O
to O
render O
himself O
responsible O
for O
his O
|
| O
debts O
, O
and O
liable O
to O
refund O
the O
sum O
paid O
by O
|
| O
Mr O
Granville B-PERSON
. O
Thus O
, O
whether O
the O
entail O
held O
|
| O
good O
, O
and O
carried O
the O
estate O
back O
to O
Lord B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
, O
or O
whether O
it O
had O
been O
legally O
|
| O
broken O
, O
so O
as O
to O
entitle O
the O
Granville B-PERSON
family O
|
| O
to O
keep O
it O
, O
or O
whether O
, O
if O
it O
were O
refunded O
, O
the O
|
| O
price O
could O
be O
claimed O
from O
the O
heirs O
of O
Mr O
|
| O
Dunbar B-PERSON
, O
still O
continued O
a O
mystery O
never O
ap- O
|
| O
parently O
to O
be O
solved O
. O
|

| O
For O
many O
generations O
past O
, O
the O
ancient O
|
| O
Marquisate B-ORG
of O
Doncaster O
had O
been O
inherited O
|
| O
by O
a O
succession O
of O
only O
sons O
, O
all O
strict O
Papists O
, O
|
| O
who O
had O
each O
in O
his O
turn O
been O
reckoned O
by O
|
| O
the O
next O
heirs O
exceedingly O
sickly O
and O
unpro- O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
29 B-CARDINAL
) O
|

| O
© O
mising O
, O
but O
still O
the O
wonder O
grew O
, O
for O
not O
one O
|

| O
had O
ever O
died O
, O
till O
he O
left O
a O
substitute O
in O
regu- O
|
| O
lar O
rotation O
, O
to O
supply O
the O
vacaney O
which O
he O
|
| O
created O
himself O
  O
and O
a O
long O
train O
of O
minorities O
|
| O
in O
the O
family O
had O
caused O
the O
accumulation O
of O
|
| O
wealth O
and O
property O
to O
be O
enormous O
, O
when O
|
| O
the O
present O
proprietor O
succeeded O
, O
fifty B-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| O
before O
our O
story O
commences O
. O
Nothing O
could O
|
| O
exceed O
his O
own O
astonishment O
at O
the O
unembar- O
|
| O
rassed O
magnificence O
of O
the O
fortune O
, O
of O
which O
|
| O
he O
most O
unexpectedly O
found O
himself O
in O
pos- O
|
| O
session O
, O
as O
his O
father O
had O
been O
in O
the O
habit O
: O
|
| O
of O
concealing O
the O
amount O
of O
liis O
own O
income O
, O
|
| O
and O
allowing O
his O
heir O
rather O
less O
than O
nothing O
, O
|
| O
saying O
, O
that O
as O
he O
himself O
never O
had O
anything O
|
| O
to O
eat O
till O
he O
had O
no O
teeth O
to O
eat O
with O
, O
he O
was O
|
| O
resolved O
that O
his O
successor O
should O
be O
similarly O
|
| O
treated O
. O
In O
pursuance O
of O
this O
plan O
, O
the O
old O
|
| O
nobleman O
even O
on O
his O
death O
- O
bed O
, O
had O
actually O
|
| O
expired O
with O
a O
practical O
joke O
on O
his O
lips O
. O
He O
|
| O
sent O
for O
his O
son O
, O
gravely O
told O
him O
that O
with O
|
| O
debts O
, O
mortgages O
, O
and O
settlements O
, O
the O
very O
|
| O
encumbered O
estate O
he O
was O
about O
to O
inherit O
|
| O
would O
scarcely O
pay O
its O
own O
expenses O
, O
and O
re- O
|

| O
30 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
commended O
him O
to O
live O
in O
future O
with O
the O
|
| O
most O
penurious O
economy O
. O
When O
the O
will O
was O
|
| O
opened O
, O
finding O
to O
his O
unutterable O
joy O
, O
that O
he O
|
| O
had O
merely O
been O
played O
upon O
by O
the O
old O
hu- O
|
| O
morist O
, O
who O
in O
reality O
left O
him O
L.40,000 O
per O
an- O
|
| O
num O
clear O
, O
so O
great O
was O
Lord O
Doneaster B-PERSON
’s O
sur- O
|
| O
prise O
, O
that O
he O
declared O
his O
good O
fortune O
at O
the O
|
| O
time O
to O
be O
“ O
almost O
incredible O
  O
” O
and O
it O
might O
|
| O
have O
been O
supposed O
, O
that O
he O
never O
afterwards O
|
| O
completely O
believed O
it O
, O
as O
his O
personal O
expenses O
|
| O
were O
always O
in O
a O
style O
more O
suited O
to O
the O
old O
|
| O
Lord O
’s O
threat O
than O
his O
performance O
, O
and O
he O
|
| O
became O
a O
fresh O
instance O
of O
what O
may O
be O
so O
of- O
|
| O
ten B-CARDINAL
remarked O
, O
that O
the O
most O
extravagant O
heirs O
|
| O
in O
expectancy O
become O
the O
most O
avaricious O
in O
|
| O
possession O
. O
|

| O
There O
was O
one B-CARDINAL
singular O
peculiarity O
in O
the O
|
| O
settlements O
of O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
’s I-PERSON
family O
, O
that O
|
| O
so O
long O
as O
he O
had O
no O
son O
, O
or O
if O
his O
son O
at O
|
| O
twenty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
one I-CARDINAL
declared O
himself O
a O
Protestant B-NORP
, O
he O
|
| O
had O
the O
power O
of O
selling O
or O
bequeathing O
the O
|
| O
estates O
according O
to O
his O
own O
pleasure O
or O
ca- O
|
| O
price O
  O
and O
the O
ancestor O
who O
had O
inserted O
this O
|
| O
clause O
in O
his O
deed O
of O
entail O
, O
made O
his O
intention O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
31 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
evident O
, O
that O
the O
succession O
should O
go O
to O
the O
|
| O
Roman B-ORG
Catholic I-ORG
Chureh I-ORG
, O
rather O
than O
to O
a O
Pro- O
|
| O
testant O
heir O
  O
but O
the O
present O
peer O
had O
taken O
|
| O
advantage O
, O
on O
so O
large O
a O
scale O
, O
of O
his O
own O
|
| O
childless O
privilege O
, O
to O
sell O
the O
family O
estates O
, O
|
| O
that O
his O
two B-CARDINAL
deceased O
sisters O
, O
Lady O
Charlotte B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
De I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
and O
Lady O
Caroline B-PERSON
Smytheson I-PERSON
, O
|
| O
used O
secretly O
to O
complain O
, O
that O
little O
would O
be O
|
| O
left O
for O
their O
children O
, O
if O
he O
persevered O
in O
|
| O
turning O
every O
acre O
into O
gold O
  O
yet O
no O
one O
ever O
|
| O
could O
guess O
how O
the O
large O
sums O
were O
squan- O
|
| O
dered O
or O
melted O
away O
, O
which O
the O
old O
Marquis B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
continually O
raising O
, O
unless O
they O
went O
, O
|
| O
as O
was O
strongly O
suspected O
, O
in O
the O
form O
of O
|
| O
“ O
secret O
service O
money O
, O
” O
among O
the O
priests O
by O
|
| O
whom O
he O
was O
surrounded O
. O
|

| O
Nobody O
had O
a O
better O
right O
to O
be O
eccentric O
|
| O
than O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
! I-PERSON
— O
old O
, O
rich O
, O
unmarried O
, O
|
| O
and O
originally O
educated O
at O
home,—a B-ORG
misfor- O
|
| O
tune O
sufficient O
in O
itself O
to O
engender O
so O
many O
|
| O
peculiarities O
, O
as O
to O
render O
a O
man O
unfit O
for O
so- O
|
| O
ciety O
ever O
afterwards O
. O
The O
aged O
peer O
was O
|
| O
shy O
, O
proud O
, O
and O
arbitrary O
beyond O
all O
con- O
|
| O
ception O
, O
avaricious O
about O
trifles O
, O
yet O
lavish O
to O
|

| O
32 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
excess O
on O
great O
occasions O
, O
suspicious O
of O
all O
|
| O
men O
’s O
motives O
and O
intentions O
, O
and O
yet O
con- O
|
| O
fiding O
to O
the O
last O
extreme O
of O
weakness O
, O
in O
the O
|
| O
Abbé B-PERSON
Mordaunt I-PERSON
, O
his O
confessor O
, O
despising O
all O
|
| O
men O
, O
and O
yet O
anxious O
beyond O
measure O
for O
the O
|
| O
world O
’s O
good O
opinion O
, O
addicted O
to O
the O
very O
|
| O
worst O
female O
society O
, O
when O
he O
might O
have O
|
| O
enjoyed O
the O
best O
, O
hating O
company O
, O
and O
yet O
|
| O
sometimes O
plunging O
into O
it O
, O
when O
and O
where O
|
| O
he O
was O
least O
expected O
, O
jealous O
to O
excess O
of O
|
| O
his O
next O
heir O
, O
Louis B-PERSON
De I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
whom O
he O
|
| O
enslaved O
to O
his O
caprices O
, O
as O
if O
even O
his O
exist- O
|
| O
ence O
were O
to O
be O
given O
or O
withheld O
at O
his O
|
| O
option O
, O
yet O
sometimes O
whimsically O
cordial O
in O
|
| O
his O
manner O
to O
him O
, O
though O
ready O
to O
take O
fire O
|
| O
in O
an O
instant O
if O
his O
condescension O
led O
the O
live- O
|
| O
ly O
youth O
into O
the O
slightest O
approach O
towards O
|
| O
confidence O
or O
familiarity O
. O
|

| O
Mr O
Howard B-PERSON
Smytheson I-PERSON
, O
the O
wealthy O
bro- O
|
| O
ther O
- O
in O
- O
law O
of O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
, O
having O
pur- O
|
| O
chased O
most O
of O
the O
De B-ORG
Crespigny I-ORG
estates O
, O
as O
|
| O
acre O
after O
acre O
, O
farm O
after O
farm O
, O
and O
house O
|
| O
after O
house O
, O
came O
successively O
into O
the O
mar- O
|
| O
ket O
, O
bequeathed O
them O
on O
his O
decease O
to O
an O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
33 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
only O
daughter O
then O
an O
infant O
, O
and O
it O
became O
|
| O
a O
favourite O
day O
- O
dream O
with O
the O
old O
peer O
, O
that O
|
| O
his O
nephew O
and O
niece B-PERSON
should O
be O
educated O
for O
|
| O
each O
other O
, O
while O
to O
this O
end O
he O
tried O
his O
ut- O
|
| O
most O
power O
of O
conciliation O
with O
the B-ORG
maiden I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
sister I-ORG
of O
Mr O
Howard B-PERSON
Smytheson I-PERSON
, O
to O
whose O
|
| O
care O
the O
young O
heiress O
had O
been O
consigned O
, O
|
| O
hoping O
that O
thus O
all O
the O
amputated O
limbs O
of O
|
| O
his O
vast O
property O
might O
yet O
be O
reunited O
in O
|
| O
their O
pristine O
magnitude O
, O
to O
which O
very O
de- O
|
| O
sirable O
end O
he O
thenceforth O
directed O
his O
whole O
|
| O
conversations O
with O
young O
De B-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
, O
to O
|
| O
whom O
he O
more O
than O
hinted O
that O
, O
unless O
their O
|
| O
will O
were O
the O
same O
about O
this O
marriage O
, O
his O
|
| O
own O
will O
after O
death O
would O
be O
found O
very O
dif- O
|
| O
ferent O
from O
what O
his O
nephew O
probably O
antici- O
|
| O
pated O
and O
wished O
. O
|

| O
The O
private O
vices O
of O
Lord B-ORG
Doncaster I-ORG
had O
|
| O
been O
so O
very O
private O
, O
that O
though O
much O
was O
|
| O
suspected O
, O
little O
could O
be O
known O
  O
yet O
, O
while O
he O
|
| O
had O
few O
visible O
or O
personal O
expenses O
, O
and O
no O
|
| O
imaginable O
outlet O
for O
his O
fortune O
, O
he O
invariably O
|
| O
spent O
all O
his O
income O
, O
and O
considerably O
more O
, O
|
| O
being O
one O
of O
those O
personages O
occasionally O
seen O
|

| O
34 B-CARDINAL
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
who O
excite O
the O
wonder O
and O
speculation O
of O
rela- O
|
| O
tions O
and O
neighbours O
, O
by O
unaccountably O
frit- O
|
| O
tering O
away O
fortunes O
of O
almost O
royal O
splendour O
, O
|
| O
without O
any O
appearance O
of O
royal O
luxury O
or O
royal O
|
| O
liberality O
. O
Wearied B-PERSON
of O
the O
world O
, O
in O
which O
he O
|
| O
had O
nothing O
more O
to O
desire O
, O
and O
of O
himself O
, O
as O
|
| O
he O
had O
nothing O
to O
think O
of O
or O
to O
do,—bored O
in O
|
| O
short O
with O
the O
want O
of O
a O
want O
, O
Lord O
Doncas- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ter I-PERSON
’s O
life O
was O
indeed O
a O
mere O
heartless O
pageant O
|
| O
of O
mean O
ostentation O
and O
fretful O
pride O
, O
sternly O
|
| O
insulated O
in O
a O
state O
of O
solitary O
old O
- O
bachelor O
|
| O
despotism O
, O
and O
absorbed O
in O
himself O
to O
a O
degree O
|
| O
which O
no O
ordinary O
mind O
could O
conceive O
or O
|
| O
comprehend O
. O
Encumbered O
with O
so O
many O
un- O
|
| O
occupied O
hours B-TIME
, O
it O
was O
a O
subject O
of O
as O
much O
|
| O
wonder O
how O
he O
disposed O
of O
his O
superfluous O
|
| O
time O
, O
as O
of O
his O
superfluous O
fortune O
  O
but O
he O
set- O
|
| O
tled O
that O
question O
, O
by O
remarking O
one B-DATE
day I-DATE
to O
|
| O
his O
nephew O
, O
that O
“ O
the O
great O
business O
of O
life O
|
| O
is O
, O
to O
shuffle O
through O
the B-DATE
day I-DATE
anyhow O
till O
din- O
|
| O
ner O
time O
. O
” O
Like O
all O
parsimonious O
men O
, O
Lord B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
could O
not O
endure O
to O
hear O
any O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
else O
reckoned O
affluent O
, O
and O
Louis B-PERSON
De I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
|
| O
knew O
that O
a O
certain O
receipt O
for O
irritating O
him O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
35 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
was O
, O
to O
over O
- O
estimate O
everybody O
's O
income O
, O
con- O
|
| O
sequently O
he O
amused O
himself O
occasionally O
by O
|
| O
audibly O
giving O
out O
Lord O
Towercliffe B-PERSON
’s O
fortune O
|
| O
to O
be O
L.15,000 B-PERSON
a B-DATE
- I-DATE
year I-DATE
, O
and O
estimating O
his O
friend O
|
| O
Sir O
Patrick B-PERSON
Dunbar I-PERSON
’s O
rent O
- O
roll O
at O
a O
clear O
sum O
|
| O
of O
L.20,000 O
per O
annum O
, O
while O
he O
slyly O
watched O
|
| O
his O
unele O
’s O
rising O
choler O
, O
and O
patiently O
heard O
, O
|
| O
for O
the O
fiftieth B-ORDINAL
time O
, O
an O
elaborate O
explanation O
, O
|
| O
that O
it O
was O
impossible O
, O
and O
a O
sober O
calculation O
, O
|
| O
which O
reduced O
both O
the O
offending O
parties O
almost O
|
| O
to O
beggary O
. O
|

| O
In O
the B-DATE
month I-DATE
of I-DATE
August I-DATE
, O
as O
regularly O
as O
time O
|
| O
revolved O
, O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
delighted O
to O
read O
in O
|
| O
the O
newspapers O
, O
his O
own O
pompous O
advertise- O
|
| O
ment O
, O
the O
only O
original O
composition O
he O
was O
ever O
|
| O
known O
to O
attempt O
, O
in O
which O
he O
prohibited O
|
| O
poachers O
and O
strangers O
from O
shooting O
on O
his O
|
| O
moors O
in O
Argyleshire B-GPE
, O
Mid O
- O
Lothian O
, O
Yorkshire B-GPE
, O
|
| O
Galloway B-ORG
, I-ORG
Cromarty I-ORG
, O
and O
Caithness B-ORG
, O
but O
except O
|
| O
the O
annual B-DATE
appearance O
of O
this O
spirited O
mani- O
|
| O
festo O
, O
no O
publie O
evidence O
ever O
came O
forth O
of O
|
| O
that O
extraordinary O
wealth O
which O
property O
so O
|
| O
extensive O
must O
be O
supposed O
to O
produce O
. O
- O
No O
|
| O
charitable O
donations O
bore O
witness O
to O
Lord O
Don- O
|

| O
386 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
caster O
’s O
liberality,—no O
country O
objects O
were O
|
| O
encouraged O
by O
his O
public O
spirit,—and O
the O
mo- O
|
| O
numents O
daily B-DATE
arising O
in O
memory O
of O
departed O
|
| O
merit O
, O
made O
a O
vain O
appeal O
for O
his O
pecuniary O
|
| O
tribute O
of O
respect O
and O
regret O
, O
for O
Lord O
Doncas- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ter I-PERSON
neither O
respected O
nor O
regretted O
any O
man O
. O
|

| O
It O
was O
an O
often O
- O
repeated O
axiom O
of O
Lord O
Don- O
|
| O
caster O
’s O
, O
that O
every O
man O
cheats O
or O
is O
cheated O
  O
|
| O
but O
in O
one B-CARDINAL
instance O
, O
and O
one O
only O
, O
his O
Lordship B-ORG
|
| O
had O
shown O
apparently O
some O
kind O
feeling O
, O
or O
|
| O
rather O
perhaps O
he O
might O
be O
said O
to O
have O
exhi- O
|
| O
bited O
a O
capricious O
freak O
of O
benevolence O
, O
though O
|
| O
the O
result O
had O
been O
such O
as O
to O
afford O
him O
an O
|
| O
excuse O
ever O
afterwards O
for O
not O
again O
attempt- O
|
| O
ing O
a O
single O
act O
of O
gratuitous O
liberality O
. O
|

| O
The O
nearest O
relative O
to O
his O
ancient O
family O
, O
af- O
|
| O
ter O
Louis B-PERSON
De I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
and O
Miss O
Howard B-PERSON
, O
was O
|
| O
Mrs B-PERSON
Anstruther I-PERSON
, O
a O
distant O
cousin O
, O
who O
, O
after O
|
| O
making O
a O
low O
and O
almost O
disgraceful O
marriage O
, O
|
| O
had O
suddenly O
died O
, O
it O
was O
believed O
by O
her O
own O
|
| O
hands O
, O
thus O
consigning O
her O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
ehildren O
|
| O
to O
helpless O
, O
and O
apparently O
hopeless O
poverty O
, O
|
| O
till O
at O
length O
they O
were O
very O
unwillingly O
invited O
, O
|
| O
or O
rather O
permitted O
to O
become O
residents O
in O
an O
|

| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS O
. O
37 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
almost O
menial O
capacity O
at O
Beanjolie B-FAC
Castle I-FAC
, O
in O
|
| O
Yorkshire B-GPE
, O
where O
, O
as O
they O
could O
neither O
be O
|
| O
drowned O
like O
kittens O
, O
nor O
shot O
like O
puppy O
- O
dogs O
, O
|
| O
the O
Marquis B-PERSON
caused O
them O
to O
be O
treated O
like O
|
| O
the O
“ O
whipping O
boys O
” O
in O
Charles B-PERSON
the O
First B-ORDINAL
’s O
|
| O
time,—sometimes O
employed O
as O
playmates O
to O
|
| O
amuse O
his O
nephew O
and O
niece O
during O
their O
holi- O
|
| O
day O
visits O
to O
his O
residence O
, O
but O
more O
frequently O
|
| O
treated O
in O
a O
sort O
of O
.mongrel O
- O
way O
between O
de- O
|
| O
pendents O
and O
slaves O
by O
, O
the O
heartless O
and O
|
| O
tyrannical O
old O
peer O
, O
who O
considered O
them O
as O
|
| O
mere O
poachers O
on O
the O
preserve O
of O
his O
family O
|
| O
honours O
, O
having O
forced O
their O
way O
into O
exist- O
|
| O
ence O
by O
some O
untoward O
accident O
, O
and O
become O
|
| O
absolute O
blots O
in O
the O
creation O
, O
liable O
to O
be O
|
| O
suspected O
, O
and O
even O
accused O
to O
their O
faces O
of O
|
| O
every O
low O
and O
vicious O
propensity O
, O
in O
conse- O
|
| O
quence O
of O
which O
, O
from O
an O
early O
age O
, O
he O
destroy- O
|
| O
ed O
their O
self O
- O
respect O
, O
and O
irritated O
their O
evil O
|
| O
passions O
by O
the O
most O
rash O
and O
unfounded O
|
| O
aspersions,—theft O
, O
swindling O
, O
lying O
, O
and O
glut- O
|
| O
tony O
, O
were O
among O
the O
principal O
counts O
in O
his O
|
| O
Lordship B-ORG
’s O
indictment O
, O
when O
he O
sometimes O
|
| O
vented O
a O
paroxysm O
of O
ill O
- O
humour O
on O
these O
his O
|

| O
38 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|

| O
unhappy O
dependents O
  O
and O
many O
a O
time O
the O
|
| O
tears O
of O
Mary B-PERSON
Anstruther I-PERSON
, O
and O
the O
flashing O
eye O
|
| O
of O
her O
brother O
Ernest B-PERSON
, O
bore O
witness O
to O
the O
|
| O
anger O
and O
grief O
with O
which O
they O
listened O
to O
|
| O
his O
bitter O
and O
often O
unmerited O
upbraidings O
. O
|
| O
At O
times O
, O
however O
, O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
found O
it O
|
| O
convenient O
for O
his O
own O
private O
purposes O
to O
pa- O
|
| O
tronize O
the O
Anstruthers B-ORG
, O
and O
threatened O
, O
in O
the O
|
| O
hearing O
of O
all O
his O
young O
relatives O
, O
that O
if O
Louis B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
De I-PERSON
Crespigny I-PERSON
’s O
conduct O
did O
not O
in O
all O
respects O
|
| O
satisfy O
him O
, O
an O
heir O
more O
subservient O
to O
his O
|
| O
wishes O
might O
be O
found O
, O
and O
though O
the O
culprit O
|
| O
must O
be O
his O
nephew O
, O
he O
need O
not O
be O
his O
succes- O
|
| O
sor O
, O
while O
the O
glance O
of O
his O
eye O
towards O
Ernest B-PERSON
|
| O
aroused O
hopes O
, O
wishes O
, O
and O
even O
expectations O
|
| O
of O
the O
wildest O
extravagance O
, O
which O
were O
then O
|
| O
confirmed O
for O
a O
time O
by O
his O
being O
promoted O
|
| O
to O
temporary O
attention O
and O
consideration O
, O
not O
|
| O
only O
displayed O
ostentatiously O
by O
their O
caprici- O
|
| O
ous O
patron O
, O
but O
extending O
to O
the O
increased O
re- O
|
| O
spect O
and O
observance O
of O
the O
servants O
, O
the O
|
| O
thermometer O
of O
whose O
obedience O
rose O
and O
fell O
|
| O
according O
as O
the O
sunshine O
of O
Lord B-PERSON
Doncaster I-PERSON
’s I-PERSON
|
| O
favour O
shone O
upon O
his O
young O
relative O
or O
not O
  O
|

| O
\ O
|
| O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
39 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
yet O
brief O
as O
these O
periods O
of O
increased O
import- O
|
| O
ance O
had O
always O
been O
, O
they O
made O
an O
indelible O
|
| O
impression O
on O
the O
young O
and O
ambitious O
minds O
|
| O
of O
those O
usually O
neglected O
children O
. O
“ O
The O
|
| O
child O
becomes O
a O
boy O
, O
the O
boy O
a O
youth O
, O
and O
|
| O
then O
the O
game O
of O
life O
begins O
in O
earnest O
. O
” O
|

| O
Without O
education O
or O
principle O
, O
and O
with O
|
| O
no O
friend O
on O
the O
wide O
earth O
to O
confide O
in O
or O
to O
|
| O
consult O
, O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
Anstruthers B-ORG
, O
like O
weeds O
|
| O
that O
will O
yet O
flourish O
though O
trampled O
upon O
, O
|
| O
grew O
up O
Vigorous O
in O
body O
, O
and O
enthusiastically O
|
| O
as O
well O
as O
devotedly O
attached O
to O
each O
other O
, O
|
| O
with O
a O
depth O
and O
power O
of O
affection O
which O
ap- O
|
| O
peared O
, O
before O
long O
, O
the O
only O
redeeming O
qua- B-CARDINAL
|
| O
lity O
in O
characters O
wherein O
strong O
passions O
and O
|
| O
weak O
principles O
promised O
little O
, O
and O
threat- O
|
| O
ened O
much O
, O
to O
all O
with O
whom O
they O
might O
|
| O
hereafter O
become O
associated O
. O
|

| O
The O
resemblance O
between O
them O
was O
as O
re- O
|
| O
markable O
as O
their O
attachment O
, O
both O
having O
|
| O
dark O
Italian B-NORP
- O
looking O
countenances O
, O
of O
remark- O
|
| O
able O
symmetry O
, O
with O
a O
singularly O
excitable O
and O
|
| O
determined O
expression O
in O
their O
large O
lustrous O
|
| O
eyes O
, O
while O
it O
was O
remarkable O
that O
neither O
|

| O
40 O
MODERN O
FLIRTATIONS B-ORG
. O
|
