ty O
of O
California B-GPE
|
| O
ern O
Regional B-ORG
|
| O
ary O
Facility O
|

| O
cl O
. O
' O
|
| O
i--- O
|
| O
rerr O
|
| O
I1 O
|
| O
T O
|
| O
g O
|
| O
f/- O
|


| O
L O
.. O
- O
. O
|
| O
L- O
|
| O
s O
- O
hI O
|
| O
.---L O
|
| O
4 B-CARDINAL
= O
x- O
|
| O
k- B-ORG
|
| O
h O
|
| O
- O
|
| O
. O
|
| O
" O
|

| O
. O
|
| O
rA O
|

| O
- O
|
| O
i O
|
| O
. O
|
| O
t. O
|

| O
o O
] O
|

| O
1 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
/ O
|
| O
1e B-CARDINAL
- O
h O
|
| O
' O
5 B-CARDINAL
t O
|

| O
. O
. O
|
| O
. O
' O
' O
l O
|
 | O
A. O
|
| O
, O
|
| O
-- O
f O
|
| O
. O
, O
|
| O
IU O
- O
aII O
|
| O
s O
- O
rn O
|
| O
: O
|
| O
I O
|
 | O
.. O
- O
|

| O
3- O
|
| O
  O
.s O
. O
  O
|
 
| O
1 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
i.4-.- O
|
| O
, O
|
| O
, O
|
 | O
: O
|
| O
. O
|
 | O
- O
, O
|

| O
o O
|
| O
( O
|
| O
. O
Y O
|
| O
  O
s O
|

| O
i O
|
| O
.7- O
|
| O
7 B-PERCENT
r1 I-PERCENT
|
 
| O
g1 O
. O
|
| O
yRiY O
|
| O
. O
|
| O
t O
|
| O
ili O
, O
|
| O
. O
( O
, O
( O
|
| O
. O
' O
, O
|
| O
, O
e. B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
l.-:I I-PERSON
|
| O
I O
|
| O
-i O
A O
|
| O
I O
|
| O
E O
: O
, O
|
| O
: O
L O
|
| O
2:-A O
|

| O
, O
e O
|
 | O
ILIRB O
AND O
ADVENIRBS O
|
| O
MI0 O
| | O
ABL O
A O
RISTR0NG B-ORG
, O
|
| O
IE B-ORG
IA0OI0RY I-ORG
B0I. I-ORG
` O
' O
|
| O
RAIs O
TR0IL01 O
, O
|
 | O
4ons B-CARDINAL
o O
|
| O
] O
s O
rntn O
nsae B-GPE
| | O
seA B-LOC
|
 | I-LOC
r O
|
| O
- O
|
| O
wrrr O
LOS O
ILUsTnATIONs O
. O
A O
|
| O
5 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
1 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
lo O
|
| O
1 B-CARDINAL
, O
| | O
gegeg B-PERSON
gg I-PERSON
-- I-PERSON
yen I-PERSON
|
| O
GHABORODGH O
- O
TRIII O
|
| O
184A. B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Digitized O
by O
the O
Internet O
Archive O
|
| O
in O
2007 B-DATE
with O
funding O
from O
|
| O
Mlcrosoft B-ORG
Corporation I-ORG
|
| O
http://www.archive.org/details/lifeadventuresof00troliala O
|
| O
Stack O
|
| O
Annex B-PERSON
|

| O
s% O
|
| O
--1 O
|
| O
r3 O
|

| O
P O
R O
E O
FAC O
E. O
|
| O
WVn O
the O
author O
of O
` O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
'' I-PERSON
first B-ORDINAL
determined O
on O
|
| O
attempting O
to O
draw O
the O
attention O
of O
her O
countrymen O
to O
the O
fearful O
|
| O
evils O
inherent O
in O
the O
Factory O
ystem O
, O
as O
carried O
out O
in O
our O
manufac- O
|
| O
turing O
towns O
, O
she O
intended O
to O
divide O
her O
work O
into O
two B-CARDINAL
portions O
, O
which O
|
| O
should O
present O
the O
same O
subject O
under O
two B-CARDINAL
different O
phases O
. O
It O
was O
|
| O
her O
intention O
in O
thce O
first O
of O
these O
to O
drag O
into O
the B-DATE
light I-DATE
of I-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
and O
|
| O
place O
before O
the O
eyes O
of O
Englishmen B-FAC
, O
the O
hideous O
mass O
of O
injustice O
|
| O
and O
suffering O
to O
which O
thousands B-CARDINAL
of O
infant O
labourers O
are O
subjected O
, O
who O
|
| O
toil O
in O
our O
monstcr O
spinning O
- O
mills O
. O
In O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
, O
she O
proposed O
that O
the O
|
| O
hero O
of O
her O
tale O
, O
having O
lived O
through O
his O
toil O
- O
worn O
boyhood O
, O
should O
|
| O
have O
been O
seen O
embarkcl O
in O
those O
perfectly O
constitutional O
struggles O
|
| O
Ior O
the O
amelioration O
of O
the O
suflerings O
of O
his O
class O
, O
in O
which O
many O
of O
|
| O
the O
more O
enlightened O
operatives O
have O
been O
for O
some B-DATE
years I-DATE
engagedt O
. O
|
| O
The O
rst O
division O
of O
the O
subject O
has O
been O
some O
time O
in O
the O
reader O
's O
|
| O
hands O
. O
The O
true O
but O
most O
painful O
picture O
has O
been O
drawn O
faithfully O
|
| O
ant O
conscientiously O
. O
Of O
course O
voices O
have O
been O
raised O
to O
deny O
|
| O
loudly O
the O
truth O
of O
all O
the O
authar O
's O
statements O
, O
and O
to O
assert O
the O
whole O
|
| O
to O
be O
a O
mere O
tissue O
of O
invention O
and O
falsehood O
. O
The O
same O
charges O
|
| O
have O
been O
made O
against O
her O
upon O
anolher O
occnsion O
, O
and O
she O
has O
lived O
|
| O
to O
see O
the O
truth O
of O
her O
statements O
, O
so O
imputgned O
, O
universally O
admittetd O
. O
|
| O
She O
awaits O
with O
perfect O
confilence O
the O
time O
when O
similar O
justice O
shall O
|
| O
be O
rendered O
to O
these O
pages O
. O
|
| O
But O
with O
respect O
to O
that O
division O
of O
the O
subject O
which O
it O
was O
in- O
|
| O
tenel O
to O
bring O
forward O
in O
the O
latter O
part O
of O
ler O
work O
, O
the O
author O
's O
|
| O
views O
have O
undergone O
very O
considerable O
change O
. O
Inowing O
the O
immense O
|
| O
amount O
of O
evil O
to O
be O
remedied O
, O
and O
the O
urgent O
necessity O
, O
for O
many O
|
| O
reasons O
, O
that O
this O
remedy O
should O
not O
be O
delayed O
, O
it O
is O
grievous O
to O
see O
|
| O
REFACE B-ORG
. O
|
| O
misguided O
and O
unfortunate O
men O
pursuing O
a O
course O
which O
muslt O
neces- O
|
| O
sarily O
neutralize O
the O
efforts O
of O
their O
true O
friends O
. O
When O
those O
in O
whose O
|
| O
behalf O
she O
hoped O
to O
move O
the O
sympathy O
of O
their O
country O
are O
found O
|
| O
busy O
in O
scenes O
of O
ourage O
and O
lawless O
violence O
, O
and O
uniting O
themselves O
|
| O
with O
individuals O
whose O
doctrines O
are O
subversive O
of O
every O
species O
of O
|
| O
social O
order O
, O
the O
author O
feels O
that O
it O
would O
be O
alike O
acting O
in O
violation O
|
| O
of O
her O
own O
principles O
, O
and O
doing O
injury O
to O
the O
cause O
she O
wishes O
to O
|
| O
serte O
, O
were O
she O
to O
persist O
in O
an O
attempt O
to O
hold O
up O
as O
objects O
of O
public O
|
| O
sympathy O
, O
men O
who O
have O
stained O
their O
righteous O
cause O
with O
deeds O
of O
|
| O
violence O
and O
blood O
. O
TThe O
author O
is O
well O
aware O
that O
many O
, O
as O
well O
|
| O
operatives O
as O
their O
superiors O
, O
who O
were O
engaged O
in O
a O
virtuous O
struggle O
|
| O
against O
the O
Inwless B-ORG
power O
which O
oppresses O
them O
, O
deplore O
the O
madness O
|
| O
of O
these O
ill O
- O
advised O
men O
as O
much O
as O
herself O
. O
But O
the O
cause O
has O
been O
|
| O
too O
much O
sullied O
, O
and O
the O
sufferers O
too O
closely O
associated O
in O
the O
public O
|
| O
eye O
with O
those O
who O
have O
been O
guilty O
of O
all O
she O
most O
deprecates O
, O
to O
|
| O
permit O
her O
coutinuing O
the O
work O
as O
she O
intended O
. O
|
| O
Uhder O
tlese B-NORP
circumstanees O
she O
has O
determined O
that O
the O
existence O
of O
|
| O
ler O
hero O
as O
an O
operatire O
shall O
close O
with O
his O
childhool O
. O
No O
miseon- O
|
| O
struction O
of O
prineiples O
, O
no O
misconception O
of O
motives O
can O
exist O
with O
|
| O
regard O
to O
an O
attempt O
to O
ameliorate O
the O
lot O
of O
infant O
labourers O
. O
That O
her O
|
| O
pages O
may O
assist O
in O
promoting O
this O
object O
is O
her O
humble O
and O
most O
|
| O
et O
boe O
. O
` B-WORK_OF_ART
The I-WORK_OF_ART
Lite I-WORK_OF_ART
and I-WORK_OF_ART
Aenures I-WORK_OF_ART
of O
Micael B-PERSON
Arsrong''are O
, O
|
| O
therefore O
, O
coucluded O
in O
the O
twelfth B-ORDINAL
number O
. O
|
| O
CONTENTS B-ORG
. O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-ORG
I. I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Deseription I-ORG
of I-ORG
Dowling I-ORG
oge O
and O
its O
apputtenanees O
- O
Of O
its O
master- O
|
| O
Of O
its O
mistress O
- O
And O
all O
the O
Masters O
and O
Misses O
Dowling O
- O
A O
lrge O
|
| O
dinner O
- O
party- O
hot O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
and O
the O
way O
to O
cseape O
from O
it O
... O
I O
|
| O
CHAPIER O
II O
. O
|
| O
A O
delightful O
ramble O
- O
Friendship O
and O
the O
MIuse B-ORG
- O
An O
adventure O
- O
Danger O
|
| O
and O
escnpe O
- O
Gratitude O
and O
benevolence O
.... O
|
| O
cIIAPTER O
III O
. O
|

| O
Introduction O
of O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
into O
the O
family O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
- I-PERSON
Conjectures I-PERSON
concerning O
his O
parentage O
- O
A O
confabulation O
|
| O
between O
Sir O
Mtthew B-PERSON
and O
Mr O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
Parsons I-PERSON
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
Iy I-LAW
. O
|
 | O
24 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
little O
cottage O
gossip O
- O
Avisit O
of O
charity O
- O
Pmactical O
benevolence O
........ O
35 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
cHAPTER O
V. O
|
| O
A O
separation O
of O
loving O
learts O
- O
A O
specimen O
of O
finishod O
composition- O
|
| O
Condescension B-PRODUCT
and O
generosity O
- O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
clathes O
little O
Michael B-PERSON
|
| O
with O
his O
own O
hands O
... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
VI I-LAW
. O
|
| O
4 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Michael B-PERSON
's O
introluction O
to O
nll O
the O
Miss O
Dowlings B-PERSON
- O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
feeds O
|
| O
him O
with O
his O
own O
hand O
, O
aud O
presents O
him O
to O
all O
his O
mst O
valued O
|
| O
friends O
.... O
-- O
|
| O
CHRAPTER O
VII O
. O
|
| O
.. O
52 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
popular O
clamacter O
- O
MIore O
enerolenee O
- O
lInteresting O
intelligence O
re O
|
| O
zeived O
witl O
beconing O
animation O
- O
A O
select O
committee O
--- O
A O
farewell O
|
| O
full O
of O
meaning O
....... O
|
| O
.7 O
|
| O
coxTEyTS O
. O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-ORG
VIII I-ORG
. O
|
| O
A O
ery O
innoeent O
tte O
-- O
tte O
, O
but O
in O
wvhich O
Miss O
Miarthia B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
comes O
|
| O
to O
a O
wrong O
conclusion O
- O
An O
untortnnate O
emhassy O
-- O
hn O
agreenble O
ex- O
|
| O
cursion O
- O
nA O
philosophical O
disquisition- O
isit O
to O
the O
factory O
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTE O
IX O
. O
|
| O
72 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Some O
pnrticulars O
respecting O
Miiss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
- O
A O
demonstration O
of O
|
| O
neighbonrly O
friendsli O
and O
anxiety O
- O
Te O
wilfulncss O
of O
an O
leiress O
- O
A O
|
| O
glenam O
of O
light O
caught O
in O
the O
darkness.- O
. O
.. O
- O
.. O
|
| O
cAPTER O
X. O
|
| O
.B1 O
|
| O
More O
wilfulness O
on O
the O
part O
of O
the O
heiress O
- O
Private O
theatricals O
- O
Failnre O
|
| O
of O
a O
young O
performer O
, O
and O
its O
conscquences O
- O
Plilosoplical O
brenkfast- O
|
| O
table O
- O
A O
morning B-TIME
's O
excursion O
...... O
|
| O
CHAPTER O
XI O
. O
|
 | O
D5 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
MIss O
Brotherton B-GPE
pushcs O
ler O
inquiries O
further O
- O
A O
well O
- O
arranged O
scheme O
|
| O
isagreeably O
defeated O
- O
A O
isit O
, O
and O
its O
consequcenees O
..... O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-ORG
XII I-ORG
. O
|
| O
- O
... O
112 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
An O
unfortunate O
rencounter O
- O
An O
adventure O
- O
Mliss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
grows O
wiser O
|
| O
every B-DATE
day I-DATE
.... O
|
| O
CAPTER O
XIII O
. O
|
| O
.. O
123 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Disagreeahle B-ORG
meditations O
- O
A O
confidential O
interview O
with O
a O
faithfial O
senr- O
|
| O
vant O
- O
Another O
intervie O
, O
not O
quite O
so O
confidential O
, O
witl O
s O
dauglter- O
|
| O
MIarth O
and O
Michael B-PERSON
take O
a O
pleasant O
alk O
togetlier O
to O
visit O
tle O
widow O
|
| O
Amstrong B-ORG
- I-ORG
A I-ORG
consultation I-ORG
... O
- O
|
| O
cAPTER O
XIV B-ORG
. O
|
| O
.. O
137 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Mlary B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
continues O
sick O
in O
heart O
and O
mind O
- O
But O
is O
roused O
and O
|
| O
cheered O
hy O
her O
own O
steadlast O
will O
-- O
An O
o'er O
trtc O
tale O
.... O
|
| O
cHAPTEn O
YV B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
- O
. O
14E B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
tato--'te O
walk O
- O
Lively O
if O
not O
instructive O
conversation O
- O
The O
ricl O
|
| O
visiting O
the O
poor O
- O
Miisplaced O
confidenee O
- O
Innocent O
sin O
... O
- O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-LAW
XVI I-LAW
. O
|
| O
PAGE B-ORG
|
| O
... O
158 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
MIiss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
visits O
tle O
widow O
Armstrong B-PERSON
, O
and O
lays O
tle O
foundation O
of O
|
| O
a O
very O
lasting O
friendship O
- O
She O
then O
calls O
at O
Dowling B-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
, O
but O
fails O
|
| O
of O
abtaining O
what O
she O
ent O
for O
. O
|
| O
.. O
163 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNTNT O
. O
|
| O
cIIAPTER O
XVII B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
AGE O
|
| O
A O
journey O
begun O
in O
very O
good O
style O
, O
but O
ending O
not O
qite O
so O
well O
- O
A O
|
| O
faithful O
deseription O
of O
n O
valley O
in O
Derbsyshiroe B-GPE
- I-GPE
Mlichael I-GPE
makes O
some O
|
| O
new O
araintance O
... O
- O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-LAW
XVIII I-LAW
. O
|
| O
.... O
174 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
An O
explanatory O
epistle O
, O
wlricl O
docs O
not O
prove O
satisfctory O
- O
Plans O
for O
the O
|
| O
fntre O
, O
followed O
by O
active O
measures O
to O
carry O
them O
into O
cffect O
- O
A O
|
| O
morning O
visit O
to O
MIrs O
, O
Gabberly B-NORP
..... O
|
| O
cIAPFER O
XIX B-ORG
. O
|
| O
vii O
|
| O
. O
18S B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
oyage O
of O
discovsery O
- O
A. O
plain O
statement O
, O
leading O
to O
tle O
conviction O
|
| O
that O
eren O
wlere O
ignorance O
is O
not O
bliss O
, O
knowledge O
is O
not O
always O
hap- O
|
| O
piness O
- O
A O
hasty O
friendship O
that O
mny B-ORG
nevertheless O
prove O
lasting O
....... O
19U B-CARDINAL
|
| O
cIIAPTER O
XYX B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Trade O
in O
a O
flonrishing O
state O
- O
The O
benefits O
conferrel O
thereby O
to O
those O
|
| O
employed O
in O
it O
- O
The O
natural O
logic O
of O
religion O
- O
Its O
fallibility O
when O
|
| O
ut O
to O
the O
test O
.... O
|
| O
cHATER O
XXI B-ORG
. O
|
| O
.. O
212 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
MIiss O
Brothierton B-PERSON
exerts O
er O
cloqence O
, O
and O
nurse O
Tremlett B-PERSON
is O
brought O
to O
|
| O
reason O
therehy O
-- O
Tle O
lreiress O
hardens O
lcr O
hcart O
, O
and O
speaks O
harsh O
|
| O
trutis O
to O
Martha B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
but O
all O
in O
vain O
- O
She O
conceives O
a O
projeet O
, O
|
| O
and O
sets O
about O
putting O
it O
in O
execution O
with O
great O
spirit O
... O
- O
. O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
XXII B-ORG
. O
|
| O
-- O
.. O
I0 B-NORP
|
| O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
sets O
of O
on O
her O
travels O
, O
and O
feels O
frighitened O
at O
her O
own O
|
| O
temerity O
- O
lut O
speedily O
recoers O
her O
courage O
, O
and O
plays O
the O
leroins- O
|
| O
She O
visits O
some O
factories O
, O
nand O
is O
introduced O
to O
a O
Sunday B-DATE
- O
school O
- O
She O
|
| O
approches O
the O
precincts O
of O
thc O
Deep B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
..... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-ORG
XIII I-ORG
. O
|
| O
. O
235 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
hMiss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
and O
her O
friend O
arrive O
at O
tle O
Deep B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
- I-LOC
hA I-LOC
roview- O
|
| O
Disappointment- O
' O
A O
sudden O
thouglt O
strikes O
'' O
thce O
hcircss O
- O
She O
con- O
|
| O
cludes O
a O
hargain O
, O
though O
not O
the O
one O
for O
which O
she O
meditated O
- O
She O
|
| O
sets O
out O
upon O
a O
walk O
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-ORG
XXIv O
. O
|
| O
.... O
25 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
The O
walk O
proves O
too O
fatiguing O
to O
one O
of O
the O
party O
, O
but O
not O
to O
Mliss B-PERSON
Bro- I-PERSON
|
| O
therton O
- O
She O
wanders O
further O
, O
and O
meets O
with O
an O
adventure O
, O
but O
at O
|
| O
last O
returns O
in O
safety O
to O
her O
inn O
- O
A O
journey O
homeward O
, O
and O
a O
fact O
re- O
|
| O
lated O
withiount O
ornameut O
.. O
|
| O
- O
.. O
262 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
viii O
|
| O
coNTEyTS O
. O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-LAW
xxV. I-LAW
|
| O
The O
narratie O
returns O
to O
its O
hero O
- O
nd O
relates O
wby O
and O
wherefore O
le O
|
| O
was O
kept O
alive O
- O
The O
boy O
grows O
tall O
, O
and O
tkes O
to O
thinking O
........ O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
YXYVI O
. O
|
| O
.. O
78 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
dismal O
enterprise O
, O
and O
its O
melancholy O
result O
- O
MIartha O
Dowling O
p- O
|
| O
nished O
more O
severely O
than O
sle O
desered O
- O
Very O
wild O
projects O
conceived O
|
| O
by O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
, O
and O
speedily O
put O
in O
execution O
..... O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
XXVII O
. O
|
| O
.. O
28 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Mlichael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
sets O
ont O
upon O
a O
dangerous O
expedition O
- O
Its O
termi- O
|
| O
nation O
proes O
rather O
more O
than O
he O
cnn B-ORG
bear O
- O
He O
meets O
a O
good O
man O
|
| O
and O
takes O
service O
under O
im O
- O
He O
asks O
anl O
obtains O
a O
holiday O
, O
and O
|
| O
meets O
several O
adventures O
in O
the O
course O
of O
it O
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XXVIII I-LAW
. O
|
| O
An O
important O
interview O
- O
Doubts O
and O
fenrs O
... O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
XXIX B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
.. O
207 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
- O
.. O
32l B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Michael B-PERSON
calls O
his O
wisdom O
to O
couneil O
, O
and O
the O
points O
to O
be O
discussed O
puzzle O
|
| O
them O
- O
hn O
early O
walk O
- O
An O
old O
friend O
with O
a O
changed O
face O
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTER O
XXX O
. O
|
| O
. O
334 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Mlichael B-GPE
grows O
rich O
, O
and O
takes O
a O
very O
delightful O
walk O
back O
to O
WYestmor- B-ORG
|
| O
land O
-- O
His O
preparations O
for O
a O
longer O
journey O
are O
suddenly O
stopped- O
|
| O
He O
makes O
apainfiul O
visit O
, O
but O
meets O
many O
old O
aeuaintances O
.... O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
XXXI I-LAW
. O
|
| O
... O
34U B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
friendly O
consultation O
- O
A O
dangerous O
embassy O
- O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
receives O
|
| O
same O
disagreeable O
intelligence O
- O
An O
awkward O
contest O
- O
Unpleasant O
|
| O
rislons O
- O
A O
fitting O
termination O
to O
the O
cnnfidential O
union O
bctween O
|
| O
master O
and O
tnan O
.. O
- O
. O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
XXXII B-ORG
. O
|
| O
... O
35 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
MIr O
. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
gives O
his O
sister O
Martha B-PERSON
notice O
to O
quit O
the O
pre- O
|
| O
mises O
, O
which O
occasions O
Mlicbael B-GPE
to O
appear O
in O
a O
new O
character- O
long O
|
| O
journey O
taken O
by O
novices O
, O
but O
they O
do O
not O
lose O
their O
way O
, O
and O
arrive O
|
| O
at O
the O
right O
place O
at O
last O
- O
.. O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-LAW
XXXIII I-LAW
. O
|
| O
... O
87 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
tdte O
- O
a O
- O
tite O
-- O
A O
second B-ORDINAL
- O
A O
third B-ORDINAL
-- O
hA O
mysterious O
result O
- O
Conclusion O
.... O
379 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
TIIE O
|
| O
LIFE O
AND O
ADVENTURES B-ORG
|
| O
oB B-GPE
|
| O
M O
IC O
H O
AEL O
A O
R O
MSTRON O
G O
, O
|
| O
I O
|
| O
3 B-CARDINAL
T O
|
 | O
AcoY O
BO O
. O
|
| O
c O
II B-CARDINAL
APTER O
I. O
|
| O
EsCIrO O
O O
DOLIG O
ODGE O
A O
TTS O
PPURTENANCE- O
|
| O
o O
IT O
TFER O
- O
D O
I O
MIITLESS O
- O
AYD O
ALL O
TIE O
IAETERs O
A1D O
|
| O
IISSLES O
DOWI.IG O
- O
A O
LAr O
, O
E O
IR O
- O
PITY- O
IIOT O
DING- O
|
| O
oox O
, O
AND O
TIIE O
wY O
To O
ESCAPE O
ROI O
IT O
, O
|
| O
No O
traveller O
can O
ride O
or O
drive O
withia O
sight O
of O
Dowling B-PERSON
Lolge I-PERSON
, O
|
| O
without O
heing O
tempted O
to O
inquire O
, O
: O
Whose O
house O
is O
that O
? O
|
| O
It O
forms O
, O
indeed O
, O
a O
very O
striking O
object O
on O
the O
right O
of O
the O
London B-GPE
|
| O
road O
, O
as O
the O
hill O
rises O
gradually O
, O
and O
overlooks O
the O
town O
of O
Ashleigh B-GPE
, O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
busiest O
in O
Lancashire B-GPE
, O
to O
the O
left O
  O
for O
although O
the O
trees O
|
| O
about O
the O
mansion O
are O
not O
yet O
of O
sufficient O
growth O
to O
make O
it O
pic- O
|
| O
turesque O
, O
its O
lofty O
portico O
, O
well O
- O
proportioned O
wings O
, O
and O
command- O
|
| O
ing O
site O
, O
render O
it O
an O
ornament O
to O
the O
neighbourhood O
for O
miles O
|
| O
round O
. O
|
| O
Those O
who O
are O
admitted O
to O
a O
nearer O
view O
of O
the O
house O
( O
and O
, O
for O
|
| O
the O
conveience O
of O
the O
public O
, O
every O
Wenesday O
is O
set O
apart O
for O
|
| O
its O
heing O
shown O
) O
, O
will O
find O
still O
more O
to O
admire O
, O
than O
such O
as O
see O
it O
|
| O
only O
from O
a O
distance O
. O
It O
has O
its O
park O
and O
its O
pinery O
  O
conservatories O
, O
|
| O
which O
cause O
the O
mercnry O
in O
the O
thermometer O
, O
when O
paraled O
through O
|
| O
them O
, O
to O
run O
up O
to O
the O
cocoa O
- O
ripening O
heat O
of O
the O
tropics O
. O
, O
nd O
ice- O
|
| O
houses O
that O
would O
bring O
it O
down O
agnin O
to O
the O
temperature O
of O
Bhering O
's O
|
| O
traits O
. O
It O
has O
three B-CARDINAL
drawing O
- O
rooms O
, O
two B-CARDINAL
dining O
- O
rooms O
, O
a O
great O
|
| O
library O
, O
all O
full O
of O
new O
books O
  O
as O
many O
bedrooms O
, O
dressing O
- O
rooms O
, O
|
| O
and O
boudoirs O
, O
as O
a O
great O
man O
's O
house O
ought O
to O
have O
, O
an O
a O
stuly O
|
| O
besides O
- O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
's O
own O
private O
study O
. O
This O
de- O
|
| O
lightful O
little O
apartnet O
is O
small O
, O
not O
more B-QUANTITY
than I-QUANTITY
twelve I-QUANTITY
feet I-QUANTITY
sqare O
  O
|
| O
but O
nathing O
can O
be O
more O
agreeable O
andl O
convenient O
. O
lt O
opens O
by O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
door O
from O
the O
great O
hall O
of O
entrance O
, O
and O
by O
another O
commu- O
|
| O
TEE B-ORG
LIFE I-ORG
AD I-ORG
ADETDnES I-ORG
|
| O
nicates O
through O
a O
long O
stone O
- O
passage O
with O
the O
offices O
of O
the O
mansiou O
: O
|
| O
enabling O
the O
kuight O
to O
receivse O
, O
without O
interruption O
, O
not O
only O
ls O
|
| O
overlookers O
( O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
being O
the O
poprietor O
of O
many O
cotton O
- O
mills O
) O
, O
|
| O
but O
his O
coachman O
, O
gardener O
, O
bailifl O
, O
and O
whomever O
else O
he O
might O
|
| O
wish O
to O
transact O
business O
with O
. O
|
| O
O O
the O
fitting O
up O
of O
this O
princely O
mansion O
, O
it O
is O
only O
necessary O
to O
|
| O
sy O
, O
that O
it O
is O
done O
in O
a O
spirit O
of O
emulative O
imitation O
, O
which O
ren- O
|
| O
ders O
it O
fully O
equal O
, O
in O
this O
respect O
, O
to O
the O
most O
finished O
private O
|
| O
dwellings O
in O
Europe B-LOC
. O
The O
furniure O
is O
uniformly O
rich O
throughout O
: O
|
| O
the O
picture O
- O
frames O
in O
the O
best O
style O
of O
art O
  O
iaxony O
carpets O
in O
the O
|
| O
drawing O
- O
sooms O
, O
Turkey B-GPE
ditto O
in O
the O
dining O
- O
reoms O
, O
russels O
in O
the O
|
| O
bedrooms O
, O
and O
indeed O
not O
a B-QUANTITY
single I-QUANTITY
inch I-QUANTITY
of O
Kidderminster B-PERSON
any O
|
| O
where O
, O
except O
in O
the O
garrets O
. O
|
| O
I O
will O
not O
attempt O
to O
state O
the O
amount O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
's O
|
| O
wealth O
  O
Cocker B-NORP
himself O
would O
have O
found O
it O
a O
laborious O
task O
to O
|
| O
make O
the O
calculation O
  O
and O
it O
is O
sufficient O
for O
the O
gratification O
of O
all O
|
| O
reasonable O
curiosity O
to O
say O
, O
that O
throughout O
the O
whole O
line O
of O
that O
|
| O
Golconda B-GPE
conntry O
, O
which O
, O
being O
the O
busiest O
of O
the O
manufacturing O
|
| O
districts O
, O
is O
probably O
the O
richest O
in O
the O
world O
, O
there O
was O
not O
any O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
who O
could O
vie O
in O
wealth O
with O
him O
. O
In O
a O
worl O
, O
he O
shone O
amidst O
his O
|
| O
rich O
neighbours O
like O
a O
golden O
sun O
, O
surrounded O
by O
siler O
moons O
. O
|
| O
But O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
was O
a O
superior O
man O
in O
all O
ways O
. O
He O
was O
six B-QUANTITY
|
| I-QUANTITY
feet I-QUANTITY
two I-QUANTITY
inches I-QUANTITY
in O
height O
, O
and O
stout O
in O
proportion O
, O
with O
hands O
and O
|
| O
feet O
that O
might O
have O
sufficed O
a O
giant O
. O
His O
intellectual O
gifts O
were O
|
| O
also O
of O
no O
ordinary O
character O
. O
He O
liked O
well O
enough O
, O
perhaps O
, O
to O
|
| O
stand O
pre O
- O
eminent O
in O
the O
commercial O
estimation O
of O
his O
neighbours O
  O
|
| O
but O
so O
enlightened O
was O
his O
spirit O
, O
that O
he O
liked O
better O
still O
to O
shine O
be- O
|
| O
fore O
their O
eyes O
as O
a O
man O
of O
taste O
, O
a O
literary O
and O
accomplished O
gentle- O
|
| O
man O
, O
a O
speaker O
of O
modern O
languages O
, O
a O
critical O
French B-NORP
scholar O
, O
a O
|
| O
playfnl O
votary O
of O
the O
muses O
himself O
, O
and O
a O
universal O
Mecaenas B-PERSON
to O
all O
|
| O
who O
wielded O
a O
pen O
in O
their O
service O
. O
But O
beyond O
all O
else O
, O
Sir O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
valued O
himself O
upon O
his O
reputation O
for O
the O
lighter O
graces O
of O
|
| O
wit O
and O
guallantry O
: O
he O
sought O
to O
make O
himnself O
into O
something O
of O
|
| O
a O
delightful O
mixture O
between O
Killigrew B-PERSON
and O
the O
Count O
de O
Gra- O
|
| O
mont O
: O
and O
there O
was O
no O
receptacle O
of O
wit O
from O
Joe B-PERSON
Miller I-PERSON
downwards O
, O
|
| O
egeey O
ise O
y,)e O
4euus B-CARDINAL
|
| O
with O
assiduity O
and O
perseveranice O
of O
the O
highest O
order O
. O
|
| O
lie O
was O
often O
heard O
to O
declare O
, O
that O
he O
loved O
nothing O
so O
well O
as O
|
| O
the O
promotion O
of O
mirth O
and O
light O
- O
heartedness O
among O
his O
fellow- O
] O
|
| O
creatures O
  O
but O
tragedy O
and O
cmely O
often O
walk O
through O
the O
] O
|
| O
wold O
he O
in O
han B-NORP
tegehe O
, O
as O
tei O
alliaece O
ays O
be O
uaed O
|
| O
without O
difficulty O
in O
the O
career O
of O
Sir O
Mlatthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
. O
|
| O
The O
wife O
of O
this O
prosperous O
gentleman O
hat O
also O
many O
admirable O
|
| O
qualities O
. O
She O
was O
not O
one O
of O
the O
idle O
gossipers O
who O
delight O
in O
|
| O
chattering O
about O
their O
own O
concerns O
to O
avery O
one B-CARDINAL
vho O
will O
listen O
: O
: O
|
| O
she O
despised O
such O
weakness O
, O
and O
had O
never O
been O
heard O
to O
hint O
atl O
|
| O
her O
ow O
parenage O
, O
or O
early O
history O
, O
to O
any O
one O
: O
rightly O
considering O
. O
|
| O
that O
when O
such O
matters O
are O
unceasingly O
discussed O
, O
they O
may O
be O
ex-- O
|
  | O
te O
gey O
| | O
ies O
| | O
s O
bne O
] O
|
| O
while O
devoting O
an O
undue O
share O
of O
attention O
to O
that O
of O
others O
. O
|

| O
TRE O
LIPE O
AND O
AD B-ORDINAL
ETIRES O
|
| O
degree O
at O
all O
  O
but O
, O
though O
a O
good O
man O
, O
and O
an O
excellent O
clergyman O
|
| O
to O
boot O
, O
he O
had O
a O
strong O
taste O
for O
humour O
, O
and O
had O
already O
dis- O
|
| O
covered O
that O
his O
neighbour O
at O
the O
great O
house O
was O
rich O
in O
more O
|
| O
ways O
thanone O
. O
It O
was O
, O
therefore O
, O
with O
the O
utmost O
civility O
that O
he O
|
| O
answered O
, O
| | O
My O
degree O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
was O
that O
of O
Master B-WORK_OF_ART
of I-WORK_OF_ART
Arts I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
'' O
|
| O
` O
And O
pray O
, O
sir O
, O
does O
it O
give O
you O
any O
title O
by O
which O
you O
cnn B-ORG
he O
|
| O
listinguished O
as O
in O
any O
way O
a O
superior O
sort O
of O
person O
in O
society O
? O
'' O
|
| O
I O
am O
afraid O
not O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
'' O
was O
the O
reply O
. O
|
| O
1I O
thank O
you O
, O
sir O
, O
for O
your O
sincerity O
, O
'' O
rejoined O
the O
knight O
. O
| | O
It O
|
| O
was O
important O
that O
l O
should O
ascertain O
the O
truth O
on O
this O
point.--You O
|
| O
are O
, O
then O
, O
never O
addressed O
in O
company O
as O
Mr. O
Master O
of O
Arts O
, O
or O
|
| O
any O
thing O
of O
that O
kind O
? O
' O
|
| O
e O
I. B-ORG
have O
never O
yet O
, O
Sir O
latthew O
, O
met O
with O
any O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
sufficient O
|
| O
politeness O
to O
do O
me O
that O
honour O
, O
'' O
repliel O
Mr. O
Hetherington B-PERSON
gravely O
. O
|
| O
` O
And O
I O
suppose O
you O
have O
lived O
in O
respectable O
society O
? O
'' O
|
| O
Very O
decent O
soeiety O
- O
very O
decent O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
'' O
replied O
|
| O
Hetherington B-ORG
, O
whose O
mother O
was O
the O
daughter O
of O
a O
distinguished O
|
| O
nobleman O
. O
|
| O
Good O
morning B-TIME
, O
sir O
: O
I O
shall O
he O
happy O
to O
see O
you O
at O
Dowling O
|
| O
Lodge O
- O
that O
is O
to O
say O
, O
sir O
, O
if O
your O
gown O
does O
not O
lead O
you O
to O
object O
|
| O
to O
elegantamusements O
. O
I O
love O
science O
, O
MIr O
. O
Hetherington B-ORG
, O
and O
am O
|
| O
indeed O
devoted O
to O
every O
thing O
intellecetunal O
  O
but O
, O
notwithstanding O
|
| O
this O
, O
I O
am O
a O
worshipper O
at O
the O
shrine O
of O
grace O
and O
wit O
, O
and O
could O
|
| O
not O
exis O
among O
people O
who O
did O
not O
relish O
the O
lighter O
embellish- O
|
| O
ments O
of O
society O
. O
'' O
|
| O
eI O
shuall O
be O
happy O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
to O
share O
in O
your O
gayer O
hours B-TIME
, O
|
| O
prvided O
I O
am O
fortnate O
enough O
to O
iind O
that O
you O
have O
no O
objection O
|
| O
to O
profit O
by O
my O
graver O
ones O
, O
'' O
replied O
the O
clergyman O
. O
|
| O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
returnel O
from O
this O
visit O
very O
well O
pleased O
with O
the O
|
| O
new O
reetor O
. O
Mlr O
. O
Augustus B-PERSON
was O
immediately O
comforted O
by O
a O
letter O
, O
|
| O
informing O
him O
that O
he O
might O
eall O
in O
his O
accounts O
, O
and O
prepare O
to O
|
| O
leave O
the O
university O
as O
soon O
as O
he O
pleased O
  O
and O
, O
within O
ten B-DATE
days I-DATE
|
| O
after O
receiving O
it O
, O
the O
amiable O
young O
man O
was O
restored O
to O
the O
bosom O
|
| O
of O
his O
family O
. O
|
| O
Next O
to O
this O
primal O
hope O
of O
the O
Dowling O
race O
, O
came O
three B-CARDINAL
young O
|
| O
ladies O
, O
between B-DATE
the I-DATE
ages I-DATE
of I-DATE
seventeen I-DATE
and O
twent O
- O
one O
  O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
|
| O
eldest O
of O
thiem O
being O
as O
like O
as O
two B-CARDINAL
peas O
, O
and O
the O
third B-ORDINAL
like O
nothing O
|
| O
on O
earth O
hut O
herself O
. O
Then O
followed O
several O
young O
gentlemen O
, O
|
| O
who O
were O
placed O
at O
different O
fashionable O
schools O
  O
for O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
who O
was O
a O
man O
of O
very O
enlarged O
mind O
, O
declared O
it O
to O
be O
his O
opinion O
|
| O
and O
his O
principle O
, O
that O
the O
patronage O
of O
such O
a O
fortune O
as O
his O
should O
|
| O
be O
extended O
as O
widely O
as O
possible O
. O
Afer O
these O
young O
gentlemen O
|
| O
came O
, O
one O
after O
the O
other O
, O
with O
the O
interval O
of O
about B-DATE
eleven I-DATE
months I-DATE
|
| O
between O
them O
, O
ever O
so O
many O
little O
girls O
, O
who O
, O
for O
the O
present O
, O
were O
|
| O
all O
educated O
at O
home O
, O
having O
a O
particularly O
clever O
French B-NORP
governess O
. O
|
| O
All O
the O
rest O
were O
nice O
liutle O
children O
of O
diiferent O
degrees O
of O
baby- O
|
| O
haood O
  O
the O
dear O
little O
girls O
being O
remarkable O
for O
their O
long O
plaited O
|
| O
hair O
, O
short O
frocks O
, O
and O
furhelowed O
trousers O
, O
and O
the O
dear O
liutle O
boys O
|
| O
for O
the O
manly O
bustle O
with O
which O
they O
wore O
their O
Scotch B-NORP
honnets O
and O
|
| O
plaided O
tunics O
, O
which O
, O
considering O
that O
neither O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
nor O
his O
|
| O
O O
IICIAEL O
ARMISTROG O
. O
|
| O
lady O
hal O
ever O
been O
in O
Sicotland B-GPE
in O
their O
lives O
, O
showed O
great O
enlarge- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
national O
feeling O
. O
Altogether O
, O
it O
was O
considered O
to O
be O
the O
|
| O
finest O
family O
ever O
seehn O
. O
|
| O
It O
happened O
upon O
a O
broiliug O
day O
about O
the O
midle O
of O
July B-DATE
, O
during O
|
| O
e O
of O
the O
hottest O
summens O
ngland O
had O
ever O
known O
, O
that O
sir O
|
| O
Mauthew B-PERSON
and O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
` O
entartained O
a O
party O
of O
distinguished O
|
| O
fashionables O
'' O
at O
dinner O
, O
|
| O
It O
may O
hae O
been O
remarked O
by O
those.who O
study O
such O
subjects O
, O
|
| O
that O
there O
is O
a O
difference O
betweon O
a O
dinner O
- O
party O
given O
at O
such O
a O
|
| O
grand O
mansion O
as O
that O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
and O
one O
at O
a O
dwell- O
|
| O
Pg O
of O
perhaps O
not O
a O
quarter O
the O
size O
, O
where O
the O
owners O
are O
of O
a O
dif- O
|
| O
ferent O
order O
of O
the O
aristocracy O
, O
huving O
a O
longer O
pedigres O
, O
and O
a O
|
| O
shorter O
purse O
. O
At O
hoth O
, O
probably O
, O
  O
the O
banquet O
will O
be O
a O
costly O
one O
, O
|
| O
yet O
the O
vne O
entertainment O
will O
comne O
of O
' O
in O
a O
manner O
as.unlike O
as O
|
| O
essible O
to O
the O
other O
. O
There O
is O
something O
in O
the O
usual O
way O
of O
wearing O
|
| O
stiff O
new O
- O
made O
grandeur O
, O
not O
far O
unlike O
that O
of O
wearing O
stiff O
new- O
|
| O
made O
clothes O
. O
Neither O
the O
onenor O
the O
other O
sit O
easily O
. O
|
| O
At O
this O
splendid O
dinner O
at O
Dowling B-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
, O
the O
company O
consisted O
|
| O
of O
a O
selection O
from O
the O
neighbouring O
families O
, O
made O
on O
the O
most O
le- O
|
| O
gitmate O
principles O
of O
exelusiveness O
: O
no O
family O
being O
invited O
who O
|
| O
did O
not O
drive O
four B-CARDINAL
horses O
at O
the O
races O
. O
To O
this O
there O
were O
indeed O
|
| O
two B-CARDINAL
exceptions O
. O
The O
frst O
was O
the O
Right O
Honourable O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
|
| O
Shrimpton B-ORG
  O
but O
this O
distinguished O
lady O
, O
though O
she O
drove O
only O
one O
|
| O
pony O
instead O
of O
four B-CARDINAL
horses O
, O
was O
considered O
by O
all O
the O
country O
|
| O
round O
as O
the O
one B-CARDINAL
thing O
needful O
to O
render O
a O
party O
completely O
elegant O
. O
|
| O
She O
was O
, O
indeed O
, O
neither O
young O
, O
handsomne O
, O
nor O
rich O
, O
but O
she O
was O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
and O
this O
was O
enough O
. O
|
| O
The O
other O
exception O
was O
to O
be O
found O
in O
the O
rotund O
person O
of O
Dr. O
|
| O
Crockley O
, O
who O
having O
formerly O
been O
a O
celebrated O
quack O
, O
made O
a O
|
| O
little O
fortune O
, O
and O
taken O
out O
a O
diploma O
, O
had O
lately O
married O
a O
beauty O
, O
|
| O
and O
seutled O
in O
the O
town O
of O
Ashleigh B-GPE
, O
where O
he O
was O
well O
pleased O
to O
|
| O
pick O
up O
a O
few O
guiuea O
fees O
, O
both O
as O
a O
public O
eidence O
of O
his O
being O
a O
|
| O
renal O
Mi B-ORG
. O
D. B-NORP
, O
and O
as O
a O
private O
fund O
wlerewith O
to O
indulge O
his O
still O
|
| O
ery O
tender O
passion O
. O
, O
by O
buying O
finery O
for O
his O
pretty O
young O
wife O
. O
|
| O
This O
fat O
litle O
gentleman O
was O
an O
especial O
favourite O
with O
Sir O
MIat- B-PERSON
|
| O
thew O
, O
chiefly O
on O
aceount O
of O
his O
jocund O
humour O
and O
ready O
langh O
: O
  O
|
| O
and O
also O
, O
perhaps O
, O
because O
he O
had O
a O
pleasan O
way O
, O
peculiar O
to O
him- O
|
| O
self O
, O
of O
paying O
compliments O
in O
the O
bluntest O
and O
. O
most O
unstudied O
|
| O
manner O
possible O
, O
|
| O
But O
, O
notwithstanding O
the O
presence O
of O
all O
. O
these O
distinguished O
per- O
|
| O
sons O
, O
the O
dinner O
moved O
on O
very O
slowly O
. O
Sir O
Mlatthew B-PERSON
, O
indeed O
, O
was O
|
| O
as O
brilliant O
as O
it O
was O
possible O
for O
any O
man O
to O
be O
under O
the O
circum- O
|
| O
stances O
, O
and O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
who O
did O
not O
scruple O
to O
declare O
that O
she O
|
| O
was O
very O
partial O
to O
him O
, O
- O
listened O
to O
all O
he O
said O
to O
her O
with O
as O
much O
|
| O
attention O
at O
least O
as O
any O
lady O
could O
be O
expected O
to O
do O
, O
who O
was O
|
| O
making O
one O
of O
sixteen B-CARDINAL
at O
a O
dinner O
, O
where O
there O
were O
an O
equal O
num- O
|
| O
ber O
of O
dishes O
of O
hot O
meats O
reeking O
upon O
the O
table O
, O
and O
the O
thermo- O
|
| O
meter O
standing O
at O
87 B-CARDINAL
' I-CARDINAL
. O
r O
, O
Crockley B-PERSON
, O
too O
, O
laughed O
repeatedly O
: O
|
| O
but O
his O
laugh O
was O
like O
a O
Lucifer B-PERSON
match O
that O
fails O
, O
just O
kinling O
and O
|
| O
TIE B-ORG
LIFE I-ORG
AD O
ADVEFRES O
|
| O
sputtering O
a O
little O
, O
but O
going O
out O
before O
it O
is O
able O
to O
communicate O
its O
|
| O
light O
. O
|
| O
The O
very O
sight O
of O
the O
servants O
as O
they O
panted O
round O
the O
table O
, O
|
| O
was O
qite O
enough O
to O
smother O
and O
stifle O
all O
inclination O
for O
enjoyment O
|
| O
--their O
shoes O
creaked O
- O
their O
faces O
shone O
- O
ice O
became O
water O
- O
the O
|
| O
salad O
looked O
as O
if O
it O
were O
stewed O
- O
the O
cucumbers O
seemcd O
to O
have O
|
| O
fainted O
away O
- O
the O
prodigious O
turbot O
smelt O
fishy O
, O
and O
its O
attendant O
|
| O
lobster O
- O
sauce O
glowed O
not O
with O
a O
deeper O
tint O
, O
than O
did O
my O
ILady B-ORG
Dow- O
|
| O
ling O
's O
cheeks O
as O
her O
nose O
caught O
the O
unfragrant O
gale O
. O
In O
short O
, O
|
| O
it O
was O
a O
great O
dinner O
in O
the O
dog O
- O
days O
, O
and O
no O
more O
need O
be O
said O
of O
|
| O
it O
. O
|
| O
Great O
was O
the O
inward O
satisfaction O
of O
every O
guest O
, O
when O
at O
last O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
rose O
, O
and O
gave O
signal O
that O
the O
party O
was O
to O
be O
|
| O
divided O
in O
al B-GPE
. O
The O
languid O
ldies O
welcomed O
the O
coolness O
of O
the O
|
| O
marble O
hall O
as O
they O
passed O
through O
it O
, O
and O
the O
gentlemen O
gazed O
|
| O
eagerly O
at O
the O
butler O
as O
he O
brought O
forwvard O
a O
fresh O
supply O
of O
claret O
, O
|
| O
and O
a O
reinforcement O
of O
ice O
. O
But O
the O
cnjoyment O
of O
neither O
party O
|
| O
lasted O
long O
  O
for O
ady O
Dowling O
was O
too O
grand O
and O
too O
solemn O
not O
|
| O
to O
marshal O
all O
her O
company O
into O
her O
fine O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
where O
they O
|
| O
were O
all O
ceremoniously O
deposited O
on O
satin B-PERSON
sofas I-PERSON
, O
amidst O
swelling O
|
| O
pillows O
that O
might O
have O
defied O
the O
frosts O
of O
January B-DATE
  O
while O
seven B-CARDINAL
or O
|
| O
eight B-CARDINAL
hot O
- O
looking O
children O
were O
commanded O
to O
walk O
round O
the O
circle O
|
| O
and O
kiss O
every O
body O
. O
|
| O
Nor O
did O
the O
gentlemen O
fare O
much O
better O
  O
for O
scarcely O
had O
the O
|
| O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
closed O
after O
the O
ladies O
, O
before O
the O
shining O
ald- O
|
| O
head O
of O
Dr. O
Crackley B-PERSON
stretched O
itself O
up O
nearly O
to O
a O
loevel O
with O
the O
|
| O
long O
-backed O
Sir O
Matthewv B-PERSON
's O
breast O
- O
pin O
, O
whilst O
, O
with O
a O
very O
ominous O
|
| O
sort O
of O
growl O
, O
making O
itself O
heard O
before O
his O
lips O
opened O
, O
hce O
first B-ORDINAL
|
| O
preluded O
, O
and O
then O
uttered O
the O
following O
speech O
. O
|
| O
1 B-CARDINAL
do O
n't O
like O
it O
, O
Sir O
Matthew.-I B-PERSON
do O
n't O
like O
this O
business O
at O
the O
|
| O
Weavers O
' O
Arms O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
What O
business O
, O
Doctor O
? O
'' O
replied O
his O
fiend O
sharply O
. O
|
 | O
WVh O
this O
meeting O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
. O
I O
ca O
n't O
get O
the O
notion O
of O
a O
strike O
|
| O
out O
of O
my O
head O
. O
'' O
Eery O
chair O
was O
drawn O
towards O
the O
little O
doctor O
: O
no- O
|
| O
body O
had O
heard O
a O
word O
of O
it O
. O
e O
Well O
, O
gentlemen O
, O
perhaps O
I O
am O
mis- O
|
| O
taken O
- O
perhaps O
there O
has O
been O
no O
meeting O
, O
'' O
resumed O
the O
friendly O
|
| O
doctor O
. O
God O
knows O
, O
I O
do O
n't O
wish O
to O
spoil O
the O
enjoyment O
of O
this O
|
| O
dclightfal O
hour O
: O
but O
at O
any O
rate O
, O
my O
geod O
friends O
, O
it O
is O
as O
well O
for O
|
| O
you O
to O
be O
on O
the O
look O
- O
out O
. O
'' O
Then O
lowering O
his O
voicc O
, O
he O
muttered O
, O
|
| O
as O
near O
to O
the O
ear O
of O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
as O
he O
could O
reach O
, O
| | O
I O
knows O
that O
|
| O
your O
people O
are O
meeting O
, O
in O
doors O
and O
out O
of O
doors O
. O
But O
you O
are O
|
| O
such O
a O
good O
, O
generous O
, O
kind O
- O
hearted O
creature O
, O
that O
I O
dare O
say O
we O
|
| O
shall O
hear O
, O
before O
long O
, O
of O
your O
having O
done O
some O
d O
- O
d O
good- O
|
| O
natured O
thing O
or O
other O
, O
and O
that O
perhaps O
will O
set O
all O
right O
  O
: O
who O
|
| O
knowe2 B-PERSON
' O
|
| O
Si B-PERSON
Matthew I-PERSON
gave O
an O
almost O
imperceptible O
nod O
, O
and O
pushed O
on O
|
| O
the O
claret O
- O
jug O
: O
but O
the O
gaiety O
of O
the O
party O
had O
been O
efectually O
|
| O
checked O
, O
and O
it O
was O
not O
long O
before O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
richest O
man O
in O
com- O
|
| O
any O
( O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
of O
course O
being O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
) O
said O
, O
| | O
Ido O
think O
and O
|
| O
II O
|   | O
urr O
LIII O
|
| O
h O
|
| O
a O
- O
m O
|
| O
----w- O
ms O
|
| O
3 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
--- O
r O
- O
i O
|
| O
T-- O
|
| O
, O
---- O
|
| O
- O
|
| O
--.- O
-i O
' O
. O
|
| O
l.- O
|
| O
.t O
. O
| | O
--- O
|
| O
- O
' O
. O
|
| O
f O
, O
|
| O
- O
|
| O
. O
|
| O
I O
|
| O
L O
|
| O
i O
|
| O
I- O
|
| O
] O
- O
z O
|
| O
: O
  O
-- O
|
| O
= O
. O
|
| O
i O
|

| O
-f O
|
| O
] O
ee O
|

| O
h O
|
| O
: O
|

| O
EP O
: O
|
| O
- O
g O
|
| O
r O
-- O
er O
|
| O
lir.--2 O
|
| O
F B-PRODUCT
|
| I-PRODUCT
- I-PRODUCT
|
| I-PRODUCT
. O
.. O
|
| O
: O
.- O
: O
|
| O
-.- O
, O
  O
|
| O
- O
. O
|
 | O
F O
|
| O
. O
| | O
-r O
. O
|
 
| O
r O
- O
F O
|
| O
rLA O
|
| O
t O
5- O
- O
|

| O
.. O
, O
|

| O
o O
IICHIAEL B-ORG
AIITROO I-ORG
. O
|
| O
belicve O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
that O
my O
lady O
's O
caflee O
would O
do O
more O
to O
cool O
|
| O
ns O
than O
your O
wine O
. O
'' O
The O
opinion O
was O
not O
opposed O
, O
and O
, O
much O
|
| O
earlier O
than O
usual O
, O
the O
gcentlemen O
rose O
, O
and O
followied O
the O
ladies O
. O
|
| O
But O
this O
movement O
did O
not O
appear O
greatly O
to O
increase O
the O
cnjoy- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
either O
party O
. O
It O
was O
near O
nine B-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
, O
but O
the O
heat O
con- O
|
| O
tinued O
to O
be O
most O
oppressive O
, O
and O
the O
company O
being O
faor O
the O
most O
|
| O
part O
massive O
in O
all O
ways O
, O
their O
union O
prduced O
more O
additional O
ca- O
|
| O
loric O
than O
gaiety O
. O
The O
whole O
process O
seemed O
to O
have O
the O
power O
of O
|
| O
turning O
the B-TIME
hours I-TIME
into O
molten O
lead O
ass O
they O
passed O
, O
a O
portion O
|
| O
of O
which O
appeared O
to O
drop O
, O
and O
weigh O
heavily O
on O
ench O
individual O
|
| O
heal O
. O
In O
vain O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
made O
the O
circuit O
of O
the O
company O
, O
|
| O
pausing O
in O
front O
either O
of O
the O
richest O
or O
handsomest O
ladies O
, O
as O
duty O
|
| O
or O
inclination O
' O
preponderated O
  O
in O
vain O
he O
uttered O
his O
newest O
puns O
|
| O
and O
freshest O
bon O
- O
mots O
- O
not O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
them O
had O
strength O
to O
laugh O
, O
|
| O
bcyond O
a O
little O
feehle O
` O
he O
, O
hel O
'' O
and O
even O
that O
was O
evidently O
a O
|
| O
painful O
effort O
. O
|
| O
Things O
were O
in O
this O
state O
, O
when O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
Shrimpton O
suddenly O
|
| O
rose O
from O
the O
silken O
couch O
amidst O
whose O
pillows O
she O
was O
im- O
|
| O
bedded O
, O
and O
, O
without O
explaining O
her O
intentions O
to O
my O
Lady O
Dowling O
, O
|
| O
or O
any O
one O
else O
, O
darted O
through O
the O
open O
French B-NORP
- O
window O
, O
and O
out O
|
| O
  O
.. O
- O
|
| O
ignorant O
of O
the O
rank O
of O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
he O
must O
from O
that O
moment O
|
| O
have O
fclt O
an O
innate O
conviction O
that O
she O
was O
somebody O
  O
for O
nobody O
that O
|
| O
was O
not O
somebody O
could O
have O
vehtured O
upon O
so O
daring O
an O
escapade O
|
| O
from O
such O
a O
solemn O
presence O
- O
chamber O
. O
' O
The O
effect O
it O
produced O
was O
|
| O
electric O
. O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
darted O
across O
the O
room O
with O
the O
eagerness O
ofa O
|
| O
man O
of O
gallantry O
and O
gaiety O
. O
He O
piqued O
himself O
upon O
being O
, O
of O
all O
the O
|
| O
great O
men O
in O
the O
neighbourhood O
the O
one O
upon O
whom O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
|
| O
bestowed O
the O
most O
attention O
. O
His O
estimate O
of O
the O
outward O
advan- O
|
| O
tages O
of O
his O
extensive O
person O
was O
indeed O
not O
a O
low O
one O
  O
and O
, O
despite O
|
| O
all O
his O
lady O
could O
do O
to O
ecrush O
such O
an O
odious O
idea O
, O
he O
was O
conscious O
|
| O
that O
he O
was O
dcvoted O
to O
the O
fair O
sex O
, O
and O
flattered O
himself O
that O
the O
|
| O
fair O
sex O
was O
naot O
ungrateful O
. O
In O
fact O
, O
his O
general O
manner O
to O
ladies O
|
| O
had O
a O
good O
deal O
of O
what O
in O
female O
slang O
is O
called O
swaining O
, O
: O
but O
to O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
it O
was O
certainly O
something O
more O
. O
Had O
she O
been O
simply O
|
| O
Miss O
Shrimpton B-PERSON
, O
it O
is O
prbable O
that O
, O
notwithsstanding O
her O
great O
|
| O
mental O
advantages O
, O
she O
would O
never O
ave O
been O
exposed O
to O
the O
|
| O
danger O
of O
this O
fascinating O
distinction O
, O
for O
she O
was O
nearly B-DATE
forty I-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
old I-DATE
, O
had O
a O
sharp O
nose O
, O
and O
was O
deplorably O
thin O
. O
But O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
was O
not O
a O
man O
to O
be O
insensible O
to O
the O
charm O
of O
getting O
talked O
of O
in O
|
| O
the O
neighbourhood O
about O
his O
devsotion O
to O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
any O
body O
, O
|
| O
even O
had O
she O
been O
a O
skeleton O
with O
aGorgon B-ORG
's O
hcad O
. O
There O
was O
, O
|
| O
however O
, O
independently O
of O
her O
bewitching O
title O
, O
a O
charm O
in O
her O
con- O
|
| O
versation O
and O
character O
, O
to O
which O
the O
knight O
was O
peculiarly O
sensible O
|
| O
Her O
ladyship O
was O
celebrated O
for O
her O
davotion O
both O
to O
literature O
and O
|
| O
art O
  O
and O
she O
permittcd O
all O
the O
world O
to O
know O
, O
for O
indeed O
she O
never O
|
| O
ceased O
to O
repeat O
it O
, O
that O
talent O
of O
every O
kind O
was O
to O
her O
an O
object O
of O
|
| O
idolatry O
. O
Now O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
knew O
that O
he O
was O
full O
of O
talent O
- O
poe- O
|
| O
HE O
LIRE O
AND O
ADVNTUE B-ORG
|
| O
tical O
talent O
, O
pictorial O
talent O
, O
epigramnmatic O
talent O
, O
every O
kinl O
of O
talent O
, O
|
| O
and O
it O
was O
certainly O
very O
delightful O
to O
be O
appreciated O
by O
such O
a O
|
| O
uperior O
creature O
as O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
. O
So O
strongly O
indeed O
did O
this O
|
| O
intellectual O
sympathy O
between O
them O
occasionally O
manifest O
itsclf O
, O
|
| O
that O
not O
cven O
the O
slarp O
elbows O
and O
red O
- O
tipped O
nose O
of O
the O
noble O
|
| O
lady O
, O
who O
, O
to O
borrow O
the O
phrase O
of O
an O
iniitable O
describer O
, O
was O
in O
|
| O
eery O
sense O
` O
` O
preter O
- O
blue O
perfect O
, O
'' O
could O
render O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
|
| O
Wie B-PERSON
easy O
respccting O
the O
nature O
of O
the O
friendship O
. O
Nor O
was O
it O
|
| O
without O
soething O
like O
a O
pang O
that O
she O
marked O
the O
sudden O
alacrity O
|
| O
of O
muyement O
with O
which O
Sir O
Mlatthew B-PERSON
now O
strode O
across O
the O
floor O
to O
|
| O
accampany O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissu I-PERSON
in O
the O
extraordinary O
frolic O
which O
led O
her O
, O
|
| O
in O
white B-PERSON
satin I-PERSON
shoes O
and O
a O
gauze O
dress O
, O
to O
exchange O
the O
drawing- O
|
| O
room O
for O
the O
garden O
, O
at O
nine B-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
in O
the O
eening O
. O
|
| O
IBt O
upon O
this O
occasion O
, O
as O
upon O
many O
others O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
|
| O
found O
consolation O
in O
the O
well O
- O
known O
fact O
, O
that O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
rarely O
|
| O
moved O
a O
step O
without O
being O
obsequiously O
attended O
by O
her O
humble O
|
| O
ceupanion O
, O
Mliss B-PERSON
Mogg I-PERSON
. O
This O
young O
lady O
had O
been O
selectcl O
to O
f6ll O
|
| O
her O
prescnt O
enviable O
situation O
, O
principally O
from O
her O
appearance O
, O
|
| O
though O
she O
was O
indeed O
by O
no O
means O
oid O
of O
many O
other O
qualifica- O
|
| O
tions O
admirably O
suited O
to O
it O
. O
But O
in O
appearance O
she O
was O
a O
striking O
|
| O
contrast O
to O
her O
tall O
and O
slender O
patroness O
: O
and O
, O
notwithistanding O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
's I-PERSON
mental O
superiority O
, O
she O
was O
not O
insensible O
to O
the O
|
| O
alvuntage O
of O
having O
a O
foil O
that O
should O
set O
off O
the O
charms O
upon O
|
| O
which O
she O
particularly O
prided O
herself O
. O
Lndy B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
had O
a O
thin O
, O
|
| O
narrow O
faot O
, O
and O
an O
ancle O
that O
resembled O
nothing O
so O
much O
as O
the O
|
| O
leg O
of O
a O
Robin B-PERSON
red O
- O
breast O
  O
the O
person O
of O
Miss B-PERSON
Mlogg I-PERSON
was O
supported O
|
| O
on O
shafts O
that O
told O
her O
axon O
origin O
, O
and O
feet O
that O
need O
not O
have O
|
| O
shrunk O
from O
sustaining O
an O
ox O
ILady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
's I-PERSON
slender O
waist O
might O
|
| O
have O
been O
cncireled O
by O
a O
ring O
of O
six B-QUANTITY
inches I-QUANTITY
diameter O
  O
a O
cestus O
of O
|
| O
nearly O
double O
the O
span O
had O
often O
gone O
nigh O
to O
suffocate O
her O
plump O
|
| O
companion O
. O
The.throat O
of O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
had O
not O
only O
all O
the O
flexile O
|
| O
length O
of O
the O
swan O
's O
, O
but O
might O
een O
be O
said O
to O
resenble O
that O
of O
the O
|
| O
stork O
ia O
its O
proportions O
  O
while O
the O
head O
of O
Miss B-PERSON
Mlogg I-PERSON
was O
separated O
|
| O
from O
her O
shoulders O
by O
an O
interval O
so O
trifling O
, O
as O
hardly O
to O
be O
percep- O
|
| O
tible O
atall O
. O
The O
hair O
of O
her O
ladyship O
, O
though O
not O
very O
abndant O
, O
|
| O
was O
as O
black O
as O
ink O
, O
and O
its O
straight O
nature O
enabled O
her O
to O
lay O
| | O
it O
in O
|
| O
classic O
ands O
upon O
her O
forehead O
, O
furishing O
a O
graceful O
foundation O
|
| O
for O
the O
wreath O
of O
oak O
lcaves O
with O
whicl O
, O
in O
judicious O
imitation O
of O
|
| O
Domenichino B-GPE
's O
exquisite O
head O
of O
Sappho B-PERSON
, O
she O
usually O
adorned O
herself O
|
| O
when O
in O
full O
dress O
: O
while O
Miss O
MIogg B-PERSON
, O
on O
the O
contrary O
, O
had O
a O
bushy O
|
| O
abundance O
of O
flaxen O
curls O
, O
which O
gavea O
round O
fussy O
sort O
of O
contour O
|
| O
to O
her O
face O
, O
that O
could O
not O
fail O
of O
setting O
off O
to O
advantage O
the O
severer O
|
| O
outline O
of O
the O
noble O
lady O
  O
and O
, O
in O
a O
word O
, O
the O
contrast O
was O
alto- O
|
| O
gether O
perfect O
. O
|
| O
To O
the O
great O
satisfaction O
of O
Lady O
bDowling O
, O
this O
round O
little O
per- O
|
| O
onagc O
arose O
, O
as O
usual O
, O
when O
her O
principal O
rose O
, O
and O
waddled O
to O
the O
|
| O
window O
after O
her O
. O
MIany B-ORG
people O
are O
apt O
to O
overlook O
and O
forget O
|
| O
companions O
, O
and O
the O
poor O
toady O
is O
as O
much O
used O
to O
be O
trod O
upon O
as O
|
| O
the O
despisel O
reptile O
whose O
name O
she O
ears O
. O
But O
if O
the O
world O
in O
|
| O
o O
MICIIAEL O
AMISTRONG O
. O
|
| O
general O
e O
iound O
guilty O
of O
this O
scorn O
towards O
what O
is O
too O
lowly O
to O
|
| O
turn O
, O
and O
scorn O
again O
, O
more O
especially O
was O
our O
kniglt O
liable O
to O
the O
|
| O
weakness O
. O
|
| O
As O
he O
uow O
hastened O
to O
ofer O
his O
hand O
to O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
in O
order O
|
| O
to O
assist O
her O
in O
stepping O
over O
the O
winlow O
- O
sill O
, O
he O
very O
nerly O
over- O
|
| O
trned O
Mliss B-PERSON
Mogg I-PERSON
as O
he O
passed O
her O
  O
but O
heeding O
neithcr O
| | O
the O
re- O
|
| O
sistance O
her O
plump O
person O
offered O
to O
his O
passing O
clbow O
, O
nor O
yet O
the O
|
| O
timid O
ohI O
' O
which O
spoke O
her O
alarm O
, O
he O
hurried O
onward O
, O
and O
, O
|
| O
manfully O
seizing O
the O
hand O
whose O
touch O
was O
honour O
, O
walked O
ot O
|
| O
side O
by O
side O
with O
the O
titled O
lady O
upon O
the O
lawn O
. O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
II I-LAW
. O
|
| O
A O
DELIGITFL O
IAMLILE O
- O
IELNDIII O
AD O
TIIEL O
ISE O
- O
AY O
AD- O
|
| O
VEIUIE O
-- O
DANGEI B-ORG
IND I-ORG
3CAP I-ORG
-- O
GRTITUDE O
AD O
ENEYO O
|
| O
LECE B-ORG
. O
|
| O
OxrY O
see O
that1 B-PERSON
How O
very O
extraordinary O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
exclaimed O
Lady B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
suddenly O
rising O
, O
and O
addressing O
herself O
to O
no O
one O
in O
parti- O
|
| O
cular O
. O
|
| O
Oh1 O
how O
delightful O
. O
'' O
eried O
several O
ladies O
at O
once O
. O
` O
` O
How O
|
| O
clever O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
is1 O
Such O
a O
delicious O
refreshmentt O
'' O
s O
To O
be O
|
| O
sure O
, O
it O
is O
the O
only O
thing O
in O
the O
world O
to O
do O
on O
such O
an O
evening O
|
| O
as O
this O
, O
'' O
exclaimed O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
: O
who O
, O
as O
being O
the O
richest O
|
| O
ong O
lady O
in O
company O
, O
very O
pronerly O
thought O
she O
ought O
to O
speak O
|
| O
first B-ORDINAL
, O
I O
am O
sure O
I O
shall O
follow O
her O
example O
: O
'' O
and O
so O
saying O
, O
she O
|
| O
rose O
and O
walked O
tawards O
the O
window O
. O
Three B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
most O
daunt- O
|
| O
less O
ladies O
in O
the O
party O
started O
up O
to O
follow O
her O
  O
which O
, O
strange O
as O
|
| O
the O
manceuvre O
appeared O
to O
the O
full O
- O
dressed O
Lady B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
she O
did O
|
| O
not O
oppose O
, O
greatly O
preferring O
that O
the O
garden O
party O
should O
be O
|
| O
enlarged O
. O
But O
, O
though O
not O
byher O
, O
the O
adventurous O
fair O
ones O
were O
|
| O
stopped O
before O
they O
accomplished O
their O
lesign O
, O
hy O
a O
chorus O
of O
re- O
|
| O
monstrances O
from O
all O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
company O
, O
male O
and O
female O
. O
|
| O
My O
dear O
Mliss B-PERSON
Broherton I-PERSON
, O
you O
will O
catch O
your O
death O
: O
' O
cried O
|
| O
one O
. O
|
| O
OhI O
look O
at O
. O
your O
satin O
slioes O
1 B-CARDINAL
' O
sereamed O
another O
, O
What O
|
| O
wouId O
Mr. O
Tonkins B-PERSON
say O
if O
he O
was O
here O
, O
Mrs B-PERSON
, O
Tomkins B-PERSON
? O
'' O
demanded O
|
| O
a O
third B-ORDINAL
. O
|
| O
` O
` O
nd O
your O
neck O
and O
shoulders O
, O
MIiss O
Williamson B-PERSON
? O
'' O
whispered O
a O
|
| O
fourth B-ORDINAL
. O
|
| O
` O
` O
And O
your O
blonde O
dress O
, O
Mrs. O
Simpkins B-PERSON
: O
'' O
vociferated O
a O
fiftth O
  O
|
| O
with O
a O
vast O
deal O
more O
in O
the O
same O
strain O
. O
So O
that O
before O
the O
sortie O
|
| O
was O
accomplished O
, O
eery O
lady O
, O
save O
Miss O
Brotherton B-PERSON
, O
yielded O
before O
|
| O
the O
storm O
of O
reasons O
that O
pelted O
- O
them O
on O
all O
sides O
. O
The O
rich O
young O
|
| O
1o B-CARDINAL
|
| O
TE O
LIFE O
AN O
ADVTURES B-NORP
|
| O
laly O
, O
however O
, O
stood O
firm O
: O
what O
` O
young O
lady O
with O
twro B-CARDINAL
hundred I-CARDINAL
|
| I-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
pounds I-CARDINAL
would O
not O
l O
|
| O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
'' O
said O
she O
, O
still O
pursuing O
her O
way O
|
| O
window O
- O
ward O
, O
but O
pausing O
ere O
she O
stepped O
out O
, O
` O
' O
will O
ou O
have O
|
| O
the O
excessive O
kindness,--vraiment O
j'ai B-PERSON
honte I-PERSON
, O
  O
but O
will O
you O
have O
the O
|
| O
charity O
to O
look O
in O
the O
hall O
for O
my O
pink O
satin O
mantelet O
, O
trimmed O
with O
|
| O
swansdown O
  O
without O
it O
I O
fear O
my O
poor O
little O
shoulders O
will O
be O
|
| O
arroses- O
` O
too O
rudely O
, O
alas O
l O
' O
with O
the O
dews O
of O
night B-TIME
, O
'' O
|
| O
Now O
the O
young O
lady O
's O
shoulders O
were O
really O
very O
pretty O
little O
|
| O
shoulders O
, O
and O
, O
moreover O
, O
Mr. O
Augustus B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
, O
notwithstanding O
|
| O
all O
his O
elegant O
nonchalance O
, O
perfectly O
well O
rememhered O
that O
she O
|
| O
had O
twohundred O
thousand O
pounds O
: O
so O
, O
before O
she O
had O
stamped O
with O
|
| O
her O
litle O
foot O
twice O
, O
in O
her O
impatience O
to O
join O
those O
who O
, O
from O
thein B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
gaiety I-ORG
, O
seemed O
to O
be O
so O
greatly O
enjoyiog O
the O
fresh O
air O
, O
he O
returned O
|
| O
with O
the O
mantelet O
, O
and O
having O
, O
as O
usual O
, O
adjusted O
his O
glass O
in O
the O
|
| O
corner O
of O
his O
eye O
to O
prevent O
his O
making O
any O
mistakes O
, O
placed O
it O
on O
|
| O
her O
shoulders O
. O
|
| O
` O
Now O
, O
then O
:1 O
'' O
she O
cried O
, O
` O
` O
give O
me O
your O
arm O
. O
Is O
not O
this O
gool O
|
| O
fun O
? O
|
| O
The O
young O
gentleman O
obeyed O
, O
declaring O
it O
wvas O
deligltful O
, O
and O
in O
|
| O
a O
moment O
they O
were O
beside O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
and O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
: O
good O
|
| O
Miss O
Mlogg B-PERSON
keeping O
a O
step O
or O
twso O
behind O
. O
|
 | O
Nobody O
bu O
your O
ladyship O
had O
wit O
enough O
to O
finl O
out O
that O
|
| O
there O
was O
more O
air O
to O
be O
got O
out O
of O
doors O
than O
in O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
heiress O
, O
|
| O
enturing O
te O
pass O
her O
arm O
through O
that O
of O
her O
noble O
friend O
. O
But O
, O
|
| O
upon O
tlis O
occasion O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
thogh O
particularly O
intimate O
|
| O
with O
Mliss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
, O
and O
seldom O
refusing O
to O
use O
her O
carriage O
and O
|
| O
act O
as O
her O
chaperone O
to O
all O
the O
parties O
in O
the O
neighbourhood O
, O
seemed O
|
| O
inclined O
to O
check O
her O
advances O
. O
|
| O
Miy O
dear O
child O
, O
'' O
said O
she O
, O
I O
am O
elighted O
to O
see O
you O
come O
|
| O
out O
. O
I O
am O
sure O
you O
must O
have O
been O
half B-CARDINAL
stifled O
, O
as O
well O
as O
myself O
. O
|
| O
But O
you O
and O
Mr. O
Augustas B-PERSON
must O
wander O
away O
hy O
yourselves O
, O
and O
|
| O
you O
may O
take O
Mogg B-PERSON
with O
you O
, O
if O
you O
like O
it O
, O
for O
lhave O
just O
got O
into O
|
| O
a O
discussion O
with O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
that O
I O
would O
not O
break O
off O
for O
the O
|
| O
world O
. O
So O
away O
with O
you O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
as O
fast O
as O
you O
can O
. O
'' O
|
| O
ILady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
's I-PERSON
will O
was O
of O
course O
law O
, O
even O
to O
the O
heiress O
, O
but O
|
| O
it O
was O
not O
without O
a O
little O
toss O
of O
the O
head O
that O
she O
turned O
off O
to O
|
| O
another O
walk O
  O
nor O
was O
it O
without O
a O
considerable O
struggle O
between O
|
| O
her O
inclination O
and O
a O
sense O
of O
propriety O
, O
which O
, O
all O
things O
consi- O
|
| O
dered O
, O
really O
did O
her O
honour O
, O
that O
she O
permitted O
poor O
MIiss O
MIogg B-PERSON
|
| O
to O
obey O
the O
hint O
of O
her O
patroness O
, O
and O
follow O
after O
. O
|
| O
` O
' O
And O
so O
you O
really O
have O
not O
seen O
this O
gifted O
young O
man O
yet O
, O
Sir O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
7 I-PERSON
'' I-PERSON
resumed O
her O
ladyship O
, O
as O
soon O
as O
they O
were O
again O
alone O
. O
|
 | O
You O
have O
never O
yet O
seen O
this O
Osmund O
Norcal O
? O
'' O
|
| O
No O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
I O
have O
not O
, O
'' O
replied O
the O
knight O
  O
` O
and O
to O
say O
the O
|
| O
truth O
, O
'' O
headded O
, O
venturing O
to O
press O
with O
his O
stout O
arm O
the O
slender O
|
| O
one O
that O
rested O
on O
it O
, O
` O
` O
to O
say O
the O
truth O
, O
though O
I O
hae O
heard O
a O
|
| O
monstrous O
deal O
about O
him O
, O
I O
was O
determined O
that O
I O
would O
have O
|
| O
notling O
to O
say O
to O
him O
, O
till O
I O
had O
heard O
your O
opinion O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
'' O
|
| O
or O
IICIIAEL O
ARMSTRONG O
. O
|
| O
1I O
|
| O
How O
kind1 O
how O
flattering O
, O
Sir O
Matthew1 O
But O
you O
will O
let O
|
| O
me O
bring O
him O
to O
you O
now O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' I-CARDINAL
|
 | I-CARDINAL
I1 O
I O
? O
'' O
( O
again O
prcessing O
the O
lean O
arm O
. O
) O
| | O
Fancy O
me O
saying O
|
| O
no O
, O
when O
you O
tell O
me O
to O
say O
yesl O
Ahl O
my O
lady O
, O
you O
know O
better O
|
| O
than O
that O
, O
or O
Il B-ORG
am I-ORG
greatly O
mistaken O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
Oh1 O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
you O
are O
always O
so O
kind1 B-ORG
What O
magnificent O
|
| O
gardens O
you O
have1 B-PERSON
IBy O
the O
way O
, O
I O
think O
I O
never O
tasted O
such O
a O
pine O
|
| O
as O
that O
we O
had O
to O
- O
day O
. O
I O
assure O
you O
, O
my O
brother O
, O
Lord O
Highland- O
|
| O
loch O
, O
is O
celebratel O
for O
his O
pines O
- O
quite O
celebrated O
. O
They O
are O
the O
|
| O
finest O
in O
all O
Scotland B-GPE
, O
but O
I O
give O
you O
my O
honour O
, O
I O
never O
saw O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
equal O
to O
it O
athis O
table O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Oh1 O
my O
ladly O
, O
that O
is O
only O
your O
amiable O
condescension O
, O
'' O
repliel O
|
| O
Sir O
Matthe B-PERSON
, O
greatly O
touched O
by O
this O
preference O
. O
| | O
But O
if O
you O
|
| O
really O
can O
be O
so O
polite O
as O
to O
think O
them O
good O
, O
I O
must O
entreat O
you O
|
| O
just O
to O
let O
me O
knock O
at O
the O
head O
- O
gardener O
's O
door O
, O
who O
lives O
close O
|
| O
outside O
this O
gate O
. O
I O
do O
n't O
let O
him O
live O
inside O
, O
because O
of O
his O
|
| O
children O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
. O
I O
know O
what O
birds O
peck O
the O
worst O
- O
ha O
! O
|
| O
ha O
ha1 O
However O
, O
yO B-ORG
must O
just O
let O
me O
pass O
through O
the O
gate O
t O
|
| O
tell O
him O
to O
put O
up O
a O
bracce O
for O
your O
ladyship O
. O
They O
shall O
be O
well O
|
| O
taken O
care O
of O
now O
, O
my O
lady O
, O
trust O
me O
for O
that O
  O
I O
never O
valued O
them O
|
| O
so O
much O
before O
, O
I O
promise O
you O
. O
'' O
|
| O
` O
You O
are O
too O
kind O
a B-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
times O
'' O
said O
the O
lady O
, O
stretching O
|
| O
out O
her O
own O
and O
to O
opon O
the O
gate O
. O
| | O
I O
will O
go O
with O
you O
  O
there O
is O
|
| O
nothing O
I O
doat O
upon O
like O
visising O
a O
gardener O
. O
Could O
he O
not O
take O
|
| O
us O
into O
the O
hot O
- O
houses O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
? O
You O
have O
no O
idea O
how O
I O
|
| O
hould O
enjoy O
it O
. O
'' O
|
| O
By O
no O
means O
displeased O
to O
show O
off O
tha O
high O
- O
born O
lady O
upon O
his O
|
| O
arm O
, O
even O
to O
the O
eyes O
of O
his O
gardener O
, O
the O
knight O
joyfully O
assentel O
|
| O
to O
the O
proposal O
. O
|
| O
Macnab O
I O
' O
he O
cried O
, O
knocking O
as O
he O
passed O
the O
cottage O
- O
wia- O
|
| O
dow O
, O
| | O
Macnabl O
come O
here O
directly O
, O
and O
bring O
a O
knife O
and O
a O
|
| O
basket O
with O
you O
: O
you O
must O
come O
directly O
- O
this O
very O
moment O
, O
and O
|
| O
unlock O
the O
hot O
- O
houses O
- O
her O
ladyship O
wishes O
to O
walk O
through O
them O
, O
|
| O
and O
I O
must O
have O
one B-CARDINAL
or O
two B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
finest O
pines O
cut O
, O
and O
packed O
in O
a O
|
| O
basket O
, O
to O
be O
put O
into O
Mliss B-PERSON
Brotherton I-PERSON
's O
carriage O
: O
but O
mind O
, O
they O
|
| O
are O
for O
Lady O
Clarissa O
Shrimpton O
: O
so O
you O
had O
better O
give O
them O
in O
|
| O
charge O
to O
her O
ladyship O
's O
own O
man O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Mr. O
Alexander B-PERSON
Macnab I-PERSON
promptly O
left O
the O
seeds O
he O
was O
sortiag B-ORG
, O
|
| O
anl O
prepared O
himself O
, O
basket O
in O
hand O
, O
to O
follow O
his O
master O
. O
The O
|
| O
knight O
and O
the O
lady O
left O
the O
cottage O
, O
arm O
- O
and O
- O
arm O
togcther O
  O
but O
|
| O
before O
they O
again O
enterel O
the O
garden O
, O
a O
fancy O
seized O
her O
lively O
lady- O
|
| O
ship O
, O
that O
a O
short O
ramble O
in O
the O
green O
lane O
outside O
it O
would O
be O
the O
|
| O
most O
agreeable O
thing O
in O
the O
world O
. O
|
| O
` O
Dcarnel B-ORG
what O
a O
poetical O
idea O
: O
'' O
exclaimed O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
with O
|
| O
enthusiasm O
. O
| | O
There O
's O
only B-CARDINAL
one I-CARDINAL
thing O
, O
'' O
he O
said O
, O
stopping O
short O
, O
|
| O
` O
` O
but O
that O
will O
spoil O
my O
pleasure O
altogether O
: O
I O
am O
so O
dreadtiully O
afraid O
|
| O
that O
your O
ladyship O
will O
take O
eold O
. O
'' O
|
| O
` O
Ask O
the O
gardener O
's O
wife O
to O
lend O
me O
one O
ofr O
her O
kerchiefs O
, O
'' O
sail O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
But O
t O
yill O
only O
be O
to O
satisy B-PERSON
yo I-PERSON
, O
Sis O
|
| O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
for O
there O
is O
no O
catching O
cold O
in O
such O
weather O
as O
this O
. O
'' O
|
| O
1 B-CARDINAL
g O
|
| O
HE O
LIFE O
AND O
ADYETDRES O
|
| O
It O
was O
with O
something O
quite O
iike O
tender O
anxiety O
that O
the O
knight O
|
| O
stepped O
back O
, O
asked O
for O
nnd O
obtained O
a O
neat O
shawl O
, O
and O
himself O
|
| O
wrapped O
it O
round O
the O
slender O
person O
of O
his O
amiable O
companion O
. O
|
 | O
Thank O
youl O
thank O
you O
a O
thousand B-CARDINAL
times O
: O
But O
, O
dear O
Sir O
Mat- O
|
| O
thew O
, O
1 O
must O
not O
lose O
my O
pines O
by O
my O
frolic O
: O
will O
you O
give O
the O
gar- O
|
| O
dener O
orders O
to O
get O
them O
without O
waiting O
for O
us O
? O
and O
perhaps O
y O
|
| O
would O
let O
him O
put O
up O
a O
bunch O
of O
granes O
, O
and O
a O
few O
peaches O
at O
the O
|
| O
same O
time O
- O
it O
is O
no O
god O
to O
let O
him O
wait O
for O
us O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
  O
--when O
|
| O
you O
and O
I O
get O
intno O
a O
chat O
together O
, O
we O
shali O
neither O
of O
us O
think O
of O
|
| O
the O
pines O
again O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Quitting O
her O
highly O
- O
valued O
aristocratiec O
arm O
for O
an O
instant O
, O
the O
|
| O
flattered O
knight O
ran O
back O
and O
gave O
the O
necessary O
orders O
: O
and O
then O
, O
|
| O
almost O
unconscious O
, O
in O
his O
full O
contentment O
, O
that O
his O
own O
gray O
head O
|
| O
was O
as O
bare O
as O
that O
of O
the O
oak O
- O
crowned O
nymph O
by O
his O
side O
, O
he O
re- O
|
| O
turued O
tohis O
bewitching O
companion O
and O
led O
her O
gently O
onward O
over O
|
| O
the O
mossy O
turf O
that O
bordered O
the O
road O
. O
|
| O
The O
gardener O
and O
his O
wife O
stood O
cgether O
for O
a O
moment O
looking O
|
| O
after O
them O
. O
e O
Who O
would O
think O
now O
that O
she O
was O
one O
of O
the O
true O
|
| O
old O
gentlefolks O
, O
and O
Scotch B-GPE
to O
boot O
, O
to O
scee O
her O
pair O
off O
that O
way O
with O
|
| O
our O
rogue O
of O
a O
spinner O
there O
? O
How O
, O
in O
God O
's O
name O
, O
can O
she O
choose O
to O
|
| O
be O
so O
free O
and O
friendly O
with O
such O
as O
he O
? O
'' O
said O
the O
garlenen O
|
 | O
Just O
for O
the O
same O
reason O
as O
yourself O
, O
Sawny B-PERSON
, O
'' O
replied O
his O
wife O
  O
|
 | O
to O
get O
nll O
she O
can O
out O
of O
him O
. O
'' O
|
| O
' O
And O
that O
's O
true O
, O
'' O
replied O
Sawny B-PRODUCT
, O
setting O
off O
upon O
his O
business O
. O
|
| O
I O
had O
like O
to O
forget O
the O
pines O
, O
and O
the O
grapes O
, O
and O
the O
peaches O
. O
|
| O
She O
's O
not O
so O
far O
wrong O
after O
all O
  O
and O
yet O
' O
tis O
a O
pity O
, O
too O
. O
'' O
|
| O
The O
evening B-TIME
was O
still O
oppressively O
sultry O
, O
and O
hardly O
a O
breath O
of O
|
| O
air O
disturbed O
either O
the O
leaves O
on O
the O
oaks O
beside O
the O
road O
, O
or O
those O
|
| O
that O
mimicked O
them O
so O
abominably O
on O
the O
lady O
's O
brow O
  O
but O
, O
never- O
|
| O
theless O
, O
there O
was O
a O
freshness O
in O
the O
smell O
of O
the O
hedges O
and O
the O
grass O
, O
|
| O
which O
could O
not O
fail O
to O
be O
agreeable O
to O
any O
nerves O
that O
had O
endured O
|
| O
the O
steaming O
dinner O
, O
and O
the O
irksome O
drawing O
- O
room O
of O
Dowling B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Lodge I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Ihe I-ORG
shady O
lane O
in O
which O
the O
knight O
and O
the O
lady O
were O
thus O
re- O
|
| O
creating O
themselves O
, O
after O
skirting O
the O
extensive O
and O
lofty O
walls O
of O
|
| O
the O
garlen O
, O
turned O
at O
right O
angles O
both O
to O
the O
right O
and O
the O
left O
at O
|
| O
the O
corner O
of O
it O
. O
The O
branch O
to O
the O
loft O
followed O
the O
boundary O
of O
|
| O
the O
garden O
, O
and O
led O
to O
the O
stable O
- O
yard O
and O
back O
entrance O
to O
the O
|
| O
house O
  O
that O
to O
the O
right O
cbnducted O
to O
the O
factory O
, O
which O
was O
the O
|
| O
source O
and O
head O
- O
spring O
of O
All O
the O
wealth O
that O
flowed O
over O
, O
and O
irri- O
|
| O
gatel O
with O
its O
fructilying O
stream O
, O
meadows O
, O
parks O
, O
hot O
- O
beds O
and O
|
| O
lower O
- O
gardens O
, O
till O
it O
made O
itself O
a O
prodigious O
cistem O
in O
the O
depths O
|
| O
and O
heights O
of O
Dowling O
edge O
. O
|
| O
When O
the O
strangely O
- O
matched O
pair O
came O
to O
this O
point O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
|
| O
made O
a O
halt O
, O
till O
lady O
Cluarissa B-GPE
came O
to O
the O
end O
of O
a O
little O
poem O
, O
|
| O
which O
the O
protege O
whom O
she O
was O
so O
desirous O
of O
introducing O
to O
her O
|
| O
rich O
and O
( O
to O
use O
her O
own O
words O
) O
` O
` O
really O
very O
clever O
friend O
, O
'' O
had O
in- O
|
| O
scribed O
in O
her O
album O
. O
|
| O
Nothing O
could O
be O
more O
agreenable O
toher O
ladyship O
than O
this O
pause O
. O
|
| O
oR O
IIICIIAEL O
ARISTRONG O
. O
|
| O
13 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
In O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
place O
it O
was O
the O
greatest O
possible O
relief O
to O
her O
lung6 O
, O
for O
|
| O
the O
lines O
she O
was O
reciting O
were O
much O
too O
full O
of O
icep O
feeling O
to O
be O
|
| O
repeated O
without O
a O
pninful O
effort O
, O
wliile O
walking O
  O
and O
in O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
, O
|
| O
the O
halt O
, O
accompanied O
as O
it O
was O
by O
a O
look O
of O
earuest O
attention O
from O
|
| O
her O
apparently O
- O
delighted O
companion O
, O
furnished O
the O
most O
agreeable O
|
| O
commentary O
in O
the O
world O
upon O
the O
poem O
itself O
, O
as O
well O
as O
on O
her O
|
| O
manner O
of O
reciting O
it O
. O
|
| O
It O
suaid O
so O
plainly O
, O
` O
` O
tay O
-move O
not O
l O
- O
lest O
a O
word O
, O
an O
intona- O
|
| O
tion O
, O
a O
cadence O
, O
be O
lost O
to O
me O
: O
'' O
|
| O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
was O
rcally O
touched O
by O
it O
  O
and O
let O
Sawny B-PERSON
the O
gar- O
|
| O
dener O
, O
and O
his O
wife O
Janet B-PERSON
, O
say O
or O
think O
what O
they O
would O
, O
neither O
|
| O
peaches O
nor O
pines O
had O
any O
thing O
to O
do O
with O
the O
gratification O
she O
at O
|
| O
this O
moment O
experienced O
in O
the O
society O
of O
the O
great O
manufacturer O
. O
|
| O
Ilis B-NORP
cyes O
were O
fixcd O
on O
her O
face O
, O
and O
she O
bore O
the O
gaze O
, O
and O
|
| O
returned O
it O
with O
that O
sort O
of O
courage O
and O
confidence O
, O
which O
genuine O
|
| O
enthusiasm O
alone O
can O
gte O
|
| O
She O
had O
just O
finished O
a O
stanza O
when O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
ceased O
to O
move O
, O
|
| O
and O
feeling O
that O
he O
did O
so O
under O
the O
intluence O
of O
a O
spell O
, O
which O
she O
|
| O
well O
knew O
would O
be O
morc O
powerful O
still O
were O
it O
spoken O
when O
she O
|
| O
ere O
at O
rcst O
- O
for O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
was O
aware O
that O
she O
was O
exceedingly O
|
| O
short O
- O
breathed O
- O
she O
repeated O
the O
last O
eight B-CARDINAL
lines O
in O
a O
manner O
that O
|
| O
showed O
she O
felt O
the O
pleasure O
she O
was O
producing O
- O
a O
pleasure O
, O
as O
she O
|
| O
thought O
, O
like O
that O
occasionally O
causcd O
by O
the O
repetition O
of O
some O
|
| O
delicious O
phrase O
in O
a O
musical O
composition O
, O
reiterated O
as O
if O
to O
fll O
the O
|
| O
soul O
with O
its O
sweetness O
. O
|
| O
` O
And O
should O
the O
eye O
for O
whieh O
I O
write O
|
| O
y O
sun O
- O
lit O
morn O
, O
ar O
moon O
- O
lit O
night O
, O
|
| O
Drop B-PERSON
on O
this O
record O
of O
iy O
soul O
|
| O
Whieh B-PERSON
tells O
a O
part O
- O
ahl O
not O
the O
whole O
, O
|
| O
Of O
hones O
that O
trembliag O
. O
fltering O
. O
imid O
, O
|
| O
Now O
re O
my O
cheek O
. O
now O
turn O
it O
liid,.- O
|
| O
hould O
thast O
soft O
eye O
but O
droep O
one B-CARDINAL
tear O
, O
|
| O
I O
d O
hug O
my O
chain O
, O
and O
cnll O
it O
dearl B-PERSON
'' O
|
| O
The O
tear O
askced O
for O
, O
almost O
came O
as O
she O
ceased O
. O
|
 | O
You O
feel O
it O
, O
dear O
Sir O
hatthewI B-PERSON
'' O
she O
said O
, O
in O
a O
voice O
of O
consider- O
|
| O
able O
emotion O
. O
|
| O
d O
hug O
my O
chain O
, O
and O
call O
it O
dear1''-she O
again O
murmurel O
, O
|
| O
hanging O
on O
his O
arm O
with O
such O
an O
evident O
degree O
of O
weakness O
, O
as O
|
| O
showed O
the O
slender O
form O
to O
be O
less O
powerful O
than O
the O
ardent O
spirit O
|
| O
it O
enshrined O
. O
|
| O
Let O
us O
turn O
bnaek O
, O
'' O
said O
Sir O
Mathew B-PERSON
. O
| | O
My O
dear O
friend O
, O
'' O
|
| O
faintl O
ejaculated O
ady O
Clarissa B-ORG
, O
` O
` O
you O
are O
moved O
too O
strongly-- O
|
| O
But O
- O
no O
, O
no O
: O
Sir O
MatthewI O
bBelieve O
me O
, O
it O
were O
far O
better O
for O
both O
|
| O
of O
us O
that O
we O
should O
proceed.-Are O
we O
, O
cither O
of O
us O
, O
. O
my O
dear O
friend O
, O
|
| O
in O
a O
state O
at O
thismoment O
to O
meet O
the O
curious O
stare O
of O
idle O
eyesl-- B-PERSON
|
| O
Come O
on O
, O
dear O
Sir O
Mnatthe''-and O
she O
gently O
pulled O
him O
forwvard O
|
| O
as O
she O
spoke- O
` O
` O
this O
sott O
glade O
invites O
us O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Though O
pertfectly O
determined O
to O
find O
some O
excuse O
for O
not O
leading O
|
| O
his O
fascinating O
companion O
within O
sight O
of O
his O
grim O
- O
looking O
factory O
, O
|
| O
which O
unother O
turn O
in O
the O
lane O
at O
no O
great O
distance O
would O
have O
|
| O
made O
very O
unpicturesquely O
vyisible O
, O
it O
was O
impossible O
at O
that O
moment O
|

| O
o O
IICiAE B-GPE
. O
ARDMISTRONG O
. O
|
| O
15s B-DATE
|
| O
The O
youngest O
, O
but O
by O
far O
the O
stoutest O
and O
tallest O
of O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
boys O
, O
|
| O
instantly O
obeyed O
this O
command O
, O
and O
placing O
himself O
midway O
be- O
|
| O
tween O
the O
tormented O
cow O
and O
the O
fair O
creature O
, O
whose O
nerves O
her O
|
| O
menacing O
attitude O
had O
so O
cruelly O
shaken O
, O
he O
stood O
manfully O
astride O
|
| O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
te O
lane O
, O
flourished O
his O
ragged O
hat O
on O
high O
, O
and O
|
| O
with O
a O
few O
lusty O
` O
` O
wough1 B-WORK_OF_ART
woughsI O
'' O
repeated O
at O
the O
top O
of O
his O
|
| O
yeng B-PERSON
voice O
, O
succeeded O
in O
turning O
the O
front O
of O
the O
enemy O
, O
which O
|
| O
was O
presently O
seen O
to O
wheel O
round O
, O
and O
, O
by O
a O
sort O
of O
feeble O
, O
ambling O
|
| O
little O
trot O
, O
speedily O
got O
out O
of O
sight O
round O
the O
corner O
. O
|
 | O
Now O
, O
then O
, O
'' O
said O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
` O
` O
let O
me O
leal O
you O
hoeme O
, O
my O
dear O
|
| O
ladyi O
' O
|
 | O
Not O
till O
I O
have O
thanked O
my O
little O
dliverer O
, O
'' O
exclaimed O
Lady B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
with O
very O
sentimental O
fervour O
. O
e O
Good O
heaven O
what O
|
| O
might O
have O
been O
my O
fate O
without O
him O
t O
I O
know O
- O
I O
feel O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
that O
you O
never O
could O
have O
borne O
to O
leave O
me O
, O
and O
what O
then O
could O
|
| O
have O
stopped O
the O
fearful O
approach O
of O
that O
most O
vicious O
animal?- O
|
| O
Death O
, O
or O
worse O
than O
death O
- O
dislocation O
of O
limb O
, O
disfigurement O
of O
|
| O
featuro O
: O
Oh O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
your O
heart O
, O
I O
know O
, O
will O
go O
side O
by O
side O
|
| O
with O
mine O
. O
Tell O
me O
, O
what O
can O
I O
do O
- O
what O
can O
we O
both O
do O
, O
to O
reward O
|
| O
the O
astonishing O
bravery O
of O
that O
noble O
little O
fellow O
? O
|
| O
Depend O
upon O
it O
, O
my O
laly O
, O
he O
will O
he O
delighted O
if O
you O
will O
give O
|
| O
him O
sixpeuce O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
Sixpence O
1 O
'' O
cried O
her O
lalyship O
, O
turning O
extremely O
red,-but O
in O
a O
|
| O
moment O
she O
recovered O
herself O
and O
said O
: O
` O
' O
Oh1 O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
: O
do O
Inot O
|
| O
know O
how O
dearly O
you O
love O
a O
jest O
? O
Men O
of O
witand O
humour O
can O
rarely O
|
| O
be O
grave O
for O
long O
together O
, O
even O
under O
circumstances O
that O
most O
keenly O
|
| O
touch O
their O
feelings O
  O
did O
I O
not O
know O
you O
well O
, O
my O
friend O
, O
what O
|
| O
should O
I O
not O
think O
of O
your O
proposul O
But O
come O
, O
come O
- O
be O
serious O
|
| O
for O
a O
moment O
longer O
: O
we O
have O
, O
it O
is O
true O
, O
escaped O
a O
tremendous O
|
| O
danger O
, O
and O
it O
may O
well O
make O
us O
feel O
light O
at O
heart O
: O
but O
we O
will O
not O
|
| O
laugh O
over O
it O
, O
till O
we O
have O
settlod O
in O
what O
way O
that O
heroic O
child O
|
| O
shall O
receive O
the O
meed O
he O
has O
eamned O
. O
I O
shall O
not O
rest O
in O
pece B-GPE
, O
my O
|
| O
friend O
, O
unless O
his O
destiny O
be O
as O
faoirably O
influenced O
by O
me O
, O
as O
|
| O
mine O
has O
probably O
been O
by O
him O
. O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
you O
have O
great O
|
| O
power O
, O
enormous O
wealth O
, O
a O
generous O
heart O
, O
a O
noble O
nature O
, O
and O
in- O
|
| O
tellect O
, O
before O
whieh O
, O
if O
I O
mistake O
not O
, O
all O
difficulties O
will O
melt O
away O
|
| O
like O
a O
mist O
before O
the O
sun O
. O
Of O
all O
this O
I O
am O
quite O
certain O
. O
There O
|
| O
is O
but O
one B-CARDINAL
r O
in O
the O
business O
. O
Ir O
you O
value O
me O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
, O
as O
much O
|
| O
as O
I O
think O
you O
do O
, O
that O
little O
boy O
now O
getting O
over O
the O
gate O
will O
bo O
|
| O
clothed O
, O
educated O
, O
fed B-ORG
, O
lodged O
by O
you O
. O
Do O
I O
deceive O
myself O
' O
? O
or O
will O
|
| O
the O
daily O
sight O
of O
him O
, O
by O
renewing O
the O
memory O
of O
this B-TIME
evening I-TIME
, O
|
| O
rather O
cause O
you O
pleasure O
than O
pain O
? O
'' O
|
| O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
Dowling I-PERSON
clearly O
saw O
, O
that O
sending O
` O
` O
the O
little O
black- O
. O
|
| O
guard O
to O
the O
deil O
, O
'' O
which O
was O
decidedly O
what O
his O
heart O
whispered O
|
| O
to O
him O
, O
would O
, O
at O
this O
stage O
of O
the O
business O
, O
he O
inevitably O
sending O
|
| O
her O
sentimental O
ladyship O
to O
at O
least O
an O
equal O
distance O
from O
himself O
  O
|
| O
and O
this O
he O
had O
no O
inelination O
to O
do O
. O
She O
ws O
the O
only O
Lady B-PERSON
Some- I-PERSON
|
| O
body O
Something B-GPE
in O
the O
whole O
neighbourhood O
, O
and O
he O
was O
quite O
aware O
|
| O
that O
he O
had O
already O
acquired O
more O
envy O
and O
hatred O
among O
his O
|
| O
friends O
and O
neighbours O
, O
by O
the O
superior O
degree O
of O
intimacy O
he O
had O
|
| O
16 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
TB B-ORG
LIFE I-ORG
AND O
ADVETRES O
|
| O
contrived O
to O
achieve O
with O
her O
, O
than O
by O
all O
his O
successful O
struggles O
|
| O
to O
outspend O
them O
all O
. O
|
| O
This O
pleasure O
was O
not O
to O
be O
given O
up O
for O
a O
trifle O
, O
especially O
at O
a O
|
| O
moment O
wrhen O
it O
seemed O
so O
very O
clear O
that O
it O
only O
denended O
on O
him- O
|
| O
self O
to O
make O
all O
the O
world O
percoive O
that O
they O
were O
dearer O
friends O
|
| O
than O
ever O
  O
so O
, O
making O
a O
virtue O
of O
necessity O
, O
he O
looked O
in O
her O
face O
|
| O
with O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
wittiest O
smiles O
, O
and O
cleverly O
taking O
the O
cue O
she O
had O
|
| O
given O
, O
repliced O
-- O
y O
1f B-CARDINAL
you O
had O
ot O
found O
out O
that O
I O
was O
jesting O
with O
|
| O
you O
, O
ILady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
I O
neer O
, O
should O
have O
believed O
in O
your O
fricndship O
|
| O
more O
: O
Come O
here O
, O
my O
boy O
, O
'' O
he O
continued O
, O
raising O
his O
ioud O
voice O
to O
|
| O
a O
note O
that O
must O
have O
been O
heard O
as O
far O
as O
the O
factory O
, O
` O
come O
here O
, O
|
| O
1I O
say O
. O
' O
|
| O
The O
little O
fellow O
, O
on O
hearing O
these O
imperative O
accents O
, O
which O
were O
|
| O
not O
quite O
unknown O
to O
him O
, O
thought O
this O
was O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
he O
had O
|
| O
been O
so O
greatly O
honoured O
as O
to O
have O
them O
addressed O
to O
himsclf O
, O
|
| O
again O
let O
go O
the O
hand O
of O
his O
brother O
, O
by O
whose O
side O
he O
had O
begun O
to O
|
| O
resume O
his O
progress O
homeward O
, O
and O
once O
more O
clambering O
over O
|
| O
the O
gatc O
presented O
himself O
, O
cap O
in O
hand O
, O
before O
the O
illustcious O
|
| O
pair O
. O
|
 | O
You O
are O
a O
happy O
little O
boy O
, O
'' O
said O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
` O
` O
in O
having O
had O
|
| O
the O
extraordinary O
good O
fortunc O
of O
looking O
over O
yonder O
gate O
at O
the O
|
| O
moment O
you O
did O
  O
and O
you O
are O
a O
brave O
little O
fellow O
into O
the O
bargain O
|
| O
for O
not O
running O
away O
, O
as O
you O
certainly O
might O
have O
done O
, O
when O
you O
|
| O
saw O
.that O
dreadful O
east O
. O
Oh O
I O
thosc O
tremendous O
horns O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
1 I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
tley I-PERSON
haunt O
me O
still O
| | O
I O
am O
quite O
sure O
it O
will O
be O
weeks B-DATE
before O
I O
lay O
|
| O
my O
head O
on O
my O
pillow O
without O
dreaming O
of O
them O
. O
But O
you O
droe O
|
| O
them O
away O
, O
my O
deatr O
child O
, O
and O
as O
a O
reward O
for O
it O
, O
you O
shall O
be O
com- O
|
| O
fortably O
clothed O
and O
fed B-ORG
for O
the O
rest O
of O
your O
life O
. O
You O
will O
like O
that O
, O
|
| O
wo O
n't O
you O
? O
'' O
|
| O
I O
should O
very O
much O
like O
never O
to O
go O
to O
work O
at O
the O
factory O
any O
|
| O
more O
, O
'' O
repliced O
the O
child O
  O
` O
hut O
, O
please O
ma'am O
, O
'' O
he O
added O
the O
mdinute O
|
| O
after O
, O
` O
I O
'd O
sooner O
you O
'd O
clothe O
and O
feed O
Teddy B-PERSON
than O
me O
. O
He O
looked O
|
| O
ovor O
the O
gate O
first B-ORDINAL
, O
please O
ma'am O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
Did O
he O
, O
my O
dear7 O
Then O
that O
is O
another O
reason O
why O
this O
good O
|
| O
gentleman O
's O
favour O
should O
be O
shown O
to O
you O
: O
for O
if O
your O
brother O
saw O
|
| O
my O
distress O
first B-ORDINAL
, O
it O
was O
yon O
who O
were O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
to O
relieve O
it O
, O
'' O
|
| O
: O
That O
was O
only O
because O
Teddy B-PERSON
is O
so O
lame O
, O
please O
ma'am O
, O
'' O
said O
|
| O
the O
boy O
. O
|
| O
Lame O
, O
is O
he O
? O
'' O
repeated O
her O
lalyship O
, O
' O
Poor O
fellow O
t1 O
However O
, O
|
| O
my O
littlc O
man O
, O
if O
I O
do O
not O
greatly O
mistake O
, O
yo O
have O
this B-DATE
day I-DATE
made O
|
| O
a O
tfriend O
by O
serving O
me O
, O
who O
will O
put O
you O
in O
a O
situation O
where O
, O
if O
you O
|
| O
behave O
well O
, O
you O
will O
be O
able O
to O
assist O
all O
vho O
belong O
to O
you O
. O
'' O
|
| O
The O
child O
opened O
a O
pair O
of O
remarkabl O
large O
cycs O
, O
and O
fixing O
|
| O
them O
on O
her O
face O
, O
said O
, O
| | O
What1 B-PERSON
mother O
and O
all O
e O
' O
|
| O
Yes O
, O
I O
should O
think O
so O
, O
my O
dear O
. O
IIe O
is O
a O
fine O
intelligent O
look- O
|
| O
ing O
liutle O
fellow O
, O
is O
he O
not O
, O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
? O
But O
he O
does O
not O
look O
|
| O
healthy O
. O
Howcver O
, O
I O
dare O
say O
he O
will O
imnrove O
in O
that O
respect O
. O
|
| O
Plenty O
of O
food O
generally O
cures O
all O
poor O
people O
's O
complaints O
, O
par- O
|
| O
ticularly O
when O
they O
are O
young O
. O
How O
old O
are O
you O
, O
my O
dear O
? O
'' O
|
| O
Nine B-CARDINAL
last O
birthday O
, O
'' O
replied O
the O
boy O
. O
|
| O
oy O
MIICHRAL O
AISTOG B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
11 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
A O
tall O
liutle O
fellow O
for O
his O
age O
, O
though O
very O
thin O
, O
to O
be O
sure O
. O
|
| O
And O
what O
is O
your O
name O
? O
'' O
|
| O
: O
Michael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
, O
ma'am O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Micehael B-PERSON
Armstrong I-PERSON
: O
Ishall O
not O
forget O
it O
, O
I O
assure O
you O
: O
for O
truly O
|
| O
do O
I O
believe O
that O
I O
should O
hae O
been O
trampled O
in O
the O
dust O
by O
this O
|
| O
time O
, O
if O
you O
had O
not O
been O
heart O
- O
strong O
as O
well O
as O
Armstrong B-PERSON
. O
And O
|
| O
what O
shall O
we O
do O
with O
him O
at O
first B-ORDINAL
  O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
? O
Shall O
we O
take O
|
| O
him O
home O
with O
us O
? O
' O
|
 | O
WVhat O
: O
to O
your O
cottage O
, O
my O
dear O
lady O
2 B-CARDINAL
- O
Yes O
, O
certainly O
, O
if O
it O
|
| O
will O
give O
you O
plcasure O
. O
'' O
|
| O
My O
dearest O
Sir O
Matthew1 O
there O
you O
are O
at O
your O
jestings O
|
| O
again O
. O
'' O
|
| O
HaI B-LOC
hal O
ha1 O
Lady B-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
, O
you O
begin O
to O
know O
me O
so O
well O
, O
|
| O
that O
I O
shall O
never O
be O
able O
to O
cut O
my O
little O
dry O
jokes O
upen O
you O
, O
'' O
re- O
|
| O
plied O
the O
knight O
laughing O
, O
as O
it O
seemed O
, O
most O
heartily O
, O
but O
inwvardly O
|
| O
cursing O
the O
audacious O
exaction O
of O
his O
fuir O
friend O
, O
in O
attempting O
to O
|
| O
make O
him O
pay O
the O
enormous O
price O
she O
hinted O
at O
, O
for O
permitting O
him O
|
| O
to O
enjoy O
the O
honour O
and O
glory O
of O
flirting O
with O
her O
. O
The O
idea O
of O
|
| O
being O
thus O
entrapped O
, O
and O
forced O
to O
adopt O
` O
` O
ua O
bag O
of O
rags O
out O
af O
|
| O
his O
own O
fsctory O
'' O
( O
for O
it O
was O
thus O
he O
inwardly O
designtel O
little O
|
| O
Michael B-PERSON
) O
, O
galled O
him O
for O
a O
moment O
so O
severely O
, O
that O
he O
was O
within O
an O
|
| O
ace O
of O
exclaiming O
, O
` O
Confound O
yo O
, O
and O
the O
eggar O
's O
brat O
together O
, O
|
| O
you O
old O
fool O
? O
'' O
Bnt B-ORG
, O
most O
fortunatelyfor O
all O
parties O
, O
helid O
no O
such O
|
| O
thing O
: O
on O
the O
contrary O
, O
he O
happily O
remembered O
at O
that O
critical O
|
| O
momcnt O
the O
important O
hints O
he O
had O
received O
from O
his O
cxcellent O
|
| O
friend O
Dr. O
Crockley B-PERSON
, O
and O
instantly O
decided O
` O
' O
` O
that O
this O
absurd O
whim O
|
| O
of O
her O
ladyship O
's O
should O
be O
worked O
up O
iuto O
the O
d O
- O
d O
good O
- O
natutred O
|
| O
thing O
that O
was O
to O
set O
all O
right O
. O
'' O
|
| O
At O
the O
very O
same O
moment O
, O
as O
if O
to O
confirm O
his O
resolution O
, O
Lady B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Clarissa I-PERSON
rew O
from O
her O
pocket O
a O
cambric O
pocket O
- O
handkerchief O
, O
|
| O
somcthing O
the O
worse O
for O
wcar O
, O
perhaps O
, O
but O
most O
elaborately O
em- O
|
| O
broidered O
at O
each O
corner O
with O
the O
cnronet O
of O
a O
countess O
, O
lt O
was O
|
| O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
a O
dozen O
bequenthed O
to O
her O
a B-DATE
few I-DATE
years I-DATE
before O
by O
her O
thrifty O
|
| O
and O
truly O
admirable O
mother O
, O
the O
late O
Countess O
of O
Ilighlandloch B-GPE
. O
|
| O
This O
coincidence O
appeared O
to O
be O
the O
work O
of O
Providence B-GPE
. O
|
| O
Give O
me O
your O
arm O
, O
my O
charming O
friend O
I O
'' O
said O
the O
well O
- O
satisfied O
|
| O
kniglt O
, O
with O
an O
air O
of O
tender O
gallantry O
, O
` O
` O
and O
only O
remember O
, O
that O
|
| O
all O
1 B-CARDINAL
shall O
do O
in O
this O
busines O
, O
will O
proceed O
wholly O
from O
my O
devoted O
|
| O
friendship O
to O
you O
. O
Follow O
us O
, O
little O
oy O
, O
and O
you O
shall O
learn O
what O
|
| O
it O
is O
to O
have O
served O
Sir O
Matthew B-PERSON
