| 

| O
Bodleian O
Libraries O
|

| O
UNIVERSITY O
OF O
OXFORD O
|

| O
This O
book O
is O
part O
of O
the O
collection O
held O
by O
the O
Bodleian O
Libraries O
|
| O
and O
scanned O
by O
Google B-ORG
, I-ORG
Inc. I-ORG
for O
the B-ORG
Google I-ORG
Books I-ORG
Library I-ORG
Project I-ORG
. O
|

| O
For O
more O
information O
see O
: O
|

| O
http://www O
. O
bodleian.ox.ac.uk/dbooks O
|

| O
hee O
|

 

 

 

 

| O
bingtt B-PERSON
fom I-PERSON
h I-PERSON
Chote I-PERSON
Artem I-PERSON
[ O
422- B-ORG
. O
|

| O
i O
gS O
) O
Rate O
sent O
|
| O
? O
|

| O
G5 B-PERSON
ese I-PERSON
VIR I-PERSON
|




 

| I-PERSON
Sila I-PERSON
unaided O
, O
A O
loth O
om O
ently O
Sha B-PERSON
’ O
|

 

 

| O
A O
Asvel B-GPE
without O
a O
Here O
. O
|

| O
PY O
|

| O
WILLIAM O
MAKEPEACE O
THACKERAY O
. O
|

 

 

| O
oat O
|
| O
Chu O
Z O
|

| O
=) O
|

| O
GH O
: O
oe O
|

| O
7 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
Wotiox O
wewarded O
, O
A O
berth O
in O
3 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
A O
Povel O
without O
a O
Bers O
. O
|

| O
WILLIAM O
MAKEPEACE O
THACKERAY O
. O
|

 


 

| O
A O
Dovel B-PERSON
without O
a O
Hers O
, O
|

| O
WILLIAM O
MAKEPEACE O
@HACGCKERAY O
. O
|

 

 

 

 

| O
Bung B-PERSON
it O
fm O
hk O
. O
Ctbutern B-PERSON
Artem I-PERSON
[ O
i22 O
. O
|

| O
i O
patechi B-PERSON
( O
Ce O
a8 O
|
| O
~ O
|
| O
P O
|

| O
ast O
-@s O
Wya24 B-GPE
|




| O
— O
— O
ELLE O
|

 

| O
ZG O
|

| O
Vanity O
Catt O
’ O
|

| O
A. O
|

| O
Uetoe O
: O
rewarded O
, O
4 B-CARDINAL
fecth O
. O
he O
|

 

| O
A O
Asvel B-GPE
without O
.a O
Here O
. O
|

| O
PY O
|

| O
WILLIAM O
MAKEPEACE O
@HACKERAY O
. O
|

 


| O
VANITY B-ORG
FAIR I-ORG
. O
|

| O
A O
Nobel B-WORK_OF_ART
without O
a O
Mero B-PERSON
. O
|

| O
BY O
|

| O
WILLIAM O
MAKEPEACE O
THACKERAY O
. O
|

| O
WITH O
ILLUSTRATIONS O
ON O
STEEL O
AND O
WOOD O
BY O
THE O
AUTHOR O
. O
|

| O
LONDON B-GPE
: O
|
| O
BRADBURY B-ORG
AND I-ORG
EVANS I-ORG
, O
11 B-DATE
, O
BOUVERIE B-ORG
STREET O
. O
|
| O
1849 B-DATE
, O
|

 

| O
LONDON B-GPE
: O
|
| O
BRADEURY B-ORG
AND O
EVANS O
, O
PRINTERS O
, O
WHITBRRIARS O
. O
|

| O
To O
|

| O
B. B-PERSON
W. I-PERSON
PROCTER I-PERSON
|

| O
THIS O
STORY O
IS O
AFFECTIONATELY B-ORG
DEDICATED O
. O
|


| O
BEFORE O
THE O
CURTAIN O
. O
|

| O
— O
— O
|

| O
As O
the O
Manager O
of O
the O
Performance O
sits O
before O
the O
|
| O
curtain O
on O
the O
boards O
, O
and O
looks O
into O
the O
Fair B-ORG
, O
a O
feeling O
of O
|
| O
profound O
melancholy O
comes O
over O
him O
in O
his O
survey O
of O
the O
|
| O
bustling O
place O
. O
There O
is O
a O
great O
quantity O
of O
cating*and O
drink- O
|
| O
ing O
, O
making O
love O
and O
jilting O
, O
laughing O
and O
the O
contrary O
, O
|
| O
smoking O
, O
cheating O
, O
fighting O
, O
dancing O
, O
and O
fiddling O
: O
there O
are O
|
| O
bullies O
pushing O
about O
, O
bucks O
ogling O
the O
women O
, O
knaves O
picking O
|
| O
pockets O
, O
policemen O
on O
the O
look O
- O
out O
, O
quacks O
( O
other O
quacks O
, O
|
| O
plague O
take O
them O
! O
) O
bawling O
in O
front O
of O
their O
booths O
, O
and O
yokels O
|
| O
looking O
up O
at O
the O
tinselled O
dancers O
and O
poor O
old O
rouged O
|
| O
tumblers O
, O
while O
the O
light O
- O
fingered O
folk O
are O
operating O
upon O
their O
|
| O
pockets O
behind O
. O
Yes O
, O
this O
is O
Vanity B-ORG
Farr I-ORG
  O
not O
a O
moral O
place O
|
| O
certainly O
  O
nor O
a O
merry O
one O
, O
though O
very O
noisy O
. O
Look O
at O
the O
|
| O
faces O
of O
the O
actors O
and O
buffoons O
when O
they O
come O
off O
from O
their O
|
| O
business O
  O
and O
Tom B-PERSON
Fool I-PERSON
washing O
the O
paint O
off O
his O
cheeks O
before O
|
| O
he O
sits O
down O
to O
dinner O
with O
his O
wife O
and O
the O
little O
Jack B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Puddings I-PERSON
behind O
the O
canvass O
. O
The O
curtain O
will O
be O
up O
presently O
, O
|
| O
and O
he O
will O
be O
turning O
over O
head O
and O
heels O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
|
| O
“ O
How O
are O
you O
? O
” O
|

| O
A O
man O
with O
a O
reflective O
turn O
of O
mind O
, O
walking O
through O
|

| O
viii O
BEFORE O
THE O
CURTAIN O
. O
|

| O
an O
exhibition O
of O
this O
sort O
, O
will O
not O
be O
oppressed O
, O
I O
take O
it O
, O
by O
|
| O
his O
own O
or O
other O
people O
’s O
hilarity O
. O
An O
episode O
of O
humour O
or O
|
| O
kindness O
touches O
and O
amuses O
him O
here O
and O
there O
  O
— O
a O
pretty O
|
| O
child O
looking O
at O
a O
gingerbread O
stall O
  O
a O
pretty O
girl O
blushing O
|
| O
whilst O
her O
lover O
talks O
to O
her O
and O
chooses O
her O
fairing O
  O
poor O
Tom B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Fool I-PERSON
, O
yonder O
behind O
the O
waggon O
, O
mumbling O
his O
bone O
with O
the O
|
| O
honest O
family O
which O
lives O
by O
his O
tumbling O
  O
— O
but O
the O
general O
|
| O
impression O
is O
one B-CARDINAL
more O
melancholy O
than O
mirthful O
. O
When O
you O
|
| O
come O
home O
, O
you O
sit O
down O
, O
in O
a O
sober O
, O
contemplative O
, O
not O
|
| O
uncharitable O
frame O
of O
mind O
, O
and O
apply O
yourself O
to O
your O
books O
|

| O
or O
your O
business O
. O
|

| O
I O
have O
no O
other O
moral O
than O
this O
to O
tag O
to O
the O
present O
|
| O
story O
of O
“ O
Vanity B-ORG
Fair I-ORG
. O
’ O
Some O
people O
consider O
Fairs B-ORG
immoral O
|
| O
altogether O
, O
and O
eschew O
such O
, O
with O
their O
servants O
and O
families O
: O
|
| O
perhaps O
they O
are O
right O
. O
But O
persons O
who O
think O
otherwise O
and O
|
| O
are O
of O
a O
lazy O
, O
or O
a O
benevolent O
, O
or O
a O
sarcastic O
mood O
, O
may O
perhaps O
|
| O
like O
to O
step O
in O
for O
half B-TIME
an I-TIME
hour I-TIME
and O
look O
at O
the O
performances O
. O
|
| O
There O
are O
scenes O
of O
all O
sorts O
  O
some O
dreadful O
combats O
, O
some O
|
| O
grand O
and O
lofty O
horse O
- O
riding O
, O
some O
scenes O
of O
high O
life O
, O
and O
some O
|
| O
of O
very O
middling O
indeed O
  O
some O
love O
making O
for O
the O
sentimental O
, O
|
| O
and O
some O
light O
comic O
business O
: O
the O
whole O
accompanied O
by O
|
| O
appropriate O
scenery O
, O
and O
brilliantly O
illuminated O
with O
the O
|
| O
Author O
’s O
own O
candles O
. O
|

| O
What O
more O
has O
the O
Manager O
of O
the O
Performance O
to O
say O
? O
— O
|
| O
To O
acknowledge O
the O
kindness O
with O
which O
it O
has O
been O
received O
|
| O
in O
all O
the O
principal O
towns O
of O
England B-GPE
through O
which O
the O
Show O
|
| O
has O
passed O
, O
and O
where O
it O
has O
been O
most O
favourably O
noticed O
|
| O
by O
the O
respected O
conductors O
of O
the B-ORG
Public I-ORG
Press I-ORG
, O
and O
by O
the O
|
| O
Nobility O
and O
Gentry O
. O
He O
is O
proud O
to O
think O
that O
his O
Puppets O
|
| O
have O
given O
satisfaction O
to O
the O
very O
best O
company O
in O
this O
empire O
. O
|

| O
BEFORE O
THE O
CURTAIN O
. O
ix O
|

| O
The O
famous O
little O
Becky B-PERSON
Puppet I-PERSON
kas O
been O
pronounced O
to O
be O
|
| O
uncommonly O
flexible O
in O
the O
joints O
and O
lively O
on O
the O
wire O
: O
the O
_ O
|
| O
Amelia B-PERSON
Doll I-PERSON
, O
though O
it O
has O
had O
a O
smaller O
circle O
of O
admirers O
, O
|
| O
has O
yet O
been O
carved O
and O
dressed O
with O
the O
greatest O
care O
by O
|
| O
the O
artist O
: O
the O
Dobbin O
Figure O
, O
though O
apparently O
clumsy O
, O
yet O
|
| O
dances O
in O
a O
very O
amusing O
and O
natural O
manner O
: O
the O
Little O
Boys O
’ O
|
| O
Dance O
has O
been O
liked O
by O
some O
  O
and O
please O
to O
remark O
the O
richly O
|
| O
dressed O
figure O
of O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Wicked I-WORK_OF_ART
Nobleman I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
on O
which O
no O
expense O
|
| O
has O
been O
spared O
, O
and O
which O
Old O
Nick B-PERSON
will O
fetch O
away O
at O
the O
|
| O
end O
of O
this O
singular O
performance O
. O
|

| O
And O
with O
this O
, O
and O
a O
profound O
bow O
to O
his O
patrons O
, O
the O
|

| O
Manager O
retires O
, O
and O
the O
curtain O
rises O
. O
|

| O
Loxpox B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
June B-DATE
28 I-DATE
, I-DATE
1848 I-DATE
, O
|


| O
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
cHar B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
l.—CHISWICK O
MALL O
. O
. O
° O
. O
* O
‘ O
. O
. O
6 B-CARDINAL
e O
. O
1 B-CARDINAL
|

| I-CARDINAL
2 B-CARDINAL
— O
IN O
WHICH O
MISS O
SHARP O
AND O
MIS$ B-CARDINAL
SEDLEY O
PREPARE O
TO O
OPEN O
THE O
|

| O
CAMPAIGN O
, O
© O
26 B-CARDINAL
5 I-CARDINAL
ee O
te O
le O
ll O
CB B-GPE
|
| O
3,.—REBECCA B-DATE
18 I-DATE
IN O
PRESENCE O
OF O
THE O
ENEMY O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
- O
16 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
4.—THE B-CARDINAL
GREEN O
SILK O
PURSE O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
a O
ee O
ee O
|
| O
5-—DOBBIN B-CARDINAL
OF O
OURS B-DATE
, O
a O
Be O
a O
igre O
URE B-ORG
eae O
we O
SBS O
|
| O
6.—VaUxXHALL B-CARDINAL
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
oe B-PERSON
43 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
87 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
7.—CRAWLEY O
OF O
QUEEN O
’s O
CRAWLEY B-PERSON
« O
5 B-CARDINAL
set O
et O
|
| O
8.—PRIVATE B-CARDINAL
AND O
CONFIDENTIAL O
. O
. O
qs O
. O
. O
. O
oe B-PERSON
68 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
9.—FAMILY O
PORTRAITS O
a O
sts O
) O
Veg O
“ O
Ad O
a O
ir O
ad O
ere O
|||| O
) O
oe O
“ O
78 B-CARDINAL
. O
|
| O
10,—at1s8 B-CARDINAL
SHARP O
BEGINS O
TO O
MAKE O
FRIENDS B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
» O
. O
79 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Vl O
— O
arcapian O
simPLIcITy O
2 B-CARDINAL
. O
we O
eee O
|
| O
12,—QUITE B-CARDINAL
A O
SENTIMENTAL O
CHAPTER O
. O
. O
° O
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
. O
aw O
' O
9F O
|
| O
13.—sENTIMENTAL B-CARDINAL
AND O
OTHERWISE O
. O
. O
. O
es B-PERSON
oe I-PERSON
» I-PERSON
| | I-PERSON
« O
104 O
|

| O
I4 O
— O
aiss O
CRAWLEY O
AT O
HOME O
© O
we O
ww O
ts O
- O
ld O
|

| O
xii O
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
cuar B-GPE
. O
PAGE O
|
| O
15.—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
REBECCA O
’S O
HUSBAND O
APPEARS O
FOR O
A O
SHORT O
TIME O
ee O
+ B-CARDINAL
129 I-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
16,—THE B-CARDINAL
LETTER O
ON O
THE O
PINCUSHION B-GPE
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
« O
« O
137 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
17.—How B-CARDINAL
caPTAIN O
DOBBIN B-ORG
BOUGNT O
A O
PIANO B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
oe B-PERSON
6 B-CARDINAL
lt O
|
| O
18,—WHO B-CARDINAL
PLAYED O
ON O
THE O
PIANO B-ORG
CAPTAIN O
DOBBIN O
BOUGHT O
? O
! O
. O
. O
- O
« O
151 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
19.—MIsS B-CARDINAL
CRAWLEY B-GPE
AT O
NURSE B-GPE
. O
. O
wo O
Te B-PERSON
wt I-PERSON
Ge I-PERSON
, O
a O
ke O
. O
WEL B-ORG
|
| O
20.—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
CAPTAIN O
DOBDIN O
ACTS O
AS O
THE O
MESSENGER O
OF O
HYMEN O
« O
- O
« O
170 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
21.—A B-CARDINAL
QUARREL O
ALOUT O
AN O
HEIRESS O
. O
‘ O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
- O
. O
178 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
22.—a B-CARDINAL
MARRIAGE O
AND O
PART O
OF O
A O
HONEYMOON O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
- O
186 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
23.—CAPTAIN B-CARDINAL
DOBBIN B-ORG
PROCEEDS I-ORG
ON I-ORG
HIS O
CANVASS B-ORG
. O
a O
is O
« O
+ B-CARDINAL
193 I-CARDINAL
|
| O
24,—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
MR O
. O
OSBORNE O
TAKES O
DOWN O
THE O
FAMILY O
BIBLE O
. O
. O
+ O
198 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
25.—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
ALL O
THE O
PRINCIPAL O
PERSONAGES O
THINK O
FIT O
TO O
LEAVE B-ORG
|
| I-ORG
BRIGHTON I-ORG
, O
6 B-CARDINAL
© O
+ O
s O
© O
© O
© O
« O
© O
© O
« O
© O
« O
© O
« O
209 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
26,—BETWEEN B-CARDINAL
LONDON B-GPE
AND O
CHATHAM O
. O
& O
Oe O
9 O
. O
. O
+ O
2 B-QUANTITY
225 I-QUANTITY
|

| I-QUANTITY
27.—IN I-QUANTITY
WHICH O
AMEIJA B-PRODUCT
JOINS O
HER B-ORG
REGIMENT I-ORG
. O
eee O
« O
232 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
28.—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
AMELIA B-ORG
INVADES O
THE O
LOW O
COUNTRIES O
. O
. O
. O
- O
« O
288 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
29.—pRussEIS B-CARDINAL
« O
le O
. O
. O
oe B-PERSON
. O
ee O
ee O
ee O
+ O
246 O
|

| O
30 B-CARDINAL
. O
— O
“ O
THE O
GIRL O
I O
LEFT O
BEHIND O
ME O
” O
OR O
” O
eA. O
er O
ey O
SST O
|
| O
31.—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
JoS B-PERSON
SEDLEY I-PERSON
TAKES O
CARE O
OF O
HIS O
SISTER O
. O
. O
« O
| | O
« O
265 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
32,—1IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
JOS B-PERSON
TAKES I-PERSON
FLIGHT O
, O
AND O
THE O
WAR O
IS O
BROUGHT O
TO O
A O
CLOSE O
. O
275 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
33,—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
MISS O
CRAWLEY B-GPE
’S O
RELATIONS O
ARE O
VERY O
ANXIOUS O
ABOUT O
HER O
. O
289 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
34.—JAMES O
CRAWLEY B-GPE
'S O
PIPE O
IS O
PUT B-ORG
OUT I-ORG
. O
. O
. O
= O
6 B-CARDINAL
+ O
3 O
( O
298 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
35,—WIDOW B-CARDINAL
AND O
MOTHER O
. O
. O
oe B-PERSON
. O
. O
. O
» O
. O
. O
312 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
36.—HoW B-CARDINAL
To O
LIVE O
WELL O
ON O
NOTHING O
A O
- O
YEAR O
we O
af O
fas O
We O
. O
321 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
cuar B-GPE
, O
|

| O
37.—THE B-CARDINAL
SUBJECT O
CONTINUED O
» O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
38.—a B-CARDINAL
FAMILY O
IN O
A O
VERY O
SMALL O
war O
Oe B-PERSON
a I-PERSON
Ore I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
39.—Aa B-CARDINAL
CYNICAL B-ORG
CHAPTER O
oe B-PERSON
ae I-PERSON
+ O
8 B-CARDINAL
. O
. O
|

| O
40.—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
BECKY O
1S O
RECOGNISED O
BY O
THE O
FAMILY O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
41,—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
BECKY O
REVISITS O
THE O
HALLS O
OP O
HER O
ANCESTORS O
|
| O
42.—WiICH B-CARDINAL
TREATS O
OF O
THE O
OSBORNE O
FAMILY O
ge O
|

| O
an O
WHICH O
THE O
READER O
HAS O
TO O
DOUBLE O
THE O
CAPE O
. O
|
| O
44.—A B-CARDINAL
ROUND O
- O
ABOUT O
CHAFTER O
BETWEEN O
LONDON O
AND O
HAMPSHIRE O
. O
|
| O
45.—BETWEEN O
HAMPSHIRE O
AND O
LONDON B-GPE
. O
abs O
|

| O
46.—STRUGGLES B-CARDINAL
AND O
TRIALS O
» O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|

| O
47.—GAUST B-CARDINAL
HOUSE B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|

| O
48—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
TUE B-DATE
READER O
18 B-CARDINAL
INTRODUCED O
TO O
THE O
VERY O
BEST O
|

| O
COMPANY O
» O
5 O
6 O
6 O
+ O
et O
|
| O
49.—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
WE O
ENJOY O
THREE B-CARDINAL
COURSES O
AND O
A O
DESSERT O
. O
. O
|

| O
50.—CONTAINS B-ORG
A I-ORG
VULGAR I-ORG
INCIDENT I-ORG
. I-ORG
. O
. O
|

| O
51,—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
A O
CHARADE O
18 B-CARDINAL
ACTED O
WHICH O
MAY B-DATE
OR O
MAY O
NOT O
PUZZLE O
|
| O
READER O
Be O
tee O
Bet O
lew O
18S O
|

| O
52.—1N B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
LORD O
STEYNE B-ORG
SHOWS O
HIMSELF O
IN O
A O
MOST O
AMIABLE O
LIGHT O
|
| O
53,—a B-CARDINAL
RESCUE O
AND O
A O
CATASTROPHE O
. O
= O
» O
we O
we O
|
| O
54,—SUNDAY B-CARDINAL
AFTER O
THE O
BATTLE B-GPE
. O
. O
. O
|

| O
55.—1IN O
WHICH O
THE O
SAME O
SUBJECT O
IS O
PURSUED O
. O
|
| O
56.—GEORGY B-CARDINAL
1S B-ORG
MADE O
A O
GENTLEMAN B-ORG
|

| O
Si,—rotuen O
, O
. O
ee O
Oe O
|

| O
xiii O
|
| O
TAGE O
|
| O
329 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
341 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
353 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
361 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
369 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
379 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
385 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
293 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
402 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
410 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
417 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
425 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
434 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
441 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
449 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
464 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
473 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
481 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
489 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
502 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
513 B-MONEY
|

| I-MONEY
xiv I-MONEY
CONTENTS O
. O
|

| O
CHAP O
. O
PAGE O
|
| O
58.--OUR B-CARDINAL
FRIEND B-ORG
THE O
MAJOR B-ORG
ae O
tay B-PERSON
aD I-PERSON
ee O
coos O
Wa O
’ O
o O
Bet O
Me O
521 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
58 B-CARDINAL
... O
THE O
OLD O
PIANO O
Cr O
a O
re O
|||| O
) O
|

| O
60,--RETURNS B-CARDINAL
TO O
THE O
GENTEEL O
WORLD O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
« O
, O
« O
539 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
61.—1N B-DATE
WHICH O
TWO B-CARDINAL
LIGHTS O
ARE O
PUT O
OUT O
oe O
. O
eee O
. O
64S B-CARDINAL
|
| O
62.—aM B-CARDINAL
RHEIN B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
eo O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
« O
557 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
63,.—IN B-CARDINAL
WHICH O
WE O
MEET B-ORG
AN I-ORG
OLD O
ACQUAINTANCE O
. O
° O
. O
. O
© B-ORG
w I-ORG
( O
667 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
64.—A B-CARDINAL
VAGABOND B-ORG
CHAPTER O
. O
ro B-ORG
Ne I-ORG
eG I-ORG
for O
Ro B-ORG
le I-ORG
ETE I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
65.—FULL B-CARDINAL
OF O
BUSINESS O
AND O
PLEASURE O
. O
. O
: O
. O
. O
« O
6 B-CARDINAL
« O
5921 O
|

| O
66.—aMANTIUM B-CARDINAL
IRE O
. O
we O
oo O
. O
. O
. O
« O
6 B-CARDINAL
+ I-CARDINAL
598 I-CARDINAL
|

| O
67.—WHICH O
CONTAINS O
BIRTHS B-ORG
, O
MaRRIAGES B-ORG
, O
AND O
DEATHS O
. O
. O
. O
. O
» O
611 B-MONEY
|

| I-MONEY
LIST I-MONEY
OF I-MONEY
PLATES O
. O
|

| O
— O
_ O
— O
— O
|

| O
PAGE O
|
| O
Toe B-PERSON
Lerrer I-PERSON
BEFORE I-PERSON
WATERLOO I-PERSON
. O
+ O
é O
. O
. O
« O
+ O
Frontispiece O
. O
|
| O
Vicxerre O
TitLe O
- O
pace O
|
| O
Resecca B-PERSON
’s O
Farewe.t B-PRODUCT
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
a O
8 B-CARDINAL
. O
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Mr O
, O
Josep B-PERSON
ENTANGLED O
. O
Ws O
fe O
. O
oe B-PERSON
eh O
os O
LA B-GPE
CEP O
|
| O
Mr. O
Joseru B-PERSON
in O
a O
State B-ORG
op O
ExciteMENT O
« O
we O
, O
eo O
) O
a O
: O
we O
~ O
180 B-CARDINAL
) O
|
| O
REBecca O
MAKES O
ACQUAINTANCE O
WITH O
A O
LIVE O
BARONET O
. O
. O
3 B-CARDINAL
« O
« O
59 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Miss O
Swarr B-PERSON
1n O
HER O
Scuoot O
- O
Room O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
° O
« O
86 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Miss O
Crawtey B-PERSON
’s O
arrectionate O
Rewatives B-PERSON
. O
i O
ye O
” O
ats O
o O
® O
B O
, O
OS O
|
| O
Mr. O
Osporne B-PERSON
’s O
Wetcomz B-ORG
TO I-ORG
AMELIA O
. O
. O
. O
| | O
. O
- O
» O
« O
109 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Lizvrenant B-PERSON
Osporxe I-PERSON
AND O
wis O
aRDENT O
Love O
- O
Letrrerns O
. O
. O
. O
.. O
113 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Tue O
Note O
on O
THE O
Pixcusuion O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
+ O
140 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
An O
Evepmant O
ron O
Sate O
. O
we O
wwe O
we O
« O
YS O
|
| O
Mr. O
Sevtey B-PERSON
at O
tue B-ORG
Corree I-ORG
- I-ORG
House I-ORG
. O
» O
. O
« O
« O
© O
« O
« O
6 B-CARDINAL
« O
. O
« O
+ O
172 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Miss O
SwaRTZ B-PERSON
REHEARSING O
FoR O
THE O
Drawine O
- O
Roon O
. O
ar O
+ O
» O
181 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Exsicn B-PERSON
Sruppte I-PERSON
practising O
THE O
Ant O
or O
Wan O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
+ B-CARDINAL
207 I-CARDINAL
|
| O
A B-ORG
Fauity I-ORG
Party I-ORG
at O
Bricuton B-GPE
. O
. O
: O
Kates O
3 O
- O
« O
213 O
|
| O
Mas O
. O
O'Dowp O
at O
tue B-ORG
Flower I-ORG
Marker I-ORG
. O
| | O
. O
| | O
- O
eee O
ODD O
|

| O
Mas O
. O
Ospornr B-ORG
’s O
CaRRIaGE O
storPinc O
THE O
Way O
a O
pS O
+ O
+ O
255 O
|

| O
Xxv1 O
LIST O
OF O
PLATES O
, O
|

| O
VeNvS B-GPE
PREPARING O
THE O
AnmouR O
oF O
Mars B-LOC
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Jos B-PERSON
suaves O
OFF O
uIs O
Mustacnios B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Ma B-PERSON
, O
James B-PERSON
’s O
Pirg B-PERSON
purour O
. O
. O
. O
« O
|
| O
Mason B-PERSON
Sucarruss I-PERSON
= O
. O
wwe O
, O
Z O
|
| O
Mrs. O
Rawpoy B-PERSON
’s O
Departure O
From O
Paris B-GPE
. O
|
| O
Georcr B-PERSON
Makes I-PERSON
ACQUAINTANCE I-PERSON
WITH I-PERSON
A I-PERSON
WATERLOO I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Tae I-PERSON
Rissons I-PERSON
Discoverep I-PERSON
IN O
THE O
Fact O
. O
= O
. O
|
| O
Sm O
Pirt O
's O
rast O
Stace B-PERSON
SWS I-PERSON
Dey I-PERSON
el O
KS O
|
| O
GLorVINA O
TRIES O
MER O
Fascination O
oN O
THE O
Magor B-PERSON
|
| O
Tue O
Arrival O
at O
QueEN O
’s O
CRAWLEY B-GPE
. O
‘ O
. O
|
| O
Becny O
1n O
Lowparp O
- O
Srreer O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
Groncy B-PERSON
Gors I-PERSON
To I-PERSON
CHURCH I-PERSON
GENTEELLY I-PERSON
. O
« O
le O
|
| O
Tue B-TIME
Triumpa I-TIME
or O
CLYTEMNESTRA B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
CotoneL O
CRAWLEY B-GPE
18 B-CARDINAL
WANTED O
a O
ad O
’ O
|
| O
Sr O
Pirt O
’s O
Strupy B-PERSON
Cua I-PERSON
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
Georcy B-PERSON
A I-PERSON
GENTLEMAN O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
A O
Meetinc O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
Mr O
, O
Jos B-PERSON
’s O
HookaupapaR. B-EVENT
= O
. O
Se O
|

| O
A O
rine O
Summer B-WORK_OF_ART
Eveninc I-WORK_OF_ART
. O
. O
: O
. O
. O
|
| O
Jos O
PERFORMS O
A O
POLONAISE B-ORG
. O
. O
. O
. O
|
| O
Becky O
’s O
Seconp O
APPEARANCE O
IN O
THE O
CHARACTER O
|

| O
Virtug B-PERSON
Rewarvep I-PERSON
  O
a O
Bootm B-ORG
in O
Vanity O
Fain O
|

| O
or O
CLYTEMNESTRA B-ORG
|

| O
Pace O
|

| O
257 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
279 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
307 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
319 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
327 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
340 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
359 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
362 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
400 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
433 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
448 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
525 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
533 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
560 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
569 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
623 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
624 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
VANITY O
FAIR O
. O
|

| O
@ O
Nobel B-WORK_OF_ART
without O
a O
Hero B-PRODUCT
. O
|

| O
CHAPTER O
IL O
|
| O
CHISWICK O
MALL O
, O
|

| O
( O
> O
yy O
} O
HILE B-PERSON
the B-DATE
present I-DATE
century I-DATE
was O
in O
|

| O
“ O
It O
is O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
coach O
, O
sister O
, O
” O
said O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
. O
‘ O
Sambo B-PERSON
, O
the O
|
| O
black O
servant O
, O
has O
just O
rung O
the O
bell O
  O
and O
the O
coachman O
has O
a O
new O
red O
|
| O
waistcoat O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
The O
girls O
were O
up O
at O
four B-TIME
this I-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
packing O
her O
trunks O
, O
sister O
, O
” O
|
| O
replied O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
  O
“ O
we O
have O
made O
her O
a O
bow O
- O
pot O
. O
” O
|

| O
B O
|

  

| O
2 B-CARDINAL
VANITY O
FAIR O
. O
|

 

| O
“ O
And O
I O
trust O
, O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
you O
have O
made O
a O
copy O
of O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
|

 

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
3 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
as O
a O
young O
lady O
not O
unworthy O
to O
occupy O
a O
fitting O
position O
in O
their O
polished O
|
| O
and O
refined O
circle O
. O
Those O
virtues O
which O
characterise O
the O
young O
English B-LANGUAGE
|
| O
gentlewoman O
, O
those O
accomplishments O
which O
become O
her O
birth O
and O
station O
, O
|
| O
will O
not O
be O
found O
wanting O
in O
the O
amiable O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
whose O
industry O
|
| O
and O
obedience O
have O
endeared O
her O
to O
her O
instructors O
, O
and O
whose O
delightful O
|
| O
sweetness O
of O
temper O
has O
charmed O
her O
aged O
and O
her O
youthful O
companions O
. O
|

| O
“ O
For O
whom O
is O
this O
, O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
? O
” O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
with O
awful O
|
| O
coldness O
. O
|

| O
“ O
For O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
, O
” O
answered O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
trembiing O
very O
much O
, O
and O
|
| O
blushing O
over O
her O
withered O
face O
and O
neck O
, O
as O
she O
tured O
her O
back O
on O
|
| O
her O
sister O
. O
‘ O
For O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
: O
she O
’s O
going O
too O
. O
” O
|

| O
n2 O
|

| O
4 O
VANITY O
FAIR O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Send O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
instantly O
to O
me O
, O
” O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
. O
And O
so O
|
| O
venturing O
not O
to O
say O
another O
word O
, O
poor O
Jemima B-PERSON
trotted O
off O
, O
exceedingly O
|
| O
flurried O
and O
nervous O
. O
|

| O
But O
as O
we O
are O
to O
see O
a O
great O
deal O
of O
Amelia B-ORG
, O
there O
is O
no O
harm O
in O
saying O
|
| O
at O
the O
outset O
of O
our O
acquaintance O
, O
that O
she O
was O
one O
of O
the O
best O
and O
dearest O
|
| O
creatures O
that O
ever O
lived O
  O
and O
a O
great O
mercy O
it O
is O
, O
both O
in O
life O
and O
in O
|
| O
novels O
, O
which O
( O
and O
the O
latter O
especially O
) O
abound O
in O
villains O
of O
the O
most O
|
| O
sombre O
sort O
, O
that O
we O
are O
to O
have O
for O
a O
constant O
companion O
, O
so O
guileless O
|

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
5 B-CARDINAL
|

 

 

| O
which O
details O
, O
I O
have O
no O
doubt O
, O
Jones B-PERSON
, O
who O
reads O
this O
book O
at O
his O
Club B-ORG
, O
|

| O
6 O
VANITY O
FAIR O
. O
|

| O
“ O
You O
ll O
go O
in O
and O
say O
good O
by O
to O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
Becky O
? O
” O
said O
Miss O
|
| O
Jemima B-PERSON
to O
a O
young O
lady O
of O
whom O
: O
nobody O
took O
any O
notice O
, O
and O
who O
was O
|
| O
coming O
down O
stairs O
with O
her O
own O
bandbox O
. O
|

| O
“ O
I O
suppose O
I O
must O
, O
” O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
calmly O
, O
and O
much O
to O
the O
wonder O
|
| O
of O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
  O
and O
the O
latter O
having O
knocked O
at O
the O
door O
, O
and O
receiving O
|
| O
permission O
to O
come O
in O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
advanced O
in O
a O
very O
unconcerned O
man- O
|
| O
ner B-ORG
, O
and O
said O
in O
French B-NORP
, O
and O
with O
a O
perfect O
accent O
, O
“ O
‘ O
Mademoiselle O
, O
je B-PERSON
viens I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
vous I-PERSON
faire I-PERSON
mes O
adieux O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
‘ O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
did O
not O
understand O
French B-NORP
  O
she O
only O
directed O
those O
|
| O
who O
did O
: O
but O
biting O
her O
lips O
and O
throwing O
up O
her O
venerable O
and O
Roman- O
|
| O
nosed O
head O
, O
( O
on O
the O
: O
top O
of O
which O
figured O
a O
large O
and O
solemn O
turban O
, O
) O
she O
|
| O
said O
, O
“ O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
I'wishyou O
a O
good O
morning O
. O
” O
As O
the O
Hammersmith B-GPE
|
| O
Semiramis B-GPE
spoke O
, O
she O
waved O
one O
: O
hand O
both O
by O
way O
of O
adieu O
, O
and O
to O
give O
|
| O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
an O
opportunity O
of O
shaking O
one B-CARDINAL
- O
of O
the O
fingers O
of O
the O
hand O
which O
|
| O
was O
left O
out O
for O
that O
purpose O
. O
|

| O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
only O
folded O
her O
own O
hands O
with O
a O
very O
frigid O
smile O
and O
bow O
, O
|
| O
and O
quite O
declined O
to O
accept O
the O
proffered O
honour O
  O
on O
which O
Semiramis B-GPE
|
| O
Spesed B-PERSON
up O
her O
turban O
more O
indignantly O
than O
ever O
. O
In O
fact O
, O
it O
was O
a O
little O
|
| O
battle O
between O
the O
young O
lady O
and O
the O
old O
one O
, O
and O
the O
latter O
was O
worsted O
. O
|
| O
“ O
Heaven O
bless O
you O
, O
my O
child O
, O
” O
said O
she O
, O
embracing O
Amelia B-ORG
, O
and O
scowling O
|
| O
the O
while O
over O
the O
girl O
’s O
shoulder O
at O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
. O
‘ O
Come O
away O
, O
Becky B-PERSON
, O
” O
|
| O
said O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
pulling O
the O
young O
woman O
away O
in O
great O
alarm O
, O
and O
the O
|
| O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
closed O
upon O
them O
for O
ever O
. O
|

| O
Then O
came O
the O
struggle O
and O
parting O
below O
. O
Words O
refuse O
to O
tell O
it O
. O
|
| O
All O
the O
servants O
were O
there O
in O
the O
hall O
— O
all O
the O
dear O
friends O
— O
all O
the O
young O
|
| O
ladies O
— O
the O
dancing O
- O
master O
who O
had O
just O
arrived O
  O
and O
there O
was O
such O
a O
|
| O
scuffling O
, O
and O
hugging O
, O
and O
kissing O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
with O
the O
hysterical O
yoops O
|


 

| O
co O
ZF B-ORG
|
| O
e O
bigs O
C O
“ O
ale O
tle O
Mf O
? O
|

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
of O
Miss O
Swartz B-PERSON
, O
the O
parlour O
- O
boarder O
, O
from O
her O
room O
, O
as O
no O
pen O
can O
depict O
, O
|
| O
and O
as O
the O
tender O
heart O
would O
fain O
pass O
over O
. O
The O
embracing O
was O
over O
  O
|
| O
they O
parted O
— O
that O
is O
, O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
parted O
from O
her O
friends O
. O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
|
| O
had O
demurely O
entered O
the O
carriage O
some B-TIME
minutes I-TIME
before O
. O
Nobody O
cried O
for O
|
| O
leaving O
her O
. O
|

| O
Sambo B-PERSON
of O
the O
: O
bandy O
- O
legs O
slammed O
the O
carriage O
- O
door O
on O
his O
young O
weep- O
|
| O
ing O
mistress O
. O
He O
sprang O
up O
behind O
the O
carriage O
. O
“ O
Stop O
! O
” O
cried O
Miss O
|
| O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
Pushing O
to O
the O
gate O
with O
a O
parcel O
. O
~ O
|

| O
* O
Ti O
’s O
some O
sandwiches O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
” O
said O
she O
to O
Amelia.- O
. O
# O
You O
may O
|
| O
be O
hingry B-GPE
, O
you O
know O
  O
and O
Becky B-ORG
, I-ORG
Becky I-ORG
Sharp I-ORG
, O
here O
’s O
a B-WORK_OF_ART
Book I-WORK_OF_ART
for O
you O
|
| O
that O
my O
sister O
— O
that O
‘ O
is O
  O
I O
— O
Johnson B-PERSON
’s O
Dixonary B-PERSON
, O
you O
know O
  O
  O
you O
must O
n’t O
|
| O
leave O
us O
without O
thaty O
Good O
by O
. O
Drive O
on O
, O
coachman O
. O
God O
bless O
you O
! O
” O
|

| O
And O
the O
kind.creabure O
retreated O
into O
the O
garden O
, O
overcome O
with O
emotions O
. O
|

| O
But O
, O
lo O
! O
anid B-PERSON
just O
- O
as O
the O
coach O
drove O
off O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
put O
her O
pale O
face O
|
| O
out O
of O
the O
window O
, O
and O
actually O
flung O
the O
book O
batk O
into O
the O
garden O
. O
|

| O
This O
almost O
caused O
Jemima B-PERSON
to O
famt O
- O
with O
terror O
: O
: O
“ O
Well O
, O
I O
never O
, O
” O
— O
|
| O
said O
she O
— O
* O
what O
an O
audacious O
” O
— O
Emotion B-ORG
prevented O
her O
from O
completing O
|
| O
either O
sentence O
. O
The O
carriage O
rolled O
away O
’ O
  O
the O
great O
gates O
were O
closed O
  O
|
| O
the O
bell O
rang O
for O
the O
dancing O
lesson O
. O
The O
- O
world O
is O
before O
: O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
|
| O
ladies O
  O
and O
so O
, O
farewell O
to O
Chiswick B-FAC
Mall I-FAC
. O
|

 

| O
CHAPTER O
II O
. O
|

| O
IN O
WHICH O
MISS O
SHARP O
AND O
MISS O
SEDLEY O
PREPARE O
TO O
OPEN O
|
| O
THE O
CAMPAIGN O
. O
|

| O
HEN B-GPE
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
had O
performed O
the O
heroical O
act O
mentioned O
|
| O
in O
the O
last O
chapter O
, O
and O
had O
seen O
the O
Dixonary B-PERSON
flying O
|
| O
over O
the O
pavement O
of O
the O
little O
garden O
, O
fall O
at O
length O
at O
|
| O
the O
feet O
of O
the O
astonished O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
the O
young O
lady O
’s O
|
| O
countenance O
, O
which O
had O
before O
worn O
an O
almost O
livid O
look O
|
| O
of O
hatred O
, O
assumed O
a O
smile O
that O
perhaps O
was O
scarcely O
|
| O
more O
agreeable O
, O
and O
she O
sank O
back O
in O
the O
carriage O
in O
|

| O
j O
an O
casy O
frame O
of O
mind O
, O
saying,—‘‘So O
much O
for O
the O
|

| O
Dixonary B-PERSON
  O
and O
, O
thank O
God O
, O
I O
’m O
out O
of O
Chiswick B-GPE
. O
” O
° O
|

| O
“ O
How O
could O
you O
do O
so O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
? O
” O
at O
last O
she O
said O
, O
after O
a O
pause O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Why O
, O
do O
you O
think O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
will O
come O
out O
and O
order O
me O
back O
|
| O
to O
the O
black O
- O
hole O
? O
” O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
|

| O
“ O
No O
: O
bu O
- O
|

| O
“ O
T O
hate O
the O
whole O
house O
, O
” O
continued O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
ina O
fury O
. O
‘ O
I O
hope O
|
| O
I O
may O
never O
set O
eyes O
on O
it O
again O
. O
I O
wish O
it O
were O
in O
the O
bottom O
of O
the O
|
| O
Thames O
, O
I O
do O
  O
and O
if O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
were O
there O
, O
I O
wouldn O
’ O
t O
pick O
her O
out O
, O
|
| O
that O
I O
would O
n’t O
. O
O O
how O
I O
should O
like O
to O
see O
her O
floating O
in O
the O
water O
|
| O
yonder O
, O
turban O
and O
all O
, O
with O
her O
train O
streaming O
after O
her O
, O
and O
her O
nose O
|
| O
like O
the O
beak O
of O
a O
wherry O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Hush O
! O
” O
cried O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
. O
|

| O
“ O
Why O
, O
will O
the O
black O
footman O
tell O
tales O
? O
” O
cried O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
|
| O
“ O
He O
may O
go O
back O
and O
tell O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
that O
I O
hate O
her O
with O
all O
my O
|
| O
soul O
  O
and O
I O
wish O
he O
would O
  O
and O
I O
wish O
I O
had O
a O
means O
of O
proving O
it O
too O
. O
|
| O
For O
two B-DATE
years I-DATE
I O
have O
only O
had O
insults O
and O
outrage O
from O
her O
. O
I O
have O
been O
|
| O
treated O
worse O
than O
any O
servant O
in O
the O
kitchen O
. O
I O
have O
never O
had O
a O
friend O
|
| O
or O
a O
kind O
word O
, O
except O
from O
you O
. O
Ihave O
been O
made O
to O
tend O
the O
little O
girls O
|

 

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
9 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
in O
the O
lower O
schoolroom O
, O
and O
to O
talk O
French B-NORP
to O
the O
Misses O
, O
until O
I O
grew O
|
| O
sick O
of O
my O
mother O
- O
tongue O
. O
But O
that O
talking O
French B-NORP
to O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
capital O
fun O
, O
was O
n’t O
it O
? O
She O
does O
n’t O
know O
a O
word O
of O
French B-NORP
, O
and O
was O
|
| O
too O
proud O
to O
confess O
it O
. O
I O
believe O
it O
was O
that O
which O
made O
her O
part O
with O
|
| O
me O
  O
and O
so O
thank O
Heaven O
for O
French B-NORP
. O
Vive O
la O
France B-GPE
! O
Vive O
V O
Empereur O
! O
|
| O
Vive O
Bonaparte O
! O
” O
|

| O
“ O
O O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
for O
shame O
! O
” O
cried O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
  O
for O
this O
was O
|
| O
the O
greatest O
blasphemy O
Rebecca B-PERSON
had O
as O
yet O
uttered O
  O
and O
in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
, O
in O
|
| O
England B-GPE
, O
to O
say O
‘ O
‘ O
Long O
live O
Bonaparte O
|||| O
! O
” O
was O
as O
much O
as O
to O
say O
“ O
Long O
|
| O
live O
Lucifer B-PERSON
! O
” O
‘ O
How O
can O
you O
— O
how O
dare O
you O
have O
such O
wicked O
, O
|
| O
revengeful O
thoughts O
? O
” O
|

| O
« O
Revenge O
may O
be O
wicked O
, O
but O
it O
’s O
natural O
, O
” O
answered O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
“ O
T’m O
no O
angel O
. O
” O
And O
, O
to O
say O
the O
truth O
, O
she O
certainly O
was O
not O
. O
|

 

| O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
’s O
father O
was O
an O
artist O
, O
and O
in O
that O
quality O
had O
given O
lessons O
|
| O
of O
drawing O
at O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
’s O
school O
. O
He O
was O
a O
clever O
man O
  O
a O
pleasant O
|
| O
companion O
  O
a O
careless O
student O
  O
with O
a O
great O
propensity O
for O
running O
into O
|
| O
debt O
, O
and O
a O
partiality O
for O
the O
tavern O
. O
When O
he O
was O
drunk O
, O
he O
used O
to O
|
| O
beat O
his O
wife O
and O
daughter O
  O
and O
the B-TIME
next I-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
with O
a O
headache O
, O
he O
|
| O
used O
to O
rail O
at O
the O
world O
for O
its O
neglect O
of O
his O
genius O
, O
and O
abuse O
, O
with O
a O
|
| O
good O
deal O
of O
cleverness O
, O
and O
sometimes O
with O
perfect O
reason O
, O
the O
fools O
, O
his O
|
| O
brother O
painters O
. O
As O
it O
was O
with O
the O
utmost O
difficulty O
that O
he O
could O
keep O
|
| O
himself O
, O
and O
as O
he O
owed O
money O
for O
a O
mile O
round O
Soho O
, O
where O
he O
lived O
, O
he O
|

| O
10 B-CARDINAL
VANITY O
FAIR O
. O
|

 

| O
Rebecca B-PERSON
’s O
mother O
had O
had O
some O
education O
somewhere O
, O
and O
her O
daughter O
|
| O
spoke O
French B-NORP
with O
purity O
and O
a O
Parisian B-NORP
accent O
. O
It O
was O
in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
|
| O
rather O
a O
rare O
accomplishment O
, O
and O
led O
to O
her O
engagement O
with O
the O
orthodox O
|
| O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
. O
For O
her O
mother O
being O
dead O
, O
her O
father O
, O
finding O
him- O
|
| O
self O
not O
likely O
to O
recover O
, O
after O
his O
third B-ORDINAL
attack O
of O
delirium O
tremens O
, O
wrote O
|
| O
a O
manly O
and O
pathetic O
letter O
to O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
recommending O
the O
orphan O
|
| O
child O
to O
her O
protection O
, O
and O
so O
descended O
to O
the O
grave O
, O
after O
two B-CARDINAL
bailiffs O
|
| O
had O
quarrelled O
over O
his O
corpse O
. O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
seventeen B-DATE
when O
she O
came O
to O
|
| O
Chiswick B-PERSON
, O
and O
was O
bound O
over O
as O
an O
articled O
pupil O
  O
her O
duties O
being O
to O
|
| O
talk O
French B-NORP
, O
as O
we O
have O
seen O
, O
and O
her O
privileges O
to O
live O
cost O
free O
, O
and O
, O
|
| O
with O
a B-MONEY
few I-MONEY
guineas I-MONEY
a O
year O
, O
to O
gather O
scraps O
of O
knowledge O
from O
the O
professors O
|
| O
who O
attended O
the O
school O
. O
: O
|

| O
By O
the O
side O
of O
many O
tall O
and O
bouncing O
young O
ladies O
in O
the O
establishment O
, O
|
| O
Rebecca B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
looked O
like O
a O
child O
. O
But O
she O
had O
the O
dismal O
precocity O
of O
|
| O
poverty O
. O
Many O
a O
dun O
had O
she O
talked O
to O
, O
and O
turned O
away O
from O
her O
father O
’s O
|
| O
door O
  O
many O
a O
tradesman O
had O
she O
coaxed O
and O
wheedled O
into O
good O
- O
humour O
, O
|
| O
and O
into O
the O
granting O
of O
one B-CARDINAL
meal O
more O
. O
She O
sate O
commonly O
with O
her O
|
| O
father O
, O
who O
was O
very O
proud O
of O
her O
wit O
, O
and O
heard O
the O
talk O
of O
many O
of O
his O
|
| O
wild O
companions O
— O
often O
but O
ill O
suited O
for O
a O
girl O
to O
hear O
. O
But O
she O
never O
|
| O
had O
been O
a O
girl O
, O
she O
said O
  O
she O
had O
been O
a O
woman O
since O
she O
was O
eight B-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
old I-DATE
. O
O O
why O
did O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
let O
such O
a O
dangerous O
bird O
into O
her O
cage O
? O
|

| O
The O
happiness O
— O
the O
superior O
advantages O
of O
the O
young O
women O
round O
|
| O
about O
: O
her O
, O
gave O
Rebecca B-PERSON
inexpressible O
pangs O
of O
envy O
. O
‘ O
What O
airs O
that O
|
| O
girl O
gives O
herself O
, O
because O
she O
is O
an O
Earl B-PERSON
’s O
granddaughter O
, O
” O
she O
said O
of O
one B-CARDINAL
. O
|
| O
“ O
How O
they O
cringe O
and O
bow O
to O
that O
Creole B-ORG
, O
because O
of O
her B-CARDINAL
hundred I-CARDINAL
|
| I-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
pounds I-CARDINAL
! O
I O
am O
a O
thousand O
times O
cleverer O
and O
more O
charming O
|
| O
than O
that O
creature O
, O
for O
all O
her O
wealth O
. O
I O
am O
as O
well O
bred O
as O
the O
Earl B-PERSON
’s O
|
| O
granddaughter O
, O
for O
all O
her O
fine O
pedigree O
  O
and O
yet O
every O
one B-CARDINAL
passes O
me O
by O
|
| O
here O
. O
And O
yet O
, O
when O
I O
was O
at O
my O
father O
’s O
, O
did O
not O
the O
men O
give O
up O
their O
|
| O
gayest O
balls O
and O
parties O
in O
order O
to O
pass O
the O
evening O
with O
me O
? O
” O
She O
|
| O
determined O
at O
any O
rate O
to O
get O
free O
from O
the O
prison O
in O
which O
she O
found O
|
| O
herself O
, O
and O
now O
began O
to O
act O
for O
herself O
, O
and O
for O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
to O
make O
|
| O
connected O
plans O
for O
the O
future O
. O
|

| O
She O
took O
advantage O
, O
therefore O
, O
of O
the O
means O
of O
study O
the O
place O
offered O
|
| O
her O
  O
and O
as O
she O
was O
already O
a O
musician O
and O
a O
good O
linguist O
, O
she O
speedily O
|
| O
went O
through O
the O
little O
course O
of O
study O
which O
was O
considered O
necessary O
for O
|
| O
ladies O
in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
. O
Her O
music O
she O
practised O
incessantly O
, O
and O
one B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
|
| O
when O
the O
girls O
were O
out O
, O
and O
she O
had O
remained O
at O
home O
, O
she O
was O
over- O
|
| O
heard O
to O
play O
a O
piece O
so O
well O
, O
that O
Minerva B-ORG
thought O
wisely O
, O
she O
could O
|
| O
spare O
herself O
the O
expense O
of O
a O
master O
for O
the O
juniors O
, O
and O
intimated O
to O
|
| O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
that O
she O
was O
to O
instruct O
them O
in O
music O
for O
the O
future O
. O
|

| O
Minerva B-ORG
was O
obliged O
to O
yield O
, O
and O
, O
of O
course O
, O
disliked O
her O
from O
that B-DATE
day I-DATE
. O
|
| O
“ O
For O
five B-DATE
- I-DATE
and I-DATE
- I-DATE
thirty I-DATE
years I-DATE
, O
” O
she O
said O
, O
and O
with O
great O
justice O
, O
“ O
I O
never O
|

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUTA O
HERO O
. O
13 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
have O
seen O
the O
individual O
who O
has O
dared O
in O
my O
own O
house O
to O
question O
my O
|
| O
authority O
. O
I O
have O
nourished O
a O
viper O
in O
my O
bosom O
. O
” O
|

| O
‘ O
< O
A O
viper O
— O
a O
fiddlestick O
, O
” O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
to O
the O
old O
lady O
, O
almost O
faint- O
|
| O
ing O
with O
astonishment O
. O
‘ O
You O
took O
me O
because O
I O
was O
useful O
. O
There O
is O
no O
|
| O
question O
of O
gratitude O
between O
us O
. O
I O
hate O
this O
place O
, O
and O
want O
to O
leave O
it O
. O
|
| O
I O
will O
do O
nothing O
here O
, O
but O
what O
I O
am O
obliged O
to O
do O
. O
” O
|

| O
It O
was O
in O
vain O
that O
the O
old O
lady O
asked O
her O
if O
she O
was O
aware O
she O
was O
|
| O
speaking O
to O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
? O
Rebecca B-PERSON
laughed O
in O
her O
face O
, O
with O
a O
horrid O
|
| O
sarcastic O
demoniacal O
laughter O
, O
that O
almost O
sent O
the O
schoolmistress O
into O
fits O
. O
|
| O
« O
Give O
me O
a O
sum O
of O
money O
, O
” O
said O
the O
girl O
, O
“ O
and O
get O
rid O
of O
me O
— O
or O
, O
if O
you O
|
| O
like O
better O
, O
get O
me O
a O
good O
place O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
nobleman O
’s O
family O
— O
you O
|
| O
can O
do O
so O
if O
you O
please O
. O
” O
And O
in O
their O
further O
disputes O
she O
always O
|
| O
retumed O
to O
this O
point O
, O
‘ O
Get O
me O
a O
situation O
— O
we O
hate O
each O
other O
, O
and O
I O
|
| O
um O
ready O
to O
go O
. O
” O
|

| O
And O
so O
the O
schoolmistress O
reconciled O
the O
recommendation O
to O
her O
con- O
|
| O
science O
, O
and O
the O
indentures O
were O
cancelled O
, O
and O
the O
apprentice O
was O
free O
. O
|
| O
The O
battle O
here O
described O
in O
a O
few O
lines O
, O
of O
course O
, O
lasted O
for O
some B-DATE
months I-DATE
. O
|
| O
And O
as O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
being O
now O
seventeen B-DATE
years I-DATE
of I-DATE
age I-DATE
, O
was O
about O
to O
leave O
|
| O
school O
, O
and O
had O
a O
friendship O
for O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
( O
‘ O
’ O
tis O
the O
only O
point O
in O
|
| O
Amelia B-PERSON
’s O
behaviour O
, O
” O
said O
Minerva B-ORG
, O
‘ O
‘ O
which O
has O
not O
been O
satisfactory O
to O
|
| O
her O
mistress O
, O
” O
) O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
was O
invited O
by O
her O
friend O
to O
pass O
a B-DATE
week I-DATE
with O
|
| O
her O
* O
home O
, O
before O
she O
entered O
upon O
her O
duties O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
private O
|
| O
family O
. O
|

| O
You O
may O
be O
sure O
that O
she O
showed O
Rebecca B-PERSON
over O
every O
room O
of O
the O
|
| O
house O
, O
and O
everything O
in O
every O
one O
of O
her O
drawers O
  O
and O
her O
books O
, O
and O
|
| O
her O
piano O
, O
and O
her O
dresses O
, O
and O
all O
her O
necklaces O
, O
brooches O
, O
laces O
, O
and O
|
| O
gimcracks O
. O
She O
insisted O
upon O
Rebecca B-PERSON
accepting O
the O
white O
cornelian O
and O
|
| O
the O
turquoise O
rings O
, O
and O
a O
sweet O
sprigged O
muslin O
, O
which O
was O
too O
small O
for O
|
| O
her O
now O
, O
though O
it O
would O
fit O
her O
friend O
to O
a O
nicety O
  O
and O
she O
determined O
|
| O
in O
her O
heart O
to O
ask O
her O
mother O
’s O
permission O
to O
present O
her O
white O
Cashmere O
|
| O
shawl O
to O
her O
friend O
. O
Could O
she O
not O
spare O
it O
? O
and O
had O
not O
her O
brother O
|
| O
Joseph B-PERSON
just O
brought O
her O
two B-CARDINAL
from O
India B-GPE
? O
|

| O
“ O
Not O
alone O
, O
” O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
“ O
‘ O
you O
know O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
I O
shall O
always O
be O
your O
|
| O
friend O
, O
and O
love O
you O
as O
a O
sister O
— O
indeed O
I O
will O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Ah O
, O
but O
to O
have O
parents O
, O
as O
you O
have O
— O
kind O
, O
rich O
, O
affectionate O
parents O
, O
|
| O
who O
give O
you O
everything O
you O
ask O
for O
  O
and O
their O
love O
, O
which O
is O
more O
pre- O
|
| O
cious O
than O
all O
! O
My O
poor O
papa O
could O
give O
me O
nothing O
, O
and O
I O
had O
but O
two B-CARDINAL
|
| O
frocks O
in O
all O
the O
world O
! O
And O
then O
, O
to O
have O
a O
brother O
, O
a O
dear O
brother O
! O
|
| O
Oh O
how O
you O
must O
love O
him O
! O
” O
|

| O
Amelia B-PERSON
laughed O
. O
|

| O
* O
* O
What O
! O
do O
n’t O
you O
love O
him O
? O
you O
, O
who O
say O
you O
love O
everybody O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Yes O
, O
of O
course O
, O
I O
do O
— O
only O
— O
” O
, O
|

| O
“ O
Only O
what O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Only B-WORK_OF_ART
Joseph I-WORK_OF_ART
does O
n’t O
seem O
to O
care O
much O
whether O
I O
love O
him O
or O
not O
. O
|
| O
He O
gave O
me O
two B-CARDINAL
fingers O
to O
shake O
when O
he O
arrived O
after O
ten B-DATE
years I-DATE
’ I-DATE
absence O
! O
|
| O
He O
is O
very O
kind O
and O
good O
, O
but O
he O
scarcely O
ever O
speaks O
to O
me O
  O
I O
think O
he O
|
| O
loves O
his O
pipe O
a O
great O
deal O
better O
than O
his O
” O
* O
* O
* O
but O
here O
Amelia B-PERSON
|
| O
checked O
herself O
, O
for O
why O
should O
she O
speak O
ill O
of O
her O
brother O
? O
‘ O
‘ O
He O
was O
|
| O
very O
kind O
to O
me O
as O
a O
child O
, O
” O
she O
added O
  O
‘ O
‘ O
I O
was O
but O
five B-DATE
years I-DATE
old I-DATE
when O
|
| O
he O
went O
away O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Is O
n't O
he O
very O
rich O
? O
” O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
. O
‘ O
They O
say O
all O
Indian B-NORP
nabobs O
are O
|
| O
enormously O
rich O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
T O
believe O
he O
has O
a O
very O
large O
income O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
And O
is O
your O
sister O
- O
in O
- O
law O
a O
nice O
pretty O
woman O
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
La B-WORK_OF_ART
! I-WORK_OF_ART
Joseph B-PERSON
is O
not O
married O
, O
” O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
again O
. O
|

| O
Perhaps O
she O
had O
mentioned O
the O
fact O
already O
to O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
but O
that O
young O
|

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
15 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
“ O
No O
, O
it O
does O
n’t O
, O
” O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O
‘ O
Come O
in O
, O
do O
n’t O
be O
frightened O
. O
Papa O
|
| O
wo O
nt O
do O
you O
any O
harm O
. O
” O
|

 

| O
CHAPTER O
III O
. O
|
| O
REBECCA O
IS O
IN O
PRESENCE O
OF O
THE O
ENEMY O
. O
|

| O
very O
stout O
, O
puffy O
man O
, O
in O
buckskins O
and O
hessian B-NORP
|
| O
boots O
, O
with O
several O
immense O
neckcloths O
, O
that O
|
| O
rose O
almost O
to O
his O
nose O
, O
with O
a O
red O
striped O
|
| O
waistcoat O
and O
an O
apple O
green O
coat O
with O
steel O
|
| O
buttons O
almost O
as O
large O
as O
crown O
pieces O
, O
( O
it O
|
| O
was O
the B-TIME
morning I-TIME
costume O
of O
a O
dandy O
or O
blood O
|
| O
of O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
) O
was O
reading O
the O
paper O
by O
the O
|
| O
  O
-fire O
when O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
girls O
entered O
, O
and O
bounced O
|

| O
— O
_ O
— O
— O
| | O
* O
off O
his O
arm O
- O
chair O
, O
and O
blushed O
excessively O
, O
and O
|
| O
hid O
his O
entire O
face O
almost O
in O
his O
neckcloths O
at O
this O
apparition O
. O
|

| O
“ O
It O
’s O
only O
your O
sister O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
” O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
and O
shaking O
the O
|
| O
two B-CARDINAL
fingers O
which O
he O
held O
out O
. O
‘ O
I O
’ve O
come O
home O
for O
good O
you O
know O
  O
|
| O
and O
this O
is O
my O
friend O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
whom O
you O
have O
heard O
me O
mention O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
No O
, O
never O
, O
upon O
my O
word O
, O
” O
said O
the O
head O
under O
the O
neckcloth O
, O
shak- O
|
| O
ing O
very O
much O
, O
— O
“ O
that O
is O
, O
yes,—what O
abominably O
cold O
weather O
, O
Miss B-PERSON
  O
” O
— O
|
| O
and O
herewith O
he O
fell O
to O
poking O
the O
fire O
with O
all O
his O
might O
, O
although O
it O
was O
|
| O
in O
the B-DATE
middle I-DATE
of I-DATE
June I-DATE
. O
|

| O
“ O
He O
’s O
very O
handsome O
, O
” O
whispered O
Rebecca B-PERSON
to O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
rather O
loud O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Do O
you O
think O
so O
? O
” O
said O
the O
latter O
, O
“ O
Ill B-ORG
tell O
him O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Darling O
! O
not O
for O
worlds O
, O
” O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
starting O
back O
as O
timid O
|
| O
as O
afawn O
. O
She O
had O
previously O
made O
a O
respectful O
virgin O
- O
like O
curtsey O
to O
|
| O
the O
gentleman O
, O
and O
her O
modest O
eyes O
gazed O
so O
perseveringly O
on O
the O
carpet O
|
| O
that O
it O
was O
a O
wonder O
how O
she O
should O
have O
found O
an O
opportunity O
to O
see O
him O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Thank O
you O
for O
the O
beautiful O
shawls O
, O
brother O
, O
” O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
to O
the O
fire- O
|
| O
poker O
. O
‘ O
Are O
they O
not O
beautiful O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
? O
” O
|

| O
“ O
O O
heavenly O
! O
” O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
and O
’ O
her O
eyes O
went O
from O
the O
carpet O
|
| O
straight O
to O
the O
chandelier O
. O
|

| O
Joseph B-PERSON
still O
continued O
a O
huge O
clattering O
at O
the O
poker O
and O
tongs O
, O
puffing O
|
| O
and O
blowing O
the O
while O
, O
and O
turning O
as O
red O
as O
his O
yellow O
face O
coat O
allow O
|
| O
him O
. O
‘ O
TI O
ca O
n’t O
make O
you O
such O
handsome O
presents O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
” O
continued O
his O
|
| O
sister O
, O
“ O
but O
while O
I O
was O
at O
school O
, O
I O
have O
embroidered O
for O
you O
a O
very O
|
| O
beautiful O
pair O
of O
braces O
. O
” O
|

| O
“ O
Good B-WORK_OF_ART
Gad I-WORK_OF_ART
! O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
” O
cried O
the O
brother O
, O
in O
serious O
alarm O
, O
“ O
what O
do O
|
| O
you O
mean O
? O
” O
and O
plunging O
with O
all O
his O
might O
at O
the O
bell O
- O
rope O
, O
that O
article O
|
| O
of O
furniture O
came O
away O
in O
his O
hand O
, O
and O
increased O
the O
honest O
fellow O
’s O
con- O
|
| O
fusion O
. O
“ O
For O
heaven O
’s O
sake O
see O
if O
my O
buggy O
’s O
at O
the O
door O
. O
I O
ca O
n’t O
wait O
. O
|
| O
I O
must O
go O
. O
D O
— O
that O
groom O
of O
mine O
. O
I O
must O
go O
. O
” O
|

| O
At O
this B-TIME
minute I-TIME
the O
father O
of O
the O
family O
walked O
in O
, O
rattling O
his O
seals O
like O
|
| O
a O
true O
British B-NORP
merchant O
. O
‘ O
‘ O
What O
’s O
the O
matter O
, O
Emiby B-ORG
? O
” O
says O
he O
. O
|

| O
“ O
Joseph B-PERSON
wants O
me O
to O
see O
if O
his O
— O
his O
buggy O
is O
at O
the O
door O
, O
What O
is O
a O
|
| O
buggy O
, O
papa O
? O
” O
|

  

| O
A O
NOVEL O
WITHOUT O
A O
HERO B-ORG
. O
7 B-CARDINAL
|

 

| O
« O
Tt O
is O
a O
one B-CARDINAL
- O
horse O
palanquin O
, O
” O
said O
the O
old O
gentleman O
, O
who O
was O
a O
wag O
|
| O
in O
his O
way O
. O
|
