|

| O
C O
0 O
N O
I O
N O
G O
S O
B O
Y O
  O
|
| O
NEW O
GENEBATION O
. O
|
| O
D O
Is O
R O
A O
ELI B-ORG
, O
ES O
Q. O
M.P. O
|
| O
ALTHOR O
OF O
` O
` O
COMNTARINI O
LEMING O
, O
'' O
|
| O
eca B-PERSON
eitiau I-PERSON
. O
|
| O
vOL O
. O
I. B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
LO I-PERSON
N I-PERSON
D O
ON O
|
| O
HENRY O
COLBU O
RN O
, O
PUBLISHER B-ORG
, O
|
| O
sem- O
|
| O
HEN B-ORG
RY I-ORG
H I-ORG
OPE I-ORG
|
| O
Ir O
is O
not O
because O
these O
volumes O
were O
con- O
|
| O
ceived O
and O
partly O
executed O
amid O
the O
glades O
and O
|
| O
galleries O
of O
the O
DEPDENE O
, O
that O
I O
have O
inscribed O
|
| O
them O
with O
your O
name O
. O
Nor O
merely O
because O
I O
|
| O
was O
desirous O
to O
avail O
myself O
of O
the O
most O
graeeful O
|
| O
privilege O
of O
an O
author O
, O
and O
dedicate O
my O
work O
to O
|
| O
the O
friend O
, O
whose O
talents O
I O
have O
always O
appre- O
|
| O
ciated O
and O
whose O
virtues O
I O
have O
ever O
admired O
. O
|
| O
But O
because O
in O
these O
pages O
I O
have O
endea- O
|
| O
voured O
to O
picture O
something O
of O
that O
development O
|
| O
of O
the O
new O
and O
, O
as O
I O
believe O
, O
better O
mind O
of O
|
| O
England B-GPE
, O
that O
has O
often O
been O
the O
subject O
of O
our O
|
| O
converse O
and O
speculation O
. O
|
| O
In O
these O
volumes O
you O
will O
find O
many O
a O
thought O
|
| O
illustrated O
and O
many O
a O
principle O
attempted O
to O
be O
|
| O
DEDICATION B-GPE
. O
|
| O
established O
that O
we O
have O
often O
together O
partially O
|
| O
discussed O
and O
canvassed O
. O
Doubtless O
you O
may O
|
| O
encounter O
some O
opinions O
with O
which O
you O
may O
|
| O
not O
agree O
, O
and O
some O
conclusions O
the O
uccuracy O
|
| O
of O
which O
you O
may O
find O
cause O
to O
question O
. O
But O
|
| O
if O
I O
have O
generally O
succeeded O
in O
my O
object O
: O
to O
|
| O
scatter O
some O
suggestions O
that O
may O
tend O
to O
ele- O
|
| O
vate O
the O
tone O
of O
public O
life O
  O
ascertain O
the O
true O
|
| O
character O
of O
political O
parties O
  O
and O
induce O
us O
for O
|
| O
the O
future O
more O
carefully O
to O
distinguish O
between O
|
| O
facts O
and O
phrases O
, O
realities O
and O
phantoms O
  O
I O
|
| O
believe O
that O
I O
shall O
gain O
your O
sympathy O
, O
for O
1I O
|
| O
shall O
find O
a O
reflex O
to O
their O
efforts O
in O
your O
own O
|
| O
generous O
spirit O
and O
enlightened O
mind O
. O
|
| O
Grosvenor B-FAC
Gate I-FAC
, O
|
| O
May B-DATE
- I-DATE
Day I-DATE
, O
18 B-CARDINAL
|

| O
C O
0 O
N O
IN O
G O
S O
B O
Y. O
|
| O
BOOK O
I. O
|
| O
cHAPTER O
I. B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Ir O
was O
a O
bright O
May B-TIME
morning I-TIME
some O
twelve B-DATE
|
| I-DATE
years I-DATE
ago I-DATE
, O
when O
a O
youth O
of O
still O
tender O
age O
, O
for O
|
| O
he O
had O
certainly O
not O
entered O
his O
teens O
by O
more O
|
| O
than O
two B-DATE
years I-DATE
, O
was O
ushered O
into O
the O
waiting- O
|
| O
room O
of O
a O
house O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
St. B-GPE
James I-GPE
's I-GPE
|
| O
Square B-FAC
, O
which O
, O
though O
with O
the O
general O
appear- O
|
| O
ance O
of O
a O
private O
residence O
, O
and O
that O
too O
of O
no O
|
| O
very O
ambitious O
character O
, O
exhibited O
at O
this O
period O
|
| O
oL. O
J. B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
coNINGSBY I-PERSON
. O
|
| O
symptoms O
of O
being O
occupied O
for O
some O
public O
|
| O
purpose O
. O
|
| O
The O
house O
door O
was O
constantly O
open O
, O
and O
|
| O
frequent O
guests O
even O
at O
this B-TIME
early I-TIME
hour I-TIME
crossed O
|
| O
the O
threshold O
. O
The O
hall O
table O
was O
covered O
with O
|
| O
sealed O
letters O
  O
and O
the O
hall O
porter O
inscribed O
in O
a O
|
| O
book O
the O
name O
of O
every O
individual O
who O
entered O
. O
|
| O
The O
young O
gentleman O
we O
have O
mentioned O
|
| O
found O
himself O
in O
a O
room O
which O
offered O
few O
|
| O
resources O
for O
his O
amusement O
. O
A O
large O
table O
|
| O
amply O
covered O
with O
writing O
materials O
, O
and O
a O
few O
|
| O
chairs O
wcre O
its O
sole O
furniture O
, O
except O
the O
grey O
|
| O
drugget O
that O
covered O
the O
floor O
, O
and O
a O
muddy O
|
| O
mezzotinto O
of O
the B-GPE
Duke I-GPE
of I-GPE
Wellington I-GPE
that O
|
| O
adorned O
its O
cold O
walls O
. O
There O
was O
not O
even O
|
| O
a O
ncwspaper O
  O
and O
the O
only O
books O
were O
the O
|
| O
Court B-ORG
Guide I-ORG
and O
the B-ORG
London I-ORG
Directory I-ORG
. O
For O
|
| O
some O
time O
, O
he O
remained O
with O
patient O
endurance O
|
| O
planted O
against O
the O
wall O
, O
with O
his O
feet O
resting O
on O
|
| O
the O
rail O
of O
his O
chair O
  O
but O
at O
length O
in O
his O
shifting O
|
| O
posture O
he O
gave O
evidence O
of O
his O
restlessness O
, O
rose O
|
| O
from O
his O
seat O
, O
looked O
out O
of O
the O
window O
into O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
a O
smal O
side O
court O
of O
the O
house O
surrounded O
with O
|
| O
dead O
walls O
, O
paced O
the O
room O
, O
took O
up O
the B-ORG
Court I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Guide I-ORG
, O
changed O
it O
for O
the B-ORG
London I-ORG
Directory I-ORG
, O
|
| O
then O
wrote O
his O
name O
over O
several O
sheets O
of O
|
| O
foolscap O
paper O
, O
drew O
various O
landscapes O
and O
faces O
|
| O
of O
his O
firiends B-GPE
  O
and O
then O
, O
splitting O
up O
a O
pen O
or O
|
| O
two B-CARDINAL
, O
delivered O
himself O
of O
a O
yawn O
which O
seemed O
|
| O
the O
climax O
of O
his O
weariness O
. O
|
| O
And O
yet O
the O
youth O
's O
appearance O
did O
not O
|
| O
betoken O
a O
character O
that O
, O
if O
the O
opportunity O
had O
|
| O
offered O
, O
could O
not O
have O
found O
amusement O
and O
|
| O
even O
instruction O
. O
His O
countenance O
, O
radiant O
with O
|
| O
health O
and O
the O
lustre O
of O
innocence O
, O
was O
at O
the O
|
| O
same O
time O
thoughtful O
and O
resolute O
. O
The O
expres- O
|
| O
sion O
of O
his O
deep O
blue O
eye O
was O
serious O
. O
Without O
|
| O
extreme O
regularity O
of O
features O
, O
the O
face O
was O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
that O
would O
never O
have O
passed O
unobserved O
. O
His O
|
| O
short O
upper O
lip O
indicated O
a O
good O
breed O
  O
and O
his O
|
| O
chestnut O
curls O
cdlustered O
over O
his O
open O
brow O
, O
while O
|
| O
his O
shirt O
collar O
thrown O
over O
his O
shoulders O
was O
|
| O
unrestrained O
by O
handkerchief O
or O
ribbon O
. O
Add O
to O
|
| O
this O
, O
a O
limber O
and O
graecful O
figure O
, O
which O
the O
jacket O
|
| O
n O
2 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
of O
his O
boyish O
dress O
exhibited O
to O
great O
ad- O
|
| O
vantage O
. O
|
| O
Just O
as O
the O
youth O
, O
mounted O
on O
a O
chair O
, O
was O
|
| O
adjusting O
the O
portrait O
of O
the O
Duke O
which O
he O
had O
|
| O
observed O
to O
be O
awry O
, O
the O
gentleman O
for O
whom O
|
| O
he O
had O
been O
all O
this O
time O
waiting O
entered O
the O
|
| O
room O
. O
|
| O
Floreat O
Etona O
1 O
'' O
hastily O
exclaimed O
the O
gen- O
|
| O
tleman O
in O
a O
sharp O
voice O
, O
` O
` O
you O
are O
setting O
the O
|
| O
Duke B-ORG
to O
rights O
. O
I O
have O
left O
you O
a O
long O
time O
a O
|
| O
prisoner O
  O
but O
I O
found O
them O
so O
busy O
here O
, O
that O
I O
|
| O
myself O
made O
my O
escape O
with O
difficulty O
. O
'' O
|
| O
He O
who O
uttered O
these O
words O
was O
a O
man O
of O
|
| O
middle O
size O
and O
age O
, O
originaly B-GPE
in O
al B-GPE
probability O
|
| O
of O
a O
spare O
habit O
, O
but O
now O
a O
little O
inclined O
to O
cor- O
|
| O
pulency O
. O
Baldness O
perhaps O
contributed O
to O
the O
|
| O
spiritual O
expression O
of O
a O
brow O
, O
which O
was O
how- O
|
| O
ever O
essentially O
intellectual O
, O
and O
gave O
some O
cha- O
|
| O
racter O
of O
openness O
to O
a O
countenance O
which O
, O
|
| O
though O
not O
ill O
- O
favoured O
, O
was O
unhappily O
stamped O
|
| O
by O
a O
sinister O
character O
that O
was O
not O
to O
be O
mis- O
|
| O
taken O
. O
His O
manner O
was O
easy O
, O
but O
rather O
auda- O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
cious O
than O
well O
- O
bred O
. O
Indeed O
, O
whilo O
a O
visage O
|
| O
which O
might O
otherwise O
be O
described O
as O
handsome O
|
| O
was O
spoilt O
by O
a O
dishonest O
glance O
, O
so O
a O
demean- O
|
| O
our O
that O
was O
by O
no O
means O
deficient O
in O
self O
- O
pos- O
|
| O
session O
and O
facility O
, O
was O
tainted O
by O
an O
innate O
|
| O
vulgarity O
, O
which O
in O
the O
long O
run O
, O
though O
seldom O
, O
|
| O
yet O
surely O
, O
developed O
itself O
|
| O
The O
youth O
had O
jumped O
off O
his O
chair O
on O
the O
|
| O
entrance O
of O
the O
gentleman O
, O
and O
then O
taking O
|
| O
up O
his O
hat O
, O
said O
: O
|
| O
` O
Shall B-PERSON
we O
go O
to O
grand O
- O
papa O
now O
, O
sir O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
|
| O
` O
` O
By O
all O
means O
, O
my O
dear O
boy O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
gentle- O
|
| O
man O
, O
putting O
his O
arm O
within O
that O
of O
the O
youth O
  O
|
| O
and O
they O
were O
just O
on O
the O
point O
of O
leaving O
the O
|
| O
waiting O
- O
room O
, O
when O
the O
door O
was O
suddenly O
|
| O
thrown O
open O
and O
two B-CARDINAL
individuals O
, O
in O
a O
state O
of O
|
| O
very O
great O
excitement O
, O
rushed O
into O
the O
apartment O
. O
|
| O
' O
Rigby O
- O
Rigby O
'' O
they O
both O
exclaimed O
at O
|
| O
the O
same O
moment O
. O
` O
` O
By O
G- O
they O
're O
out O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
Who O
told O
you2 B-PERSON
'' O
|
| O
The O
best O
authority O
  O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
themselves O
. O
'' O
|
 | O
Who O
-- O
who O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
|
| O
coNINGsBY O
. O
|
| O
` O
Paul B-PERSON
Evelyn I-PERSON
  O
I O
met O
him O
as O
I O
passed O
|
| O
Brookes O
' O
, O
and O
he O
told O
me O
that O
Lord O
Grey O
had O
re- O
|
| O
signed O
, O
and O
the O
Iing O
had O
accepted O
his O
resigna- O
|
| O
tion O
. O
'' O
|
| O
But O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
who O
, O
though O
very O
fond O
of O
|
| O
news O
and O
much O
interested O
in O
the O
present O
, O
was O
|
| O
extremely O
jealous O
of O
any O
one B-CARDINAL
giving O
him O
in- O
|
| O
formation O
, O
was O
sceptical O
. O
He O
declared O
that O
|
| O
Paul B-PERSON
Evelyn I-PERSON
was O
always O
wrong O
  O
that O
it O
was O
|
| O
norally O
impossible O
that O
Paul B-PERSON
Evelyn I-PERSON
could O
ever O
|
| O
be O
right O
  O
that O
he O
knew O
, O
from O
the O
highest O
au- O
|
| O
thority O
, O
that O
Lord O
Grey O
had O
been O
twice O
yesterda O
. O
|
| O
with O
the O
King O
  O
that O
on O
the O
last O
visit O
nothing O
|
| O
was O
settled O
  O
that O
if O
he O
had O
been O
at O
the O
palace O
|
| O
gain O
to O
- O
day O
, O
he O
could O
not O
have O
been O
there O
|
| O
beforc O
twelve B-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
  O
that O
it O
was O
only O
now O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Varter B-ORG
to O
one O
  O
that O
Lord O
Grey O
would O
have O
|
| O
called O
his O
colleagues O
togetbher O
on O
his O
return O
  O
that O
|
| O
` O
ethe O
must O
bhe O
epse O
Mre B-PERSON
an- O
|
| O
ie O
e O
by O
e O
ast O
. O
.i O
. O
|
| O
` O
eeee O
ie B-PERSON
aen I-PERSON
. O
|
| O
evea B-PERSON
ineidnt O
or O
the O
lse O
twenty O
- O
uI O
, O
, O
, O
|
| O
CoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
( O
and O
nobody O
was O
stronger O
in O
dates O
than O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-GPE
) O
  O
counted O
even O
the O
number O
of O
stairs O
which O
|
| O
the O
minister O
had O
to O
ascend O
and O
descend O
in O
his O
|
| O
visit O
to O
the O
palace O
, O
and O
the O
time O
their O
mount- O
|
| O
ings O
and O
dismountings O
must O
have O
absorbed O
, O
|
| O
( O
detail O
was O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
's O
forte O
) O
  O
and O
finally O
, O
what O
|
| O
with O
his O
dates O
, O
his O
private O
information O
, O
his O
know- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ledge I-PERSON
of O
palace O
localities O
, O
his O
contempt O
for O
Paul B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Evelyn I-PERSON
, O
and O
his O
confidence O
in O
himsolf O
, O
he O
suc- O
|
| O
ceeded O
in O
persuading O
his O
downcast O
and O
dis- O
|
| O
hcartened O
friends O
, O
that O
their O
comfortable O
intelli- O
|
| O
goence O
had O
not O
the O
slightest O
foundation O
. O
|
| O
They O
all O
left O
the O
room O
together O
  O
they O
were O
|
| O
in O
the O
hall O
  O
the O
gentlemen O
who O
brought O
the O
|
| O
news O
looking O
somewhat O
depressed O
but O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
gay O
even O
amid O
the O
prostration O
of O
his O
|
| O
party O
, O
from O
the O
consciousness O
that O
he O
had O
most O
|
| O
critically O
demolished O
a O
piece O
of O
political O
gossip O
, O
|
| O
nnd O
eonveyed O
a O
certain O
degree O
of O
mortification O
|
| O
to O
a O
couple O
of O
his O
companions O
  O
when O
a O
travelling O
|
| O
carriage O
and O
four B-CARDINAL
with O
a O
ducal O
coronet O
drove O
up O
|
| O
to O
the O
house O
. O
The O
door O
was O
thrown O
open O
, O
the O
|
| O
CONINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
steps O
dashed O
down O
, O
and O
a O
youthful O
noble O
sprang O
|
| O
from O
his O
chariot O
into O
the O
hall O
. O
|
 | O
Good O
morning O
, O
Rigby B-GPE
, O
'' O
snid O
the O
Duke O
, O
|
| O
I O
see O
your O
Grace B-PERSON
well O
, O
I O
am O
sure O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
, O
with O
a O
very O
softened O
manner O
. O
|
 | O
You O
have O
heard O
the O
news O
, O
gentlemen O
? O
'' O
he O
|
| O
continued O
. O
|
 | O
What O
news2 B-PERSON
Yes O
- O
no O
- O
that O
is O
to O
say- O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
thinks- O
'' O
|
| O
You O
know O
, O
of O
course O
, O
that O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
|
| O
is O
with O
the O
King O
'' O
|
| O
It O
is O
impossible O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
I O
do O
n't O
think O
I O
can O
be O
mistaken O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
|
| O
Duke B-PERSON
smiling O
. O
|
| O
'' O
I O
will O
show O
your O
Grace B-ORG
that O
it O
is O
impossible O
, O
'' O
|
| O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
` O
` O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
slept O
at O
|
| O
Wimbledon B-EVENT
. O
Lord O
Grey O
could O
not O
have O
seen O
|
| O
the O
King O
until O
twelve B-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
  O
it O
is O
now O
five B-TIME
|
| I-TIME
minutes I-TIME
to O
one O
. O
It O
is O
impossible O
, O
therefore O
, O
that O
|
| O
any O
message O
from O
the O
IKing B-ORG
could O
have O
reached O
|
| O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
in O
time O
for O
his O
Lordship B-EVENT
to O
be O
|
| O
at O
the O
palace O
at O
this O
moment O
. O
'' O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
' O
But O
my O
authority O
is O
a O
very O
high O
one O
, O
'' O
|
| O
said O
the O
Duke B-ORG
. O
|
| O
` O
` O
Authority B-ORG
is O
a O
phrase O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
  O
|
| O
` O
' O
we O
must O
look O
to O
time O
and O
place O
, O
datcs O
and O
|
| O
localities O
, O
to O
discover O
the O
truth O
. O
'' O
|
| O
Your O
Grace B-PERSON
was O
saying O
that O
your O
autho- O
|
| O
rity- O
'' O
ventured O
to O
observe O
Mr. O
Tadpole B-PERSON
, O
em- O
|
| O
boldened O
by O
the O
presence O
of O
a O
duke O
, O
his O
patron O
, O
|
| O
to O
struggle O
against O
the O
despotism O
of O
a O
Rigby B-GPE
, O
|
| O
his O
tyrant O
. O
|
| O
Was O
the O
highest O
, O
'' O
rejoined O
the O
Duke O
smil- O
|
| O
ing O
  O
` O
` O
for O
it O
was O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
himself O
. O
I O
|
| O
came O
up O
from O
Nuneham B-GPE
this B-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
passed O
|
| O
his O
Lordship B-ORG
's O
house O
in O
Hyde B-FAC
Park I-FAC
Place I-FAC
as O
|
| O
he O
was O
getting O
into O
his O
carriage O
in O
full O
dress O
, O
|
| O
stopped O
my O
own O
, O
and O
learned O
in O
a O
breath O
, O
that O
|
| O
the O
Whigs B-GPE
were O
out O
, O
and O
that O
the O
King O
had O
|
| O
sent O
for O
the O
Chief O
Baron O
. O
So O
I O
came O
on O
here O
at O
|
| O
once O
. O
'' O
|
| O
` O
` O
I O
always O
thought O
the O
country O
was O
sound O
at O
|
| O
bottom O
, O
'' O
exclaimed O
Mr. O
Taper B-PERSON
, O
who O
, O
under O
the O
|
| O
old O
system O
, O
had O
sneaked O
into O
the B-ORG
Treasury I-ORG
Board I-ORG
. O
|
 | O
3 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGsBY O
. O
|
| O
Tadpole B-ORG
and O
Tuaper O
were O
great O
friends O
. O
Neither O
|
| O
of O
them O
ever O
despaired O
of O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Even O
if O
the B-PRODUCT
Reform I-PRODUCT
Bill I-PRODUCT
were O
passed O
, O
Taper B-GPE
was O
|
| O
convinced O
that O
the O
Whigs B-ORG
would O
never O
prove O
|
| O
men O
of O
business O
  O
and O
when O
his O
friends O
confessed O
|
| O
among O
themselves O
that O
a B-ORG
Tory I-ORG
Government I-ORG
was O
|
| O
for O
the O
future O
impossible O
, O
Taper O
would O
remark O
|
| O
in O
a O
confidential O
whisper O
, O
that O
for O
his O
part O
he O
|
| O
believed O
before O
the B-DATE
year I-DATE
was O
over O
, O
the O
Whigs B-ORG
|
| O
would O
be O
turned O
out O
by O
the O
clerks O
. O
|
| O
There O
is O
no O
doubt O
that O
there O
is O
considerable O
|
| O
re O
- O
action O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Tuadpole B-PERSON
. O
` O
` O
The O
infamous O
|
| O
conduct O
of O
the O
Whigs O
in O
the O
Amersham B-PERSON
case O
, O
|
| O
has O
opened O
the O
public O
mind O
more O
than O
anything O
, O
'' O
|
| O
` O
` O
Aldborough B-ORG
was O
worse O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Taper B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
' O
Teriblel B-WORK_OF_ART
'' O
said O
Tadpole B-ORG
. O
| | O
They O
said O
there O
|
| O
was O
no O
use O
discussing O
the B-PRODUCT
Reform I-PRODUCT
Bill I-PRODUCT
in O
our O
|
| O
heuse O
. O
I O
believe O
Rigby B-GPE
's O
great O
speech O
on O
|
| O
Aldborough B-ORG
has O
done O
more O
towards O
the O
re O
- O
action O
|
| O
t2e O
el O
the O
violenee O
ot O
al O
the O
polioal O
U O
|
| O
together O
. O
'' O
|
| O
` O
` O
Let O
us O
hope O
for O
the O
best O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
Dul B-ORG
|
| O
mildly O
. O
| | O
' O
Tis B-PERSON
a O
bold O
step O
on O
the O
part O
of O
the O
|
| O
Sovereign B-PRODUCT
, O
and O
I O
am O
free O
to O
say O
I O
could O
have O
|
| O
wished O
it O
postponed O
  O
but O
we O
must O
support O
the O
|
| O
King O
like O
men O
. O
What O
say O
you O
, O
Rigby B-ORG
? O
Youare O
|
| O
silent O
. O
'' O
|
| O
I O
am O
thinking O
what O
an O
unfortunate O
circum- O
|
| O
stance O
it O
was O
for O
the O
Sovereign B-PRODUCT
, O
the O
country O
, O
and O
|
| O
the O
party O
, O
that O
I O
did O
not O
breakfast O
with O
Lord O
|
| O
Lyndhurst O
this B-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
as O
I O
was O
nearly O
doing O
|
| O
instead O
of O
going O
down O
to O
Eton B-PERSON
. O
'' O
|
| O
To O
Eton B-PERSON
, O
and O
why O
to O
Eton2 O
'' O
|
| O
For O
the O
sake O
of O
my O
young O
friend O
here O
  O
|
| O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
's O
grandson O
. O
By O
the O
bye O
, O
you O
|
| O
are O
kinsmen O
. O
Let O
me O
present O
to O
your O
Grace- O
|
| O
MR O
. O
CoNINGsBY O
, O
'' O
|
| O
12 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGsBY O
. O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-LAW
II I-LAW
. O
|
| O
T O
political O
agitation O
which O
for O
a B-DATE
year I-DATE
and O
|
| O
a B-CARDINAL
half I-CARDINAL
had O
shaken O
England B-GPE
to O
its O
centre O
, O
re- O
|
| O
ceived O
if O
possible O
an O
increase O
to O
its O
intensity O
and O
|
| O
virulence O
, O
when O
it O
was O
known O
in O
the O
carly O
part O
|
| O
of O
the B-DATE
month I-DATE
of I-DATE
May I-DATE
, I-DATE
1832 I-DATE
, O
that O
the O
Prime O
|
| O
Minister O
had O
tendered O
his O
resignation O
to O
the O
|
| O
Iing O
, O
which O
resignation O
had O
been O
graciously O
|
| O
aceepted O
. O
|
| O
The O
amendment O
carried O
by O
the O
Opposition O
|
| O
in O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Lords I-ORG
on O
the O
evening O
of O
the O
|
| O
7th B-ORDINAL
of O
May B-DATE
, O
that O
the O
enfranchising O
clauses O
of O
|
| O
the B-PRODUCT
Reform I-PRODUCT
Bill I-PRODUCT
should O
be O
considered O
before O
|
| O
entering O
into O
the O
question O
of O
disfranchisement O
, O
|
| O
cCONINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
was O
the O
immediate O
cause O
of O
this O
startling O
event O
. O
|
| O
The O
Lords B-PRODUCT
had O
previously O
consented O
to O
the O
|
| O
second B-ORDINAL
reading O
of O
the O
Bill O
with O
the O
view O
of O
|
| O
preventing O
that O
large O
inerease O
of O
their O
numbers O
|
| O
with O
which O
they O
had O
been O
long O
menaced O
  O
rather O
|
| O
indeed O
by O
mysterious O
rumours O
than O
by O
any O
|
| O
official O
declaration O
  O
but O
nevertheless O
in O
a O
man- O
|
| O
ner O
which O
had O
carried O
conviction O
to O
no O
incon- O
|
| O
siderable O
portion O
of O
the O
Opposition O
that O
the O
|
| O
threat O
was O
not O
without O
foundation O
. O
|
| O
During O
the O
progress O
of O
the O
Bill O
through O
the O
|
| O
Lower B-FAC
House I-FAC
, O
the O
journals O
which O
were O
looked O
|
| O
upon O
as O
the O
organs O
of O
the O
ministry O
, O
had O
an- O
|
| O
nounced O
with O
unhesitating O
confidence O
, O
that O
Lord O
|
| O
Grey O
was O
armed O
with O
what O
was O
then O
called O
a O
|
| O
` O
` O
carte O
blanche O
'' O
to O
create O
any O
number O
of O
peers O
|
| O
necessary O
to O
insure O
its O
success O
. O
Nor O
were O
public O
|
| O
journalists O
under O
the O
control O
of O
the O
ministry O
, O
and O
|
| O
whose O
statements O
were O
never O
contradicted O
, O
the O
|
| O
sole O
authorities O
for O
this O
prevailing O
belief O
. O
|
| O
Members O
of O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Commons I-ORG
, O
who O
|
| O
were O
strong O
supporters O
of O
the O
cabinet O
, O
though O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
not O
connected O
with O
it O
by O
any O
official O
tie O
, O
had O
|
| O
unequivocally O
stated O
in O
their O
places O
that O
the O
|
| O
Sovereign B-PRODUCT
had O
not O
resisted O
the O
advice O
of O
his O
|
| O
counscllors O
to O
create O
peers O
, O
if O
such O
creation O
|
| O
were O
required O
to O
carry O
into O
effect O
what O
was O
then O
|
| O
styled O
` O
` O
the O
great O
national O
measure O
. O
'' O
In O
more O
|
| O
than O
one B-CARDINAL
instance O
, O
ministers O
had O
been O
warned O
, O
|
| O
that O
if O
they O
did O
not O
exercise O
that O
power O
with O
|
| O
prompt O
energy O
, O
they O
might O
deserve O
impeach- O
|
| O
ment O
. O
And O
these O
intimations O
and O
announce- O
|
| O
ments O
had O
been O
made O
in O
the O
presence O
of O
leading O
|
| O
members O
of O
the O
government O
, O
and O
had O
received O
|
| O
from O
them O
at O
least O
the O
sanction O
of O
their O
silence O
. O
|
| O
It O
did O
not O
subsequently O
appear O
that O
the O
Re- O
|
| O
form O
ministers O
had O
been O
invested O
with O
any O
such O
|
| O
power O
  O
but O
a O
conviction O
of O
the O
reverse O
fostered O
|
| O
by O
these O
circumstances O
had O
successfully O
acted O
upon O
|
| O
the O
nervous O
temperament O
, O
or O
thc B-PERSON
statesman O
- O
like O
|
| O
prudence O
, O
of O
a O
certain O
section O
of O
the O
peers O
, O
who O
|
| O
consequently O
hesitated O
in O
their O
course O
  O
werc O
|
| O
known O
as O
being O
no O
longer O
inclined O
to O
pursue O
|
| O
their O
policey O
of O
the O
preceding O
session O
, O
and O
who O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
had O
thus O
obtained O
a O
title O
at O
that O
moment O
rife O
|
| O
in O
everybody O
's O
mouth O
- O
the O
title O
of O
' O
` O
TuE B-WORK_OF_ART
|
| O
WAvERERS O
, O
'' O
|
| O
Notwithstanding O
therefore O
the O
opposition O
of O
|
| O
the B-GPE
Duke I-GPE
of I-GPE
Wellington I-GPE
and O
of O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
, O
|
| O
the O
Waverers O
carried O
the O
second B-ORDINAL
reading O
of O
the O
|
| O
Reform O
Bil O
  O
and O
then O
scared O
at O
the O
conse- O
|
| O
quences O
of O
their O
own O
headstrong O
timidity O
, O
they O
|
| O
went O
in O
a O
fright O
to O
the O
Duke O
and O
his O
able O
ad- O
|
| O
viser O
to O
extricate O
them O
from O
the O
inevitable O
|
| O
result O
of O
their O
own O
conduct O
. O
The O
ultimate O
|
| O
device O
of O
these O
distracted O
councils O
, O
where O
daring O
|
| O
and O
poltroonery O
, O
principle O
and O
expediency O
, O
pub- O
|
| O
lic O
spirit O
and O
private O
intrigue O
, O
all O
threw O
an O
|
| O
ingredient O
in O
the O
turbulent O
spell O
  O
was O
the O
cele- O
|
| O
brated O
and O
successful O
amendment O
to O
which O
we O
|
| O
have O
referred O
. O
|
| O
But O
the O
Whig O
ministers O
, O
who O
, O
whatever O
may O
|
| O
have O
been O
their O
faults O
, O
were O
at O
least O
men O
of O
|
| O
intellect O
and O
courage O
, O
were O
not O
to O
be O
beaten O
by O
|
| O
` O
` O
the O
Waverers O
. O
'' O
They O
might O
have O
made O
terms O
|
| O
with O
an O
audacious O
foe O
  O
they O
trampled O
on O
a O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-WORK_OF_ART
. O
|
| O
hesitating O
opponent O
. O
Lord O
Grey B-PERSON
hastened O
to O
|
| O
the O
Palace B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Before O
the O
result O
of O
this O
appeal O
to O
the O
Sove- O
|
| O
reign O
was O
known O
, O
for O
its O
effects O
were O
not O
im- O
|
| O
mediate O
, O
on O
the B-TIME
second I-TIME
morning I-TIME
after O
the O
vote O
|
| O
in O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Lords I-ORG
, O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
had O
made O
|
| O
that O
visit O
to O
ton O
which O
had O
summoned O
very O
|
| O
unexpectedly O
the O
youthful O
Coningsby B-PERSON
to O
Lon- O
|
| O
don O
. O
He O
was O
the O
orphan O
child O
of O
the O
youngest O
|
| O
of O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
sons O
of O
the B-ORG
Mlarquess I-ORG
of I-ORG
Monmouth I-ORG
. O
|
| O
It O
was O
a O
family O
famous O
for O
its O
hatreds O
. O
The O
|
| O
eldest O
son O
hated O
his O
father O
  O
and O
, O
it O
was O
said O
, O
in O
|
| O
spite O
had O
married O
a O
lady O
to O
whom O
that O
father O
|
| O
was O
attached O
, O
and O
with O
whom O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
|
| O
then O
meditated O
a O
second B-ORDINAL
alliance O
. O
This O
eldest O
|
| O
son O
lived O
at O
Naples B-GPE
, O
and O
had O
several O
child- O
|
| O
en O
, O
but O
maintained O
no O
connexion O
either O
with O
|
| O
his O
parents O
or O
his O
native O
country O
. O
On O
the O
|
| O
other O
hand O
, O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
hated O
his O
younget O
|
| O
son O
, O
who O
had O
married O
against O
his O
consent O
a O
|
| O
Woman B-ORG
to O
whom O
that O
son O
was O
devoted O
. O
A O
|
| O
ystem O
of O
domestic O
persecution O
, O
sustained O
by O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
the O
hand O
of O
a O
master O
, O
had O
eventually O
broken O
up O
|
| O
the O
health O
of O
its O
victim O
, O
who O
died O
of O
a O
fever O
in O
|
| O
a O
foreign O
country O
, O
where O
he O
had O
sought O
some O
|
| O
refuge O
from O
his O
creditors O
. O
|
| O
His O
widow O
returned O
to O
England B-GPE
with O
her O
|
| O
child O
  O
and O
, O
not O
having O
a O
relation O
, O
and O
scarce- O
|
| O
ly O
an O
acquaintancee O
in O
the O
world O
, O
made O
an O
|
| O
appeal O
to O
her O
husband O
's O
father O
, O
the O
wealthiest O
|
| O
noble O
in O
England B-GPE
, O
and O
a O
man O
who O
was O
often O
|
| O
prodigal O
, O
and O
occasionally O
generous O
. O
After O
some O
|
| O
time O
and O
more O
trouble O
, O
after O
urgent O
and O
repeated O
, O
|
| O
and O
what O
would O
have O
seemed O
heart O
- O
rending O
|
| O
solicitations O
, O
the O
attorney O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
|
| O
culled O
upon O
the O
widow O
of O
his O
client O
's O
son O
, O
and O
in- O
|
| O
formed O
her O
of O
his O
Lordship B-ORG
's O
decision O
. O
Provided O
|
| O
she O
gave O
up O
her O
child O
and O
permanently O
resided O
|
| O
in O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
remotest O
counties O
, O
he O
was O
|
| O
authorised O
to O
make O
her O
in O
four B-CARDINAL
quarterly B-DATE
pay- O
|
| O
mnents O
, O
the O
yearly O
allowance O
of O
three B-QUANTITY
hundred I-QUANTITY
|
| I-QUANTITY
pounds I-QUANTITY
, O
that O
being O
the O
income O
that O
Lord O
Mon- O
|
| O
mouth O
, O
who O
was O
the O
shrewdest O
accountant O
in O
the O
|
| O
country O
, O
had O
calculated O
a O
lone O
woman O
might O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
very O
decently O
exist O
upon O
in O
a O
small O
market O
|
| O
town O
in O
the O
county O
of O
Westmoreland B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Desperate O
necessity O
, O
the O
sense O
of O
her O
own O
|
| O
forlornness O
, O
the O
utter O
impossibility O
to O
strugglte O
|
| O
with O
an O
omnipotent O
foe O
, O
who O
, O
her O
husband O
had O
|
| O
taught O
her O
, O
was O
above O
all O
scruples O
, O
prejudices O
|
| O
and O
fears O
, O
and O
who O
though O
he O
respected O
law O
, O
|
| O
despised O
opinion O
, O
made O
the O
victim O
yield O
. O
But O
|
| O
her O
sufferings O
were O
not O
long O
  O
the O
separation O
|
| O
from O
her O
child O
, O
the O
bleak O
clime O
, O
the O
strange O
|
| O
faces O
around O
her O
, O
sharp O
memory O
, O
and O
the O
dull O
|
| O
routine O
of O
an O
unimpassioned O
life O
, O
all O
combined O
|
| O
to O
wear O
out O
a O
constitution O
originally O
frail O
, O
and O
|
| O
since O
shattered O
by O
many O
sorrows O
. O
Mrs. O
Co- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
ningsby I-PERSON
died O
the B-DATE
same I-DATE
day I-DATE
that O
her O
father O
- O
in- O
|
| O
law O
was O
made O
a O
Marquess B-GPE
. O
He O
deserved O
his O
|
| O
honours O
. O
The O
four B-CARDINAL
votes O
he O
had O
inherited O
in O
|
| O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Commons I-ORG
had O
been O
increased O
|
| O
by O
his O
intense O
volition O
and O
unsparing O
means O
to O
|
| O
ten B-CARDINAL
  O
and O
the B-DATE
very I-DATE
day I-DATE
he O
was O
raised O
to O
his O
|
| O
Marquisate B-ORG
, O
he O
commenced O
sapping O
fresh O
cor- O
|
| O
porations O
, O
and O
was O
working O
for O
the O
strawberry O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
leaf O
. O
His O
honours O
were O
proclaimed O
in O
the O
Lon- B-ORG
|
| O
don O
Gazette B-PERSON
, O
and O
her O
decease O
was O
not O
even O
|
| O
noticed O
in O
the B-ORG
County I-ORG
Chronicle I-ORG
  O
but O
the O
altars O
|
| O
of O
Nemesis B-NORP
are O
beneath O
every O
outraged O
roof O
, O
and O
|
| O
the O
death O
of O
this O
unhappy O
lady O
, O
apparently O
with- O
|
| O
out O
an O
earthly O
friend O
or O
an O
earthly O
hope O
, O
deso- O
|
| O
late O
and O
deserted O
, O
and O
dying O
in O
obscure O
poverty O
, O
|
| O
was O
not O
forgotten O
. O
|
| O
Coningsby B-PERSON
was O
not O
more B-DATE
than I-DATE
nine I-DATE
years I-DATE
|
| O
of O
age O
when O
he O
lost O
his O
last O
parent O
  O
and O
he O
|
| O
had O
then O
been O
separated O
from O
her O
for O
nearly B-DATE
|
| I-DATE
three I-DATE
years I-DATE
. O
But O
he O
remembered O
the O
sweet- O
|
| O
ness O
of O
his B-DATE
nursery I-DATE
days I-DATE
. O
His O
mother O
too O
|
| O
had O
written O
to O
him O
very O
frequently O
since O
he O
|
| O
quitted O
her O
, O
and O
her O
fond O
expressions O
had O
|
| O
cherished O
the O
tenderness O
of O
his O
heart O
. O
He O
wept O
|
| O
very O
bitterly O
when O
his O
schoolmaster O
broke O
to O
|
| O
him O
the O
news O
of O
his O
mother O
's O
death O
. O
True O
it O
|
| O
was O
, O
they O
had O
been O
long O
parted O
, O
and O
their O
|
| O
prospect O
of O
again O
meeting O
was O
vague O
and O
dim O
  O
|
| O
but O
his O
mother O
seemed O
to O
him O
his O
only O
link O
|
| O
to O
human O
society O
. O
It O
was O
something O
to O
have O
|
| O
20 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CONING8BY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
a O
mother O
, O
even O
if O
he O
never O
saw O
her O
. O
Other O
|
| O
boys O
went O
to O
see O
their O
mothers O
  O
he O
at O
least O
|
| O
could O
talk O
of O
his O
. O
Now O
he O
was O
alonc O
. O
His O
|
| O
grandfather O
was O
to O
him O
only O
a O
name O
. O
Lord O
|
| O
Monmouth B-GPE
resided O
almost O
constantly O
abroad O
, O
|
| O
and O
during O
his O
rare O
visits O
to O
England B-GPE
had O
found O
|
| O
no O
time O
or O
inclination O
to O
see O
the O
orphan O
with O
|
| O
whom O
he O
felt O
no O
sympathy O
. O
Even O
the O
death O
|
| O
of O
the O
boy O
's O
mother O
, O
and O
the O
consequent O
ar- O
|
| O
rangements O
, O
were O
notified O
to O
his O
master O
by O
a O
|
| O
stranger O
. O
The O
letter O
which O
brought O
the O
sad O
|
| O
intelligence O
was O
from O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
It O
was O
the O
|
| O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
that O
name O
had O
been O
known O
to O
Co- O
|
| O
ningsby O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
was O
a O
member O
for O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
Lord O
|
| O
Monmouth B-GPE
's O
boroughs O
. O
He O
was O
the O
manager O
|
| O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
's O
parliamentary O
influence O
, O
|
| O
and O
the O
auditor O
of O
his O
vast O
estates O
. O
He O
was O
|
| O
more O
  O
he O
was O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
's O
companion O
|
| O
when O
in O
England B-GPE
, O
his O
correspondent O
when O
|
| O
abroad O
- O
hardly O
his O
counsellor O
, O
for O
Lord O
Mon- O
|
| O
mouth O
never O
required O
advice O
  O
but O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
21 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
could O
instruct O
him O
in O
matters O
of O
detail O
, O
which O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
made O
amusing O
. O
Rigby B-ORG
was O
not O
a O
|
| O
professional O
man O
  O
indeed O
, O
his O
origin O
, O
education O
, O
|
| O
early O
pursuits O
, O
and O
studies O
, O
were O
equally O
obscure O
  O
|
| O
but O
he O
had O
contrived O
in O
good O
time O
to O
squeeze O
|
| O
himself O
into O
Parliament B-ORG
, O
by O
means O
which O
no O
|
| O
one O
could O
ever O
comprehend O
, O
and O
then O
set O
up O
|
| O
to O
be O
a O
perfect O
man O
of O
business O
. O
The O
world O
|
| O
took O
him O
at O
his O
word O
, O
for O
he O
was O
bold O
, O
acute O
, O
|
| O
and O
voluble O
  O
with O
no O
thought O
, O
but O
a O
good O
deal O
|
| O
of O
desultory O
information O
  O
and O
though O
destitute O
of O
|
| O
all O
imagination O
and O
noble O
sentiment O
, O
was O
blessed O
|
| O
with O
a O
vigorous O
, O
mendacious O
faney O
, O
fruitful O
in O
|
| O
small O
expedients O
, O
and O
never O
happier O
than O
when O
|
| O
devising O
shifts O
for O
great O
men O
's O
scrapes O
. O
|
| O
They O
say O
that O
all O
of O
us O
have O
one B-CARDINAL
chance O
in O
this O
|
| O
life O
, O
and O
so O
it O
was O
with O
Rigby B-ORG
. O
After O
a O
struggle O
|
| O
of O
many B-DATE
years I-DATE
, O
after O
a O
long O
series O
of O
the O
usual O
|
| O
alternatives O
of O
small O
successes O
and O
small O
failures O
, O
|
| O
after O
a O
few O
cleverish O
speeches O
and O
a O
good O
many O
|
| O
cleverish O
pamphlets O
, O
with O
a O
considerable O
reputa- O
|
| O
tion O
indeed O
for O
pasquinades O
, O
most O
of O
which O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
he O
never O
wrote O
, O
the O
articles O
in O
reviews O
to O
which O
|
| O
it O
was O
whispered O
he O
had O
contributed O
, O
Rigby B-ORG
, O
|
| O
who O
had O
already O
intrigued O
himself O
into O
a O
subor- O
|
| O
dinate O
office O
, O
met O
with O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
He O
was O
just O
the O
animal O
that O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
|
| O
wanted O
, O
for O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
always O
looked O
upon O
|
| O
human O
nature O
with O
the O
callous O
eye O
of O
a O
jockey O
. O
|
| O
He O
surveyed O
Rigby B-GPE
, O
and O
he O
determined O
to O
buy O
|
| O
him O
. O
He O
bought O
him O
  O
with O
his O
clear O
head O
, O
his O
|
| O
indefatigable O
industry O
, O
his O
audacious O
tongue O
, O
and O
|
| O
his O
ready O
and O
unscrupulous O
pen O
  O
with O
all O
his O
|
| O
dates O
, O
all O
his O
lampoons O
  O
all O
his O
private O
memoirs O
, O
|
| O
and O
all O
his O
political O
intrigues O
. O
It O
was O
a O
good O
|
| O
purchase O
. O
Rigby O
became O
a O
great O
personage O
, O
and O
|
| O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
's O
man O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
who O
liked O
to O
be O
doing O
a O
great O
|
| O
many O
things O
at O
the O
same O
time O
, O
and O
to O
astonish O
|
| O
the O
Tadpoles B-PRODUCT
and O
Tapers O
with O
his O
energetic O
|
| O
versatility O
, O
determined O
to O
superintend O
the O
educa- O
|
| O
tion O
of O
Coningsby B-GPE
. O
It O
was O
a O
relation O
which O
|
| O
iie B-PERSON
i O
i O
he O
oohoue O
orhi O
ppl O
|
| O
v O
epy O
speasing O
, O
his O
charge O
: O
for O
Mr. O
R B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
affected O
rather O
the O
graeful O
dignity O
of O
the O
gover- O
|
| O
nor O
than O
the O
duties O
of O
a O
tutor O
. O
The O
boy O
was O
re- O
|
| O
alled O
from O
his O
homely O
, O
rural O
school O
, O
where O
he O
|
| O
had O
been O
well O
grounded O
by O
a O
hard O
- O
working O
|
| O
curate O
, O
and O
affectionately O
tended O
by O
the O
|
| O
curate O
's O
unsophisticated O
wife O
. O
He O
was O
sent O
to O
|
| O
a O
fashionable O
school O
preparatory O
. O
to O
Eton B-ORG
, O
where O
|
| O
he O
found O
about B-CARDINAL
two I-CARDINAL
hundred I-CARDINAL
youths O
of O
noble O
|
| O
families O
and O
connexions O
lodged O
in O
a O
magnificent O
|
| O
villa O
, O
that O
had O
once O
been O
the O
retreat O
of O
a O
mi- O
|
| O
nister O
, O
superintended O
by O
a O
sycophantie O
Doctor O
of O
|
| O
Divinity B-GPE
, O
alrcady O
wall O
beneficed O
, O
and O
not O
despair- O
|
| O
ing O
of O
a O
bishopric O
by O
favouring O
the O
children O
of O
|
| O
great O
nobles O
. O
The O
Doctor O
's O
lady O
clothed O
in O
|
| O
cashmcres O
, O
sometimes O
inquired O
after O
their O
health O
, O
|
| O
and O
occasionally O
received O
a O
report O
as O
to O
their O
|
| O
linen O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
had O
a O
classical O
retreat O
, O
not O
distant O
|
| O
from O
this O
establishment O
, O
which O
he O
esteemed O
|
| O
a O
Tusculum B-PERSON
. O
There O
, O
surrounded O
by O
his O
busts O
|
| O
and O
books O
, O
he O
wrote O
his O
lampoons O
and O
articles O
  O
|
| O
massacred O
a O
she O
liberal O
, O
( O
it O
was O
thought O
that O
no O
|
| O
24 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
one O
could O
lash O
a O
woman O
like O
Rigby B-GPE
) O
cut O
up O
a O
|
| O
rising O
genius O
whose O
politics O
were O
different O
from O
|
| O
his O
own O
, O
or O
scarified O
some O
unhappy O
wretch O
|
| O
who O
had O
brought O
his O
claims O
before O
parliament O
, O
|
| O
proving O
by O
garbled O
extracts O
from O
official O
cor- O
|
| O
respondence O
that O
no O
one O
could O
refer O
to O
, O
that O
the O
|
| O
malcontent O
, O
instead O
of O
being O
a O
victim O
, O
was O
on O
|
| O
the O
contrary O
a O
defaulter O
. O
Tadpole B-ORG
and O
Taper O
|
| O
would O
back O
Rigby B-ORG
for O
a O
` O
` O
slashing O
reply O
'' O
against O
|
| O
the O
field O
. O
Here O
too O
at O
the O
end O
of O
a O
busy O
week O
, O
|
| O
he O
found O
it O
occasionally O
convenient O
to O
entertain O
|
| O
a O
clever O
friend O
or O
two B-CARDINAL
of O
equivocal O
reputation O
, O
|
| O
with O
whom O
he O
had O
become O
acquainted O
in O
former O
|
| O
days B-DATE
of O
equal O
brotherhood O
. O
No O
one O
was O
more O
|
| O
faithful O
to O
his O
early O
friends O
than O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
  O
|
| O
particularly O
if O
they O
could O
write O
a O
squib O
. O
|
| O
It O
was O
in O
this O
refined O
retirement O
that O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
found O
time O
enough O
, O
snatched O
from O
the O
|
| O
toils O
of O
official O
life O
and O
parliamentary O
struggles O
, O
|
| O
to O
compose O
a O
letter O
on O
the O
study O
of O
History B-GPE
, O
|
| O
addressed O
to O
Coningsby B-GPE
. O
The O
style O
was O
as O
much O
|
| O
like O
that O
of O
Lord O
Bolingbroke B-ORG
as O
if O
it O
had O
heen B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
CONINGSBY I-PERSON
. O
|
| O
25 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
written O
by O
the O
authors O
of O
the O
'' O
Rejected O
Ad- O
|
| O
dresses O
, O
'' O
and O
it O
began O
, O
' O
` O
My O
dear O
young O
friend O
. O
'' O
|
| O
This O
polished O
composition O
, O
so O
full O
of O
good O
feeling O
|
| O
and O
comprehensive O
views O
, O
and O
all O
in O
the O
best O
|
| O
taste O
, O
was O
not O
published O
. O
It O
was O
only O
privately O
|
| O
printed O
and O
a B-CARDINAL
few I-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
copies O
were O
distri- O
|
| O
buted O
among O
select O
personages O
as O
an O
especial O
fa- O
|
| O
vour O
and O
mark O
of O
high O
consideration O
. O
Each O
copy O
|
| O
given O
away O
seemed O
to O
Rigby B-GPE
like O
a O
certificate O
of O
|
| O
character O
, O
a O
property O
which O
like O
all O
men O
of O
|
| O
dubious O
repute O
he O
thoroughly O
appreciated O
. O
Rigby O
|
| O
intrigued O
very O
much O
that O
the O
head O
- O
master O
of O
|
| O
Eton B-PERSON
should O
adopt O
his O
discourse O
as O
a O
class O
book O
. O
|
| O
For O
this O
purpose O
he O
dined O
with O
the O
Doctor O
  O
told O
|
| O
him O
several O
anecdotes O
of O
the O
IKing B-ORG
, O
which O
inti- O
|
| O
mated O
personal O
influence O
at O
Windsor O
  O
but O
the O
|
| O
head O
- O
master O
was O
inflexible O
  O
and O
so O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
obliged O
to O
be O
content O
by O
his O
Letter B-NORP
on O
His- O
|
| O
tory O
being O
canonized O
as O
a O
classic O
in O
the O
Pre- O
|
| O
paratory O
eminary O
, O
where O
the O
individual O
to O
|
| O
whom O
it O
was O
addressed O
was O
a O
scholar O
. O
|
| O
This O
change O
in O
the O
life O
of O
Coningsby B-PRODUCT
contri- O
|
| O
voL. O
I. B-ORG
|
| O
26 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
buted O
to O
his O
happiness O
. O
The O
various O
characters O
|
| O
which O
alarge O
school O
exhibited O
, O
interested O
a O
young O
|
| O
mind O
whose O
active O
energies O
were O
beginning O
to O
stir O
. O
|
| O
His O
previous O
aequirements O
made O
his O
studies O
light O
  O
|
| O
and O
he O
was O
fond O
of O
sports O
in O
which O
he O
was O
quali- O
|
| O
fied O
to O
excel O
. O
He O
did O
not O
particularly O
like O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
. O
There O
was O
something O
jarring O
and O
grat- O
|
| O
ing O
in O
that O
gentleman O
's O
voice O
and O
modes O
from O
|
| O
which O
the O
chords O
of O
the O
young O
heart O
shrank O
|
| O
He O
was O
not O
tender O
  O
though O
perhaps O
he O
wished O
|
| O
it O
, O
scarcely O
kind O
  O
but O
he O
was O
good O
- O
natured O
, O
at O
|
| O
least O
to O
children O
. O
However O
this O
connexion O
|
| O
was O
on O
the O
whole O
a O
very O
agreeable O
one O
for O
Con- O
|
| O
ingsby O
. O
He O
seemed O
suddenly O
to O
have O
friends O
  O
|
| O
he O
never O
passed O
his O
holidays O
again O
at O
school O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
was O
so O
clever O
that O
he O
contrived O
always O
|
| O
to O
quarter B-WORK_OF_ART
Coningsby I-WORK_OF_ART
on O
the O
father O
of O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
of O
his O
school O
- O
fellows O
, O
for O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
knew O
all O
|
| O
his O
school O
- O
fellows O
and O
all O
their O
fathers O
. O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
also O
called O
to O
see O
him O
, O
not O
unfequently O
, O
|
| O
would O
give O
him O
a O
dinner O
at O
the O
Star O
and O
Garter B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
or O
even O
have O
him O
up O
to O
town O
for O
a B-DATE
week I-DATE
to O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
7I B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Whitehall O
. O
Compared O
with O
his O
former O
forlorn O
|
| O
existence O
, O
these O
were O
happy O
days O
when O
he O
was O
|
| O
placed O
under O
the O
gallery O
as O
a O
member O
's O
son O
, O
or O
|
| O
went O
to O
the O
play O
with O
the O
butler O
l O
|
| O
When O
Coningsby B-PERSON
had O
attained O
his O
twelfth B-ORDINAL
|
| O
year O
, O
an O
order O
was O
rcceived O
from O
Lord O
Mon- O
|
| O
mouth O
who O
was O
at O
Rome B-GPE
, O
that O
he O
should O
go O
at O
|
| O
once O
to O
Eton B-ORG
. O
This O
was O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
great O
epoch O
|
| O
of O
his O
life O
. O
There O
never O
was O
a O
youth O
who O
|
| O
entered O
into O
that O
wonderful O
little O
world O
with O
|
| O
more O
eager O
zest O
than O
Coningsby B-GPE
. O
Nor O
was O
it O
|
| O
marvellous O
. O
|
| O
That O
delicious O
plain O
, O
studded O
with O
evcry O
crea- O
|
| O
tion O
of O
graceful O
culture O
  O
hamlet O
and O
hall O
, O
and O
|
| O
grange O
  O
garden O
and O
grove O
, O
and O
park O
  O
that O
|
| O
castle O
- O
palace O
, O
grey O
with O
glorious O
ages O
  O
those O
|
| O
antique O
spires O
hoar O
with O
faith O
and O
wisdom O
, O
|
| O
the O
chapel O
and O
the O
college O
  O
that O
river O
winding O
|
| O
through O
the O
shady O
meads O
  O
the O
sunny O
glade O
|
| O
and O
the B-FAC
solemn I-FAC
avenue I-FAC
  O
the O
room O
in O
the O
Dame O
's O
|
| O
house O
where O
we O
first B-ORDINAL
order O
our O
own O
breakfast O
|
| O
and O
first B-ORDINAL
feel O
we O
are O
free O
  O
the O
stirring O
mul- O
|
| O
c O
2 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
28 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
titude O
, O
the O
energetic O
groups O
, O
the O
individual O
|
| O
mind O
that O
leads O
, O
conquers O
, O
controls O
  O
the O
emu- O
|
| O
lation O
and O
the O
affection O
  O
the O
noble O
strife O
and O
|
| O
the O
tender O
sentiment O
  O
the O
daring O
exploit O
and O
|
| O
the O
dashing O
scrape O
  O
the O
passion O
that O
pervades O
|
| O
our O
life O
, O
and O
breathes O
in O
everything O
, O
from O
the O
|
| O
aspiring O
study O
to O
the O
inspiring O
sport O
- O
oh O
|
| O
what O
hereafter O
can O
spur O
the O
brain O
and O
touch O
|
| O
the O
heasrt O
like O
this O
  O
can O
give O
us O
a O
world O
so O
|
| O
deeply O
and O
variously O
interesting O
  O
a O
life O
so O
full O
of O
|
| O
quick O
and O
bright O
excitement O
- O
passed O
in O
a O
scene O
|
| O
su O
fair O
l O
|
| O
CHAPTER O
III O
. O
|
| O
Lonn B-PERSON
Mosor I-PERSON
, O
who O
detested O
popular O
tu- O
|
| O
mults O
as O
much O
as O
he O
despised O
public O
opinion O
, O
|
| O
had O
remained O
during O
the B-DATE
agitating I-DATE
year I-DATE
of I-DATE
|
| I-DATE
1831 B-DATE
in O
his O
luxurious O
retirement O
in O
Italy B-GPE
, O
|
| O
contenting O
himself O
with O
opposing O
the O
Reform B-ORG
|
| O
Bill O
by O
proxy O
. O
But O
when O
his O
correspondent O
, O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
had O
informed O
him O
in O
the O
early O
|
| O
part O
of O
the B-DATE
spring I-DATE
of I-DATE
1832 I-DATE
of O
the O
probability O
|
| O
of O
a O
change O
in O
the O
tactics O
of O
the O
Tory O
party O
, O
|
| O
and O
that O
an O
opinion O
was O
becoming O
prevalent O
|
| O
among O
their O
friends O
, O
that O
the O
great O
scheme O
|
| O
must O
be O
defeated O
in O
detail O
rather O
than O
again O
|
| O
withstood O
on O
principle O
, O
his O
Lordship B-EVENT
, O
who O
was O
|
| O
30 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CONINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
never O
wanting O
in O
energy O
, O
when O
his O
owun O
interests O
|
| O
were O
concerned O
, O
immediately O
crossed O
the O
Alps B-LOC
, O
|
| O
and O
travelled O
rapidly O
to O
England B-GPE
. O
He O
indulged O
|
| O
a O
hope O
that O
the O
weight O
of O
his O
presence O
and O
the O
|
| O
influence O
of O
his O
strong O
character O
, O
which O
was O
at O
|
| O
once O
shrewd O
and O
courageous O
, O
might O
induce O
his O
|
| O
friends O
to O
relinquish O
their O
half B-CARDINAL
measure O
, O
a O
course O
|
| O
to O
which O
his O
nature O
was O
very O
repugnant O
. O
At O
|
| O
all O
events O
, O
if O
they O
persisted O
in O
their O
intention O
, O
|
| O
and O
the O
Bill O
went O
into O
committee O
, O
his O
presence O
|
| O
was O
indispensable O
, O
for O
in O
that O
stage O
of O
a O
par- O
|
| O
liamentary O
proceeding O
proxies O
hecome O
inef- O
|
| O
fective O
. O
|
| O
The O
councils O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
, O
though O
they O
|
| O
coincided O
with O
those O
of O
the O
Duke O
of O
Wel O
. O
|
| O
lington B-GPE
, O
did O
not O
prevail O
with O
the O
Wuverers B-ORG
. O
|
| O
Several O
of O
these O
high O
- O
minded O
personages O
had O
|
| O
had O
their O
windows O
broken O
, O
and O
they O
were O
not O
|
| O
of O
opinion O
that O
a O
man O
who O
lived O
at O
Naples B-GPE
|
| O
was O
a O
competent O
judge O
of O
the O
state O
of O
public O
|
| O
feeling O
in O
England B-GPE
. O
Besides O
, O
the B-DATE
days I-DATE
are O
|
| O
gone O
by O
for O
fSenates B-ORG
to O
have O
their O
beards O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
plucked O
in O
the O
Forum O
. O
We O
lie O
in O
an O
age O
|
| O
of O
prudence O
. O
The O
leaders O
of O
the O
people O
, O
now O
, O
|
| O
generally O
follow O
. O
The O
truth O
is O
, O
the O
peers O
were O
|
| O
in O
a O
fright O
. O
' O
Twas O
a O
pity O
  O
there O
is O
scarcely O
|
| O
a O
less O
dignified O
entity O
than O
a O
patrician O
in O
a O
panic O
. O
|
| O
Among O
the O
most O
intimate O
companions O
of O
|
| O
Coningsby B-WORK_OF_ART
at I-WORK_OF_ART
Eton I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
was O
Lonrd O
Henry B-PERSON
Sydney I-PERSON
, O
|
| O
his O
kinsman O
. O
Coningsby O
had O
frequently O
passed O
|
| O
his O
holidays O
of O
late O
at O
Beaumanoir B-PERSON
, O
the O
seat O
of O
|
| O
the O
Duke O
, O
Lord O
Henry B-PERSON
's O
father O
. O
The O
Duke B-ORG
|
| O
sate O
next O
to O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
during O
the O
debate O
|
| O
on O
the O
enfranchising O
question O
, O
and O
to O
wile O
away O
|
| O
the O
time O
, O
and O
from O
kindness O
of O
disposition O
|
| O
spoke O
, O
and O
spoke O
with O
warmth O
and O
favour O
, O
of O
his O
|
| O
grandson O
. O
The O
polished O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
bowed O
|
| O
as O
if O
he O
were O
much O
gratified O
by O
this O
notice O
of O
|
| O
one O
so O
dear O
to O
him O
. O
He O
had O
too O
much O
tact O
|
| O
to O
admit O
that O
he O
had O
never O
yet O
seen O
his O
grand- O
|
| O
child O
  O
but O
he O
asked O
some O
questions O
as O
to O
his O
|
| O
progress O
and O
pursuits O
, O
his O
tastes O
and O
habits O
, O
|
| O
which O
intimated O
the O
interests O
of O
an O
affectionate O
|
| O
relative O
. O
|
| O
Nothing O
however O
was O
ever O
lost O
upon O
Lord O
|
| O
Monmouth B-GPE
. O
No O
one O
had O
a O
more O
retentive O
|
| O
memory O
, O
or O
a O
more O
observant O
mind O
. O
And O
the O
|
| O
next B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
when O
he O
received O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
at O
his O
|
| O
morning B-TIME
levee O
, O
( O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
performed O
|
| O
this O
ceremony O
in O
the O
high O
style O
of O
the O
old O
|
| O
court O
, O
and O
welcomed O
his O
visitors O
in O
bed O
) O
, O
he O
|
| O
said O
with O
imperturbable O
calmness O
, O
and O
as O
if O
|
| O
he O
had O
been O
talking O
of O
trying O
a O
new O
horse O
, O
|
 | O
Rigby O
, O
I O
should O
like O
to O
see O
the O
boy O
at O
|
| O
Eton B-PERSON
. O
'' O
|
| O
There O
might O
be O
some O
objection O
to O
grant O
leave O
|
| O
to O
Coningsby B-PERSON
at O
this O
moment O
  O
but O
it O
was O
a O
|
| O
rule O
with O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
never O
to O
make O
difficulties O
, O
|
| O
or O
at O
least O
to O
persuade O
his O
patron O
, O
that O
he O
, O
and O
|
| O
he O
only O
, O
could O
remove O
them O
. O
He O
immediately O
|
| O
undertook O
that O
the O
boy O
should O
be O
forthcoming O
, O
|
| O
and O
, O
notwithstanding O
the O
excitement O
of O
the O
|
| O
moment O
, O
he O
went O
off O
next B-TIME
morning I-TIME
to O
fetceh O
|
| O
him O
. O
|
| O
They O
arrived O
in O
town O
rather O
early O
, O
and O
Rigby B-GPE
|
| O
wishing O
to O
know O
how O
affairs O
were O
going O
on O
, O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
33 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
ordcred O
the O
servant O
to O
drive O
immediately O
to O
the O
|
| O
head O
- O
quarters O
of O
the O
party O
  O
where O
a O
perma- O
|
| O
nent O
committee O
watched O
every O
phasis O
of O
the O
|
| O
impending O
revolution O
  O
and O
where O
every O
member O
|
| O
of O
the O
opposition O
of O
note O
and O
trust O
was O
instantly O
|
| O
admitted O
to O
receive O
or O
to O
impart O
intelligence O
. O
|
| O
It O
was O
certainly O
not O
without O
emotion O
, O
that O
|
| O
Coningsby B-PERSON
contemplated O
his O
first O
interview O
with O
|
| O
his O
grandfather O
. O
All O
his O
experience O
of O
the O
ties O
|
| O
of O
relationship O
, O
however O
limited O
, O
were O
full O
of O
|
| O
tenderness O
and O
rapture O
. O
His O
memory O
often O
|
| O
dwelt O
on O
his O
mother O
's O
sweet O
embrace O
  O
and O
ever O
|
| O
and O
anon O
a O
fitful O
phantom O
of O
some O
past O
passage O
|
| O
of O
domestic O
love O
haunted O
his O
gushing O
heart O
. O
The O
|
| O
image O
of O
his O
father O
was O
less O
fresh O
in O
his O
mind O
  O
|
| O
but O
still O
it O
was O
associated O
with O
a O
vague O
senti- O
|
| O
ment O
of O
kindness O
and O
joy O
: O
  O
and O
the O
allusions O
to O
|
| O
Mr. O
Coningsby B-PERSON
in O
his O
mother O
's O
letters O
had O
|
| O
cherished O
these O
impressions O
. O
To O
notice O
lesser O
|
| O
sources O
of O
influence O
in O
his O
estimate O
of O
the O
do- O
|
| O
mestic O
tie O
, O
he O
had O
witnessed O
under O
the O
roof O
of O
|
| O
Beaumanoir B-PERSON
, O
the O
existence O
of O
a O
family O
bound O
|
| O
c O
3 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
34 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
together O
by O
the O
most O
beautiful O
nffections O
. O
He O
|
| O
could O
not O
forget O
how O
Henry B-PERSON
Sydney I-PERSON
was O
em- O
|
| O
braced O
by O
his O
sisters O
when O
he O
returned O
home O
  O
|
| O
what O
frank O
and O
fraternal O
love O
existed O
between O
|
| O
his O
eousin O
and O
his O
elder O
brother O
  O
how O
affection- O
|
| O
ately O
the O
kind O
Duke B-PERSON
had O
welcomed O
his O
son O
|
| O
once O
more O
to O
the O
house O
where O
they O
had O
both O
|
| O
been O
born O
  O
and O
the O
dim O
eyes O
and O
saddened O
brows O
, O
|
| O
and O
tones O
of O
tenderness O
which O
rather O
looked O
|
| O
than O
said O
farewell O
, O
when O
they O
went O
back O
to O
Eton B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
And O
these O
rapturous O
meetings O
and O
these O
|
| O
mournful O
adieus O
were O
occasioned O
only O
by O
a O
sepa- O
|
| O
ration O
at O
the O
most O
of O
a B-DATE
few I-DATE
months I-DATE
, O
softened O
by O
|
| O
constant O
correspondence O
, O
and O
the O
communication O
|
| O
of O
mutual O
sympathy O
. O
But O
Coningsby B-PERSON
was O
to O
|
| O
meet O
a O
relation O
, O
his O
nearest O
, O
almost O
his O
only O
, O
|
| O
relation O
for O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
  O
the O
relation O
too O
to O
|
| O
whom O
he O
owed O
maintenance O
, O
education O
- O
it O
|
| O
might O
be O
said O
, O
existence O
. O
It O
was O
a O
great O
incident O
|
| O
for O
a O
great O
drama O
  O
something O
tragical O
in O
the O
|
| O
depth O
and O
stir O
of O
its O
emotions O
. O
Even O
the O
imagi- O
|
| O
nation O
of O
the O
boy O
could O
not O
be O
insensible O
to O
its O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
35 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
materials O
  O
and O
Coningsby B-PERSON
was O
picturing O
to O
|
| O
himself O
a O
beneficent O
and O
venerable O
gentleman O
|
| O
pressing O
to O
his O
breast O
an O
agitated O
youth O
, O
when O
|
| O
his O
reverie O
was O
broken O
by O
the O
carriage O
stopping O
|
| O
before O
the O
gates O
of O
Monmouth B-ORG
House I-ORG
. O
|
| O
The O
gates O
were O
opened O
by O
a O
gigantic O
Swiss B-NORP
, O
|
| O
and O
the O
carriage O
rolled O
into O
a O
huge O
court O
yard O
. O
|
| O
At O
its O
end O
, O
Coningsby B-PERSON
beheld O
a O
Palladian B-NORP
palace O
|
| O
with O
wings O
and O
colonnades O
encircling O
the O
court O
. O
|
| O
A O
double O
flight O
of O
steps O
led O
into O
a O
circular O
|
| O
and O
marble O
hall O
adorned O
with O
colossal O
busts O
ot O
|
| O
the O
Caesars B-ORG
  O
the O
staircase O
in O
fresco O
by O
Sir O
James B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Thornhill I-PERSON
, O
breathed O
with O
the O
loves O
and O
wars O
of O
|
| O
Gods O
and O
heroes O
. O
It O
led O
into O
a O
vestibule O
painted O
|
| O
in O
arabesque O
, O
hung O
with O
Venetian B-NORP
girandoles O
, O
|
| O
and O
looking O
into O
gardens O
. O
Opening O
a O
door O
|
| O
in O
this O
chamber O
, O
and O
proceeding O
some O
little O
way O
|
| O
down O
a O
corridor O
, O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
and O
his O
companion O
|
| O
arrived O
at O
the O
base O
of O
a O
private O
staircase O
. O
As- O
|
| O
cending O
a O
few O
steps O
, O
they O
reached O
a O
landing O
place O
|
| O
hung O
with O
tapestry O
. O
Drawing O
this O
aside O
, O
Mr. O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
opened O
a O
door O
and O
ushered O
Coningsby B-ORG
|
| O
36 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CoNINGsSBY O
. O
|
| O
through O
an O
ante O
- O
chamber O
into O
a O
small O
saloon O
of O
|
| O
beautiful O
proportion O
, O
and O
furnished O
in O
a O
brilliant O
|
| O
and O
delicate O
taste O
. O
|
| O
You O
will O
find O
more O
to O
amuse O
you O
here O
than O
|
| O
where O
we O
were O
before O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
` O
' O
and O
|
| O
I O
shall O
not O
be O
nearly O
so O
long O
absent O
. O
'' O
So O
saying O
, O
|
| O
he O
entered O
into O
an O
inner O
apartment O
. O
|
| O
The O
walls O
of O
the O
saloon O
, O
which O
were O
covered O
|
| O
with O
light O
blue O
satin O
, O
held O
in O
silver O
pannels O
por- O
|
| O
traits O
of O
beautiful O
women O
painted O
by O
Boucher B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
Couches B-PERSON
and O
easy O
chairs O
of O
every O
shape O
invited O
|
| O
in O
every B-DATE
quarter I-DATE
to O
luxurious O
repose O
, O
while O
|
| O
amusement O
was O
afforded O
by O
tables O
covered O
with O
|
| O
caricatures O
, O
French B-NORP
novels O
, O
and O
endless O
miniatures B-CARDINAL
|
| O
of O
foreign O
dancers O
, O
princesses O
, O
and O
Sovereigns B-NORP
. O
|
| O
But O
Coningsby B-PERSON
was O
so O
impressed O
with O
the O
|
| O
impending O
interview O
with O
his O
grandfather O
, O
that O
|
| O
he O
neither O
sought O
nor O
required O
diversion O
. O
Now O
|
| O
that O
the O
crisis O
was O
at O
hand O
, O
he O
felt O
agitated O
and O
|
| O
nervous O
  O
and O
wished O
that O
he O
was O
again O
at O
Eton B-ORG
. O
|
| O
The O
suspense O
was O
sickening O
, O
yet O
he O
dreaded O
still O
|
| O
more O
the O
summons O
. O
He O
was O
not O
long O
alone O
  O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
a7 O
|
| O
the O
door O
opened O
- O
he O
started O
- O
grew O
pale O
- O
he O
|
| O
thought O
it O
was O
his O
grandfather O
  O
It O
was O
not O
even O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
It O
was O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
's O
valet O
. O
|
 | O
Monsieur O
IKonigby O
2 O
' O
|
 | O
My O
name O
is O
Coningsby B-PERSON
, O
'' O
said O
the O
boy O
. O
|
| O
Milor B-ORG
is O
ready O
to O
receive O
you O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
|
| O
valet O
. O
|
| O
Coningsby O
sprang O
forward O
with O
that O
despe- O
|
| O
ration O
which O
the O
scaffold O
requires O
. O
His O
face O
|
| O
was O
pale O
  O
his O
hand O
was O
moist O
  O
his O
heart O
beat O
|
| O
with O
tumult O
. O
He O
had O
occasionally O
been O
summoned O
|
| O
by O
Dr. O
Keate B-PERSON
  O
that O
too O
was O
awful O
work O
, O
but O
com- O
|
| O
pared O
with O
the O
present O
, O
a O
morning B-TIME
visit O
. O
Music O
, O
|
| O
artillery O
, O
the O
roar O
of O
cannon O
, O
and O
the O
blare O
of O
|
| O
trumpets O
, O
may O
urge O
a O
man O
on O
to O
a O
forlorn O
hope O
, O
|
| O
ambition O
, O
one O
's O
constituents O
, O
the O
hell O
of O
previous O
|
| O
failure O
, O
may O
prevail O
on O
us O
to O
do O
a O
more O
desperate O
|
| O
thing O
- O
speak O
in O
the B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Commons I-ORG
  O
but O
|
| O
there O
are O
some O
situations O
in O
life O
, O
such O
for O
instance O
|
| O
as O
entering O
the O
room O
of O
a O
dentist O
, O
when O
the O
|
| O
prostration O
of O
the O
nervous O
system O
is O
absolute O
. O
|
| O
The O
moment O
had O
at O
length O
arrived O
, O
when O
the O
|
| O
3s B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
desolate O
was O
to O
find O
a O
benefactor O
, O
the O
forlorn O
|
| O
u O
friend O
, O
the O
orphan O
a O
parent O
  O
when O
the O
youth O
, O
|
| O
after O
a O
childhood O
of O
adversity O
, O
was O
to O
be O
formally O
|
| O
reeeived O
into O
the O
bosom O
of O
the O
noble O
house O
from O
|
| O
which O
he O
had O
bcen O
so O
long O
estranged O
, O
and O
at O
|
| O
length O
to O
assume O
that O
social O
position O
to O
which O
|
| O
his O
lineage O
entitled O
him O
. O
Manliness O
might O
sup- O
|
| O
port O
, O
affection O
might O
soothe O
, O
the O
happy O
anguish O
|
| O
of O
such O
a O
meeting O
  O
but O
it O
was O
undoubtedly O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
of O
those O
situations O
which O
stir O
up O
the O
deep O
foun- O
|
| O
tains O
of O
our O
natures O
, O
and O
before O
which O
the O
con- O
|
| O
ventional O
proprieties O
of O
our O
ordinary O
manners O
|
| O
instntaneously O
vanish O
. O
|
| O
Coningsby B-PERSON
with O
an O
uncertain O
step O
followed O
|
| O
his O
guide O
through O
a O
bed O
- O
chamber O
, O
the O
sump- O
|
| O
tuousness O
of O
which O
he O
could O
not O
notice O
, O
into O
the O
|
| O
dressing O
- O
room O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
. O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
facing O
Coningsby B-PERSON
as O
he O
entered O
, O
was O
leaning O
|
| O
over O
the O
back O
of O
a O
large O
chair O
, O
from O
which O
as O
|
| O
Coningsby B-PERSON
was O
announced O
by O
the O
valet O
, O
the O
|
| O
Lord O
of O
the O
house O
slowly O
rose O
, O
for O
he O
was O
|
| O
suffering O
slightly O
from O
the O
gout O
, O
and O
his O
left O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
39 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
hand O
rested O
on O
an O
ivory O
stick O
. O
Lord O
Mon- O
|
| O
mouth O
was O
in O
height O
above O
the O
middle O
size O
, O
but O
|
| O
somewhat O
portly O
and O
corpulent O
. O
His O
counte- O
|
| O
nance O
was O
strongly O
marked O
  O
sagacity O
on O
the O
|
| O
brow O
, O
sensuality O
in O
the O
mouth O
and O
jaw O
. O
His O
|
| O
head O
was O
bald O
, O
but O
there O
were O
remains O
of O
the O
|
| O
rich O
brown O
locks O
on O
which O
he O
once O
prided O
him- O
|
| O
self O
. O
His O
large O
deep O
blue O
eye O
, O
madid O
and O
yet O
|
| O
piercing O
, O
showed O
that O
the O
secretions O
of O
his O
brain O
|
| O
were O
apportioned O
, O
half B-CARDINAL
to O
voluptuousness O
, O
half B-CARDINAL
to O
|
| O
common O
sense O
. O
But O
his O
general O
mien O
was O
|
| O
truly O
grand O
  O
full O
f O
a O
natural O
nobility O
, O
of O
which O
|
| O
no O
one O
was O
more O
sensible O
. O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
not O
in O
dishabille B-GPE
  O
on O
the O
contrary O
, O
his O
cos- O
|
| O
tume O
was O
exact O
, O
and O
even O
careful O
. O
Rising O
as O
|
| O
we O
have O
mentioned O
when O
his O
grandson O
entered O
, O
|
| O
and O
leaning O
with O
his O
left O
hand O
on O
his O
ivory O
cane O
, O
|
| O
he O
made O
Coningsby B-PERSON
such O
a O
bow O
as O
Louis B-PERSON
Qua- I-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
torze I-PERSON
might O
have O
bestowed O
on O
the O
ambassador O
|
| O
of O
the B-ORG
United I-ORG
Provinces I-ORG
. O
Then O
extending O
his O
|
| O
ight O
hand O
, O
which O
the O
boy O
tremblingly O
touched O
, O
|
| O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
said O
: O
|
| O
40 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CoNINGsBY B-GPE
. O
|
| O
How O
do O
you O
like O
Eton O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
|
| O
This O
contrast O
to O
the O
reception O
which O
he O
had O
|
| O
imagined O
, O
hoped O
, O
feared O
, O
paralysed O
the O
reviving O
|
| O
energies O
of O
young O
Coningsby B-PERSON
. O
He O
felt O
stupified O
  O
|
| O
he O
looked O
almost O
aghast O
. O
In O
the O
chaotic O
tumult O
|
| O
of O
his O
mind O
, O
his O
memory O
suddenly O
seemed O
to O
|
| O
receive O
some O
miraculous O
inspiration O
. O
Mysterious O
|
| O
phrases O
heard O
in O
his O
earliest O
boyhood O
, O
unnoticed O
|
| O
then O
, O
long O
since O
forgotten O
, O
rose O
to O
his O
ear O
. O
Who O
|
| O
was O
this O
grandfather O
, O
seen O
not O
before O
, O
seen O
now O
|
| O
for O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
? O
Where O
was O
the O
intervening O
|
| O
link O
of O
blood O
between O
him O
and O
this O
superb O
and O
|
| O
icy O
being O
? O
The O
boy O
sank O
into O
the O
chair O
which O
|
| O
had O
been O
placed O
for O
him O
, O
and O
leaning O
on O
the O
|
| O
table O
burst O
into O
tears O
. O
|
| O
Here O
was O
a O
business O
. O
If O
there O
were O
one B-CARDINAL
|
| O
thing O
which O
would O
have O
made O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
|
| O
travel O
from O
London B-GPE
to O
Naples B-GPE
at O
four B-CARDINAL
and I-CARDINAL
twenty I-CARDINAL
|
| O
hours O
' O
notice O
, O
it O
was O
to O
avoid O
a O
scene O
. O
He O
|
| O
hated O
scenes O
- O
he O
hated O
feelings O
. O
He O
saw O
in- O
|
| O
stantly O
the O
mistake O
he O
had O
made O
in O
sending O
for O
|
| O
his O
grandchild O
. O
He O
was O
afraid O
that O
Conipgsby B-PERSON
|
| O
was O
tender O
- O
hearted O
like O
his O
father O
. O
Another O
|
| O
tender O
- O
hearted O
Coningsbyl B-ORG
Unfortunate I-ORG
fa- O
|
| O
milyl O
Degenerate B-WORK_OF_ART
racel O
He O
decided O
in O
his O
|
| O
mind O
that O
Coningsby B-PERSON
must O
be O
provided O
for O
|
| O
in O
the O
Church B-ORG
, O
and O
looked O
at O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
whose O
principal O
business O
it O
always O
was O
to O
|
| O
disembarrass O
his O
patron O
from O
the O
disagree- O
|
| O
able O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
instantly O
came O
forward O
and O
adroitly O
|
| O
led O
the O
boy O
into O
the O
adjoining O
apartment O
, O
Lord O
|
| O
Monmouth B-GPE
's O
bed O
- O
chamber O
, O
closing O
the O
door O
|
| O
of O
the O
dressing O
- O
room O
behind O
him O
. O
|
| O
My O
dear O
young O
friend O
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
|
 | O
what O
is O
all O
this O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
|
| O
A O
sob O
the O
only O
answer O
. O
|
 | O
What O
can O
be O
the O
matter O
2 B-CARDINAL
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Righy B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
I O
was O
thinking O
, O
'' O
said O
Coningsby B-PERSON
, O
` O
` O
of O
poor O
|
| O
mamma O
l O
'' O
|
 | O
Hush O
l O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
` O
` O
Lord O
Monmouth O
|
| O
never O
likes O
to O
hear O
of O
people O
who O
are O
dead O
  O
|
| O
so O
you O
must O
take O
care O
never O
to O
mention O
your O
|
| O
mother O
or O
your O
father O
. O
'' O
|
| O
A2 B-ORG
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
In O
the O
mcantime O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
had O
de- O
|
| O
cided O
on O
the O
fate O
of O
Coningsby B-GPE
. O
The O
Marquess O
|
| O
thought O
he O
could O
read O
characters O
by O
a O
glance O
, O
|
| O
and O
in O
general O
he O
was O
very O
successful O
  O
for O
his O
|
| O
natural O
sagacity O
had O
been O
nurtured O
by O
great O
|
| O
experience O
. O
His O
grandson O
was O
not O
to O
his O
taste O
  O
|
| O
amiable O
, O
no O
doubt O
, O
but O
a O
spooney O
. O
|
| O
We O
are O
too O
apt O
to O
believc O
that O
the O
character O
|
| O
of O
a O
boy O
is O
easily O
read O
. O
' O
Tis O
a O
mystery O
the O
most O
|
| O
profound O
. O
Mark B-PERSON
what O
blunders O
parcnts O
con- O
|
| O
stantly O
make O
as O
to O
the O
nature O
of O
their O
own O
|
| O
offspring O
, O
bred O
too O
undcr O
their O
eyes O
, O
and O
display- O
|
| O
ing O
every B-TIME
hour I-TIME
their O
characteristics O
. O
How O
often O
|
| O
in O
the O
nursery O
does O
the O
genius O
count O
as O
a O
duncte O
|
| O
because O
he O
is O
pensive O
  O
while O
a O
rattling O
urchin O
is O
|
| O
invested O
with O
almost O
supernatural O
qualities O
be- O
|
| O
cause O
his O
animal O
spirits O
make O
him O
impudent O
|
| O
and O
flippant O
. O
The O
school O
- O
boy O
above O
all O
others O
|
| O
is O
not O
the O
simple O
being O
the O
world O
imagines O
. O
In O
|
| O
that O
young O
bosom O
are O
often O
stirring O
passions O
as O
|
| O
strong O
as O
our O
own O
, O
desires O
not O
less O
violent O
, O
a O
|
| O
volition O
not O
less O
supreme O
. O
In O
that O
young O
|
| O
CONINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
43 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
bosom O
what O
burning O
love O
, O
what O
intense O
ambi- O
|
| O
tion O
, O
what O
avarice O
, O
what O
lust O
of O
power O
  O
envy O
|
| O
that O
fiends O
might O
emulate O
, O
hate O
that O
man O
|
| O
might O
fear O
. O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
cHAPTER B-ORG
IV I-ORG
. O
|
| O
CoE B-ORG
, O
'' O
said O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
, O
when O
Coningsby B-PERSON
waes I-PERSON
|
| O
somewhat O
composed O
, O
` O
` O
come O
with O
me O
, O
and O
we O
|
| O
will O
see O
the O
house O
. O
'' O
|
| O
So O
they O
descended O
once O
more O
the O
private O
|
| O
staircase O
, O
and O
again O
entered O
the O
vestibule O
. O
|
| O
If O
you O
had O
seen O
these O
gardens O
when O
they O
|
| O
were O
illuminated O
for O
a O
fete O
to O
George B-PERSON
IV I-PERSON
|
| O
said O
Rigby B-ORG
, O
as O
crossing O
the O
chamber O
he O
ushered O
|
| O
his O
charge O
into O
the O
state O
- O
apartments O
. O
The O
|
| O
splendour O
and O
variety O
of O
the O
surrounding O
ob- O
|
| O
jects O
soon O
distracted O
the O
attention O
of O
the O
boy O
, O
|
| O
for O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
in O
the O
palace O
of O
his O
fathers O
. O
|
| O
He O
traversed O
saloon O
after O
saloon B-PERSON
hung I-PERSON
with O
rare O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
45 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
tapestry O
and O
the O
gorgeos O
produects O
of O
foreign O
|
| O
looms O
  O
filled O
with O
choice O
pictures O
and O
creations O
|
| O
of O
curious O
art O
  O
cabinets O
that O
sovereigns O
might O
|
| O
envy O
, O
and O
colossal O
vases O
of O
malachite O
presented O
|
| O
by O
Emperors O
. O
Coningsby O
alternately O
gazed O
up O
|
| O
to O
ceilings O
glowing O
with O
colour O
and O
with O
gold O
, O
|
| O
and O
down O
upon O
carpets O
bright O
with O
the O
fancies O
|
| O
and O
vivid O
with O
the O
tints O
of O
Aubusson B-PERSON
and O
of O
|
| O
Axminster B-PERSON
. O
|
 | O
This O
grandfather O
of O
mine O
is O
a O
great O
prince O
, O
'' O
|
| O
thought O
Coningsby B-PERSON
, O
as O
musing O
he O
stood O
before O
|
| O
a O
portrait O
in O
which O
he O
rccognised O
the O
features O
|
| O
of O
the O
being O
from O
whom O
he O
had O
so O
recently O
and O
|
| O
so O
strangely O
parted O
. O
There O
he O
stood O
, O
Philip B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Augustus I-PERSON
, O
Marquess O
of O
Monmouth B-GPE
, O
in O
his O
robes O
|
| O
of O
estate O
, O
with O
his O
new O
coronet O
on O
a O
table O
near O
|
| O
him O
, O
a O
despatch O
lying O
at O
hand O
that O
indicated O
|
| O
the O
special O
mission O
of O
high O
ceremony O
of O
which O
|
| O
he O
had O
been O
the O
ilustrious O
envoy O
, O
and O
the O
|
| O
garter O
beneath O
his O
knee O
. O
|
| O
You O
will O
have O
plenty O
of O
opportunities O
to O
look O
|
| O
at O
the O
pictures O
, O
'' O
said O
Rigby B-ORG
, O
observing O
that O
the O
|
| O
46 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
boy O
had O
now O
quite O
recovered O
himself O
. O
` O
` O
Somc B-WORK_OF_ART
|
| I-WORK_OF_ART
luncheon I-WORK_OF_ART
will O
do O
you O
no O
harm O
after O
our O
drive O
, O
'' O
|
| O
and O
he O
opened O
the O
door O
of O
another O
apartment O
. O
|
| O
It O
was O
a O
pretty O
room O
, O
adorned O
with O
a O
fine O
|
| O
picture O
of O
the O
chase O
: O
at O
a O
round O
table O
in O
the O
|
| O
centre O
sate O
two B-CARDINAL
ladies O
intcrested O
in O
the O
meal O
to O
|
| O
which O
Rigby B-ORG
had O
alluded O
. O
|
| O
` O
' O
Ah O
, O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
: O
'' O
said O
the O
eldcst B-ORG
, O
yet O
young O
|
| O
and O
beautiful O
, O
and O
speaking O
, O
though O
with O
fluency O
, O
|
| O
in O
a O
foreign O
accent O
, O
` O
` O
come O
and O
tell O
me O
some O
|
| O
news O
. O
Have O
you O
seen O
Milor2 O
'' O
and O
then O
she O
|
| O
threw O
a O
scrutinizing O
glance O
from O
a O
dark O
flashing O
|
| O
eye O
at O
his O
companion O
. O
|
| O
` O
Let O
me O
present O
to O
your O
Highness O
, O
'' O
said O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
with O
an O
air O
of O
some O
ceremony O
, O
` O
` O
Mr. O
|
| O
Coningsby B-PERSON
. O
'' O
|
 | O
My O
dcar O
young O
fricnd O
, O
'' O
snid O
the O
Lady B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
extending O
hcr O
white O
hand O
with O
an O
air O
of O
|
| O
joyous O
welcome O
, O
` O
` O
this O
is O
Lucretia B-PERSON
, O
my O
daughter O
. O
|
| O
We O
love O
you O
already O
. O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
will O
be O
|
| O
so O
charmed O
to O
see O
you O
. O
What O
beautiful O
eyes O
|
| O
he O
has O
, O
Mr. O
Rigbyl B-PERSON
uite O
like O
Milor B-ORG
' O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
47 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
The O
young O
lady O
, O
who O
was O
eally O
more O
|
| O
youthful O
than O
Coningsby B-PERSON
, O
but O
of O
a O
form O
and O
|
| O
stature O
so O
developed O
, O
that O
she O
appeared O
almost O
a O
|
| O
woman O
, O
bowed O
to O
the O
guest O
with O
some O
cere- O
|
| O
mony O
, O
and O
a O
faint O
sullen O
smile O
, O
and O
then O
pro- O
|
| O
ceeded O
with O
her O
chicken O
- O
pie O
. O
|
 | O
You O
must O
be O
so O
hungry O
after O
your O
drive O
, O
'' O
|
| O
said O
the O
elder O
lady O
, O
placing O
Coningsby B-PERSON
at O
her O
|
| O
side O
, O
and O
herself O
filing O
his O
plate O
. O
|
| O
This O
was O
true O
enough O
  O
and O
while O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
|
| O
and O
the O
lady O
talked O
an O
infinite O
deal O
about O
things O
|
| O
which O
he O
did O
not O
understand O
, O
and O
persons O
of O
|
| O
whom O
he O
had O
never O
heard O
, O
our O
little O
hero O
made O
|
| O
his O
first B-ORDINAL
meal O
in O
his O
paternal O
house O
with O
no O
|
| O
ordinary O
zest O
  O
and O
renovated O
by O
the O
pasty O
and O
|
| O
a O
glass O
of O
sherry O
, O
felt O
altogether O
a O
very O
different O
|
| O
being O
to O
what O
he O
was O
, O
when O
he O
had O
undergone O
|
| O
the O
terrible O
interview O
in O
which O
, O
he O
began O
to O
re- O
|
| O
flect O
he O
had O
considerably O
exposed O
himself O
|
| O
His O
courage O
revived O
, O
his O
senses O
rallied O
, O
he O
re- O
|
| O
plied O
to O
the O
interrogations O
of O
the O
lady O
with O
|
| O
calmness O
, O
but O
with O
promptness O
and O
propriety O
. O
|
| O
48 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGsBY O
. O
|
| O
It O
was O
evident O
that O
he O
had O
made O
a O
favourable O
|
| O
impression O
on O
her O
Highness O
, O
for O
ever O
and O
aon O
|
| O
she O
put O
a O
truffle O
or O
some O
small O
delicacy O
in O
his O
|
| O
plate O
, O
and O
insisted O
upon O
his O
taking O
some O
par- O
|
| O
ticular O
confectionary O
, O
because O
it O
was O
a O
favourite O
|
| O
of O
her O
own O
. O
When O
she O
rose O
, O
she O
said O
: O
|
| O
: O
In O
ten B-TIME
minutes I-TIME
the O
carriage O
will O
be O
at O
the O
|
| O
door O
  O
and O
if O
you O
like O
, O
my O
dear O
young O
friend O
, O
|
| O
you O
shall O
be O
our O
beau O
, O
'' O
|
| O
There O
is O
nothing O
I O
should O
like O
so O
much O
, O
'' O
|
| O
suaid O
Coningsby B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
` O
Ah O
'' O
said O
the O
lady O
with O
the O
sweetest O
smile O
, O
|
| O
' O
he O
is O
frank O
. O
'' O
|
| O
The O
ladies O
bowed O
and O
retired O
  O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
|
| O
returned O
to O
the O
Marquess O
, O
and O
the O
groom O
of O
the O
|
| O
chambers O
led O
Coningsby B-GPE
to O
his O
room O
. O
|
| O
This O
lady O
, O
so O
courteous O
to O
Coningsby B-GPE
, O
was O
|
| O
thc O
Princess B-PERSON
Colonna I-PERSON
, O
a O
Roman B-NORP
dame O
, O
the O
|
| O
second B-ORDINAL
wife O
of O
Prince O
Paul B-PERSON
Colonna I-PERSON
. O
The O
|
| O
Prince O
had O
first B-ORDINAL
married O
when O
a O
boy O
, O
and O
into O
|
| O
a O
family O
not O
inferior O
to O
his O
own O
. O
Of O
this O
|
| O
union O
, O
in O
every O
respect O
unhappy O
, O
the O
Princess O
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
49 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
Lucretia B-WORK_OF_ART
was O
the O
sole O
offspring O
. O
He O
was O
a O
man O
|
| O
dissolute O
, O
and O
devoted O
to O
play O
  O
and O
cared O
for O
|
| O
nothing O
much O
but O
his O
pleasures O
and O
billiards O
, O
in O
|
| O
which O
latter O
he O
was O
esteemed O
unrivalled O
. O
Accord- O
|
| O
ing O
to O
some O
, O
in O
a O
freak O
of O
passion O
, O
according O
to O
|
| O
others O
, O
to O
cancel O
a O
gambling O
debt O
, O
he O
had O
united O
|
| O
himself O
to O
his O
present O
wife O
, O
whose O
origin O
was O
|
| O
obscure O
  O
but O
with O
whom O
he O
contrived O
to O
live O
|
| O
on O
terms O
of O
apparent O
cordiality O
, O
for O
she O
was O
|
| O
much O
admired O
, O
and O
made O
the O
society O
of O
her O
|
| O
husband O
sought O
by O
those O
who O
contributed O
to O
his O
|
| O
enjoyment O
. O
Among O
these O
especially O
figured O
the O
|
| O
Marquess O
of O
Monmouth B-GPE
, O
between O
whom O
and O
|
| O
Prince B-PERSON
Colonna I-PERSON
the O
world O
recognised O
as O
existing O
|
| O
the O
most O
intimate O
and O
entire O
friendship O
, O
so O
that O
|
| O
his O
Highness O
and O
his O
family O
were O
frequent O
guests O
|
| O
under O
the O
roof O
of O
the O
English B-LANGUAGE
nobleman O
, O
and O
|
| O
now O
aeccompanied O
him O
on O
a O
visit O
ta O
England B-GPE
. O
|
| O
voL. O
I. B-ORG
|
| O
50 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
CHAPTER B-ORG
Y O
|
| O
lN B-ORG
the O
meantime O
, O
while O
ladies O
are O
luncheon- O
|
| O
ing O
on O
chicken O
pie O
, O
or O
coursing O
in O
whirling O
|
| O
britskas O
, O
performing O
all O
the O
singular O
ceremonies O
|
| O
of O
a O
London B-GPE
morning O
in O
the O
heart O
of O
the B-DATE
season I-DATE
  O
|
| O
making O
visits O
where O
nobody O
is O
seen O
, O
and O
making O
|
| O
purchases O
which O
are O
not O
wanted O
  O
the O
world O
is O
|
| O
in O
agitation O
and O
uproar O
. O
At O
present O
the O
world O
|
| O
and O
the O
confusion O
are O
limited O
to O
St. B-GPE
James I-GPE
's I-GPE
|
| I-GPE
Street I-GPE
and O
Pall O
Mall O
  O
but O
soon O
the O
boundaries O
|
| O
and O
the O
tumult O
will O
be O
extended O
to O
the O
intended O
|
| O
metropolitan O
boroughs O
  O
to O
- O
morrow O
they O
will O
|
| O
spread O
over O
the O
manufacturing O
districts O
. O
It O
is O
|
| O
entirely O
evident O
, O
that O
before B-CARDINAL
eight I-CARDINAL
and I-CARDINAL
forty I-CARDINAL
|
| O
cCoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
hours O
have O
passed O
, O
the O
country O
will O
be O
in O
a O
|
| O
state O
of O
fearful O
crisis O
. O
And O
how O
can O
it O
be O
|
| O
othervise O
Is O
it O
not O
a O
truth O
, O
that O
the O
subtle O
|
| O
Chief O
Baron B-PERSON
has O
been O
closeted O
one B-CARDINAL
whole O
hour O
|
| O
with O
the O
Iing O
  O
that O
shortly O
after O
, O
with O
thought- O
|
| O
ful O
brow O
and O
compressed O
lip O
, O
he O
was O
marked O
|
| O
in O
his O
daring O
chariot O
entering O
the O
court O
- O
yard O
|
| O
of O
Apsley B-PERSON
House I-PERSON
. O
Great O
was O
the O
panic O
at O
|
| O
Brookes O
' O
, O
wild O
the O
hopes O
of O
Carlton B-ORG
Terrace I-ORG
  O
|
| O
all O
the O
gentlemen O
who O
expected O
to O
have O
been O
|
| O
made O
peers O
, O
perceived O
that O
the O
country O
was O
going O
|
| O
to O
be O
given O
over O
to O
a O
rapacious O
oligarchy O
. O
|
| O
In O
the O
meantime O
, O
Tadpole B-ORG
and O
Taper B-GPE
, O
who O
|
| O
had O
never O
quitted O
for O
an O
instant O
the O
mysterious O
|
| O
head O
- O
quarters O
of O
the O
late O
opposition O
, O
were O
full O
|
| O
of O
hopes O
and O
fears O
, O
and O
asked O
many O
questions O
|
| O
which O
they O
chiefly O
answered O
themselves O
. O
|
| O
I O
wonder O
what O
Lord O
Lyndhurst O
will O
say O
to O
|
| O
the O
King O
, O
'' O
said O
Taper O
. O
|
 | O
He O
has O
plenty O
of O
pluck O
, O
'' O
said O
Tadpole B-ORG
. O
|
| O
' O
I O
almost O
wish O
now O
that O
Rigby B-ORG
had O
break- O
|
| O
fasted O
with O
him O
this B-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
'' O
snid O
Taper O
. O
|
| O
D O
2 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
coNINGSBY O
. O
|
 | O
If O
the O
King O
be O
firm O
, O
and O
the O
country O
|
| O
sound O
, O
'' O
said O
Tadpole B-ORG
, O
` O
` O
and O
Lord O
Monmouth O
|
| O
keep O
his O
boroughs O
, O
I O
should O
not O
wonder O
if O
|
| O
Rigby B-ORG
were O
made O
a O
privy O
counsellor O
, O
'' O
|
 | O
There O
is O
no O
precedent O
for O
an O
under O
secre- O
|
| O
tary O
being O
a O
privy O
counsellor O
, O
'' O
said O
Taper O
. O
|
| O
But O
we O
live O
in O
revolutionary O
times O
, O
'' O
said O
|
| O
Tadipole B-GPE
. O
|
 | O
Gentlemnen O
, O
'' O
said O
the O
groom O
of O
the O
cham- O
|
| O
bers O
in O
a O
loud O
voice O
, O
entering O
the O
room,'`I O
|
| O
am O
desired O
to O
state O
that O
the B-GPE
Duke I-GPE
of I-GPE
Wellington I-GPE
|
| O
is O
with O
the O
King O
. O
'' O
|
| O
There O
is O
a O
Provideneel O
'' O
exclaimed O
an O
agitated O
|
| O
gentleman O
, O
the O
patent O
of O
whose O
intended O
peerage O
|
| O
had O
not O
been O
signed O
the B-DATE
day I-DATE
that O
the O
Duke B-ORG
|
| O
had O
quitted O
office O
in O
1830 B-DATE
. O
|
| O
' O
I O
always O
thought O
the O
King O
would O
be O
firm O
, O
'' O
|
| O
said O
Mr. O
Tadpole B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
I O
wonder O
who O
will O
have O
the B-ORG
India I-ORG
Board I-ORG
, O
'' O
|
| O
said O
Taper O
. O
|
| O
At O
this O
moment O
, O
three B-CARDINAL
or O
four B-CARDINAL
gentlemen O
|
| O
entered O
the O
room O
in O
a O
state O
of O
great O
bustle O
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
and O
excitement O
  O
they O
were O
immediately O
sur- O
|
| O
rounded O
. O
|
 | O
Is O
it O
true O
? O
Quite O
true O
  O
not O
the O
slightest O
|
| O
doubt O
. O
Saw O
him O
myself O
. O
Not O
at O
all O
hissed O
  O
|
| O
certainly O
not O
hooted O
. O
Perhaps O
a O
little O
hissed O
. O
|
| O
One B-CARDINAL
fellow O
really O
cheered O
him O
. O
Saw O
him O
my- O
|
| O
self O
. O
Say O
what O
they O
like O
there O
ise O
re O
- O
action O
. O
|
| O
But O
Constitution B-PERSON
Hill I-PERSON
they O
say O
Wel B-PERSON
, O
therc O
|
| O
was O
a O
sort O
of O
inclination O
to O
row O
on O
Constitu- O
|
| O
tion O
Hill B-ORG
  O
but O
the O
Duke B-ORG
quite O
firm O
  O
pistols O
and O
|
| O
carriage O
doors O
bolted O
, O
'' O
|
| O
Such O
may O
give O
a O
faint O
idea O
of O
the O
anxious O
|
| O
inquiries O
, O
and O
the O
satisfactory O
replies O
that O
were O
|
| O
occasioned O
by O
the O
entrance O
of O
this O
group O
. O
|
| O
Up O
guards O
and O
at O
theml O
'' O
exclaimed O
Tad- O
|
| O
pole O
, O
rubbing O
his O
hands O
in O
a O
fit O
of O
patriotic O
|
| O
enthusiasm O
. O
|
| O
Later B-TIME
in I-TIME
the I-TIME
afternoon I-TIME
, O
about B-TIME
five I-TIME
o'clock I-TIME
, O
the O
|
| O
high O
change O
of O
political O
gossip O
, O
when O
the O
room O
|
| O
was O
crowded O
, O
and O
every O
one O
had O
his O
rumour O
, O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
looked O
in O
again O
to O
throw O
his O
eye O
|
| O
over O
the O
evening B-TIME
pepers O
, O
and O
catch O
in O
various O
|
| O
54 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CONINGSBY B-ORG
. O
|
| O
chit O
- O
chat O
the O
tone O
of O
public O
or O
party O
feeling O
on O
|
| O
the O
` O
crisis O
. O
' O
Then O
it O
was O
known O
that O
the O
Duke B-ORG
|
| O
had O
returned O
from O
the O
King O
, O
having O
aceepted O
|
| O
the O
charge O
of O
forming O
an O
administration O
. O
An O
|
| O
administration O
to O
do O
what O
? O
Portentous O
ques- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
tion1 I-PERSON
Were O
conceessions O
to O
be O
made O
And O
|
| O
if O
so O
, O
what O
Was O
it O
altogether O
impossible O
, O
|
| O
and O
too O
late O
, O
stare O
super O
vias O
antiquas O
CQues- B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
tions O
altogether O
above O
your O
Tadpoles B-PRODUCT
and O
your O
|
| O
Tapers B-ORG
, O
whose O
idea O
of O
the O
necessities O
of O
the O
age O
|
| O
was O
that O
they O
themselves O
should O
be O
in O
office O
. O
|
| O
Lord O
Eskdale O
came O
up O
to O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
This O
|
| O
peer O
was O
a O
noble O
Croesus B-PRODUCT
, O
aequainted O
with O
all O
|
| O
tbe O
gradations O
of O
life O
  O
a O
voluptuary O
who O
could O
|
| O
be O
a O
Spartan B-NORP
  O
clear O
- O
sighted O
, O
unprejudiced O
, O
sa- O
|
| O
gaeious O
  O
the O
best O
judge O
in O
the O
world O
of O
a O
|
| O
horse O
or O
a O
man O
  O
he O
was O
the O
universal O
referee O
  O
|
| O
a O
quarrel O
about O
a O
bet O
or O
a O
mistress O
was O
solved O
|
| O
by O
him O
in O
a O
moment O
, O
and O
in O
a O
manner O
which O
|
| O
satisfied O
both O
parties O
. O
He O
patronised O
and O
ap- O
|
| O
preciated O
the O
fine O
arts O
, O
though O
a O
jockey O
  O
re- O
|
| O
speceted O
literary O
men O
, O
though O
he O
only O
read O
French B-NORP
|
| O
novels O
  O
and O
without O
any O
affectation O
of O
tastes O
|
| O
which O
he O
did O
not O
possess O
, O
was O
looked O
upon O
by O
|
| O
every O
singer O
and O
dancer O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
as O
their O
|
| O
natural O
champion O
. O
The O
secret O
of O
his O
strong O
|
| O
character O
and O
great O
influence O
was O
his O
self O
- O
com- O
|
| O
posure O
, O
which O
an O
earthquake O
or O
a O
Reform O
Bill O
|
| O
could O
not O
disturb O
, O
and O
which O
in O
him O
was O
the O
|
| O
result O
of O
temperament O
and O
experience O
. O
He O
was O
|
| O
an O
intimate O
aequaintance O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
, O
|
| O
for O
they O
had O
many O
tastes O
in O
common O
  O
were O
both O
|
| O
men O
of O
considerable O
, O
and O
in O
some O
degree O
similar O
|
| O
abilities O
  O
and O
were O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
greatest O
proprietors O
|
| O
of O
close O
boroughs O
in O
the O
country O
. O
|
| O
'' O
Do O
you O
dine O
at O
Monmouth B-ORG
House I-ORG
to O
- O
day O
'' O
|
| O
inquired O
Lord O
Eskdle O
of O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
|
 | O
Where O
I O
hope O
to O
meet O
your O
Lordship B-EVENT
. O
|
| O
The B-WORK_OF_ART
Whig I-WORK_OF_ART
papesrs O
are O
very O
subdued O
, O
'' O
continued O
|
| O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
|
| O
` O
Ah1 O
they O
have O
not O
the O
cue O
yet O
, O
'' O
said O
Lord O
|
| O
Eskdale B-ORG
|
| O
` O
` O
And O
what O
do O
you O
think O
of O
affairs O
? O
'' O
in- O
|
| O
quired O
his O
companion O
. O
|
| O
CcoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
I O
think O
the O
hounds O
are O
too O
hot O
to O
hark O
off O
|
| O
now O
, O
'' O
said O
Lord B-ORG
Eskdale I-ORG
. O
|
 | O
There O
is O
one O
combination O
, O
'' O
said O
Rigby B-ORG
, O
who O
|
| O
seemed O
meditating O
an O
attack O
on O
Lord B-ORG
Eskdale I-ORG
's I-ORG
|
| O
button O
. O
|
 | O
Give O
us O
it O
at O
dinner O
, O
'' O
said O
Lord B-ORG
Eskdale I-ORG
  O
|
| O
who O
knew O
his O
man O
, O
and O
made O
an O
adroit O
move- O
|
| O
ment O
forwards O
as O
if O
he O
were O
very O
anxious O
to O
see O
|
| O
the O
Globe B-ORG
newspaper O
. O
|
| O
In O
the O
course O
of O
two B-TIME
or I-TIME
three I-TIME
hours I-TIME
these O
|
| O
gentlemen O
met O
again O
in O
the O
green O
drawing O
- O
room O
|
| O
of O
Monmouth B-ORG
House I-ORG
. O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
was O
sitting O
|
| O
on O
the O
sofa O
by O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
, O
detailing O
in O
|
| O
whispers O
all O
his O
gossip O
of O
the O
morn O
: O
Lord O
|
| O
Eskdale O
murmuring O
quaint O
inquiries O
into O
the O
|
| O
ear O
of O
the B-FAC
Prineess I-FAC
Lucretia I-FAC
. O
Madame O
Colonna B-PERSON
|
| O
made O
remarks O
alternately O
to O
two B-CARDINAL
gentlemen O
, O
|
| O
who O
paid O
her O
assiduous O
court O
. O
One B-CARDINAL
of O
these O
|
| O
was O
Mr. O
Ormsby B-PERSON
  O
the O
school O
, O
the O
colege O
, O
and O
|
| O
the O
club O
crony O
of O
Lord O
Monmouth B-PERSON
, O
who O
had O
|
| O
heen O
his O
shadow O
through O
life O
  O
travelled O
with O
|
| O
him O
in O
early B-DATE
days I-DATE
, O
won O
money O
with O
him O
at O
|
| O
COoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
play O
, O
had O
been O
his O
colleague O
in O
the B-ORG
IIouse I-ORG
of I-ORG
|
| I-ORG
Commons I-ORG
  O
and O
was O
still O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
nominees O
. O
|
| O
Mr. O
Ormsby B-PERSON
was O
a O
millionnaire O
, O
which O
Lord O
|
| O
Monmouth B-NORP
likecd O
. O
He O
liked O
his O
eompanions O
|
| O
to O
be O
very O
rich O
or O
very O
poor O
  O
to O
be O
his O
equals O
, O
|
| O
able O
to O
play O
with O
him O
at O
high O
stakes O
, O
or O
join O
|
| O
him O
in O
a O
great O
speculation O
  O
or O
to O
be O
his O
tools O
, O
|
| O
and O
to O
amuse O
and O
serve O
him O
. O
There O
was O
|
| O
nothing O
which O
he O
despised O
and O
disliked O
so O
|
| O
much O
as O
a O
moderate O
fortune O
. O
|
| O
The O
other O
gentleman O
was O
of O
a O
different O
class O
|
| O
and O
character O
. O
Nature O
had O
intended O
Lucian B-PERSON
|
| I-PERSON
Gay I-PERSON
for O
a O
scholar O
and O
a O
wit O
  O
necessity O
had O
made O
|
| O
him O
a O
scribbler O
and O
a O
buffoon O
. O
He O
had O
dis- O
|
| O
tinguished O
himself O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
  O
but O
he O
had O
|
| O
no O
patrimony O
, O
nor O
those O
powers O
of O
perseverance O
|
| O
which O
success O
in O
any O
learned O
profession O
requires O
. O
|
| O
He O
was O
good O
- O
looking O
, O
had O
great O
animal O
spirits O
, O
and O
|
| O
a O
keen O
sense O
of O
enjoyment O
, O
and O
could O
not O
drudge O
. O
|
| O
Moreover O
he O
had O
a O
fine O
voice O
, O
and O
sang O
his O
own O
|
| O
songs O
with O
considerable O
taste O
  O
accomplishments O
|
| O
which O
made O
his O
fortune O
in O
society O
, O
and O
completed O
|
| O
n O
3 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
58 B-CARDINAL
|
| O
CoNINGSBY O
. O
|
| O
his O
ruin O
. O
In O
due O
time O
he O
extricated O
himself O
|
| O
from O
the O
bench O
and O
merged O
into O
journalism O
, O
|
| O
by O
mcans O
of O
which O
he O
chanced O
to O
become O
|
| O
aequainted O
with O
Mr. O
Rigby B-PERSON
. O
That O
worthy O
indi- O
|
| O
vidual O
was O
not O
slow O
in O
detecting O
the O
treasure O
|
| O
he O
had O
lighted O
on O
- O
a O
wit O
, O
a O
ready O
and O
happy O
|
| O
writer O
, O
a O
joyous O
and O
tractable O
being O
, O
with O
the O
edu- B-CARDINAL
