Vanity B-ORG
Fair I-ORG
a O
Novel O
without O
a O
Hero O


William B-PERSON
Makepeace I-PERSON
Thackeray I-PERSON


With O
illustrations O
by O
the O
Author O



Before O
the O
Curtain O


As O
the O
manager O
of O
the O
Performance O
sits O
before O
the O
curtain O
on O
the O
boards O
and O
looks O


into O
the O
Fair B-ORG
, O
a O
feeling O
of O
profound O
melancholy O
comes O
over O
him O
in O
his O
survey O
of O


the O
bustling O
place O
. O
There O
is O
a O
great O
quantity O
of O
eating O
and O
drinking O
, O
making O


love O
and O
jilting O
, O
laughing O
and O
the O
contrary O
, O
smoking O
, O
cheating O
, O
fighting O
, O


dancing O
and O
fiddling O
; O
there O
are O
bullies O
pushing O
about O
, O
bucks O
ogling O
the O
women O
, O


knaves O
picking O
pockets O
, O
policemen O
on O
the O
look O
- O
out O
, O
quacks O
( O
OTHER O
quacks O
, O
plague O


take O
them O
! O
) O
bawling O
in O
front O
of O
their O
booths O
, O
and O
yokels O
looking O
up O
at O
the O


tinselled O
dancers O
and O
poor O
old O
rouged O
tumblers O
, O
while O
the O
light O
- O
fingered O
folk O


are O
operating O
upon O
their O
pockets O
behind O
. O
Yes O
, O
this O
is O
VANITY B-ORG
FAIR I-ORG
; O
not O
a O
moral O


place O
certainly O
; O
nor O
a O
merry O
one O
, O
though O
very O
noisy O
. O
Look O
at O
the O
faces O
of O
the O


actors O
and O
buffoons O
when O
they O
come O
off O
from O
their O
business O
; O
and O
Tom B-PERSON
Fool I-PERSON
washing O


the O
paint O
off O
his O
cheeks O
before O
he O
sits O
down O
to O
dinner O
with O
his O
wife O
and O
the O


little O
Jack B-PERSON
Puddings I-PERSON
behind O
the O
canvas O
. O
The O
curtain O
will O
be O
up O
presently O
, O
and O
he O


will O
be O
turning O
over O
head O
and O
heels O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
 O
How O
are O
you O
? O
 O


A O
man O
with O
a O
reflective O
turn O
of O
mind O
, O
walking O
through O
an O
exhibition O
of O
this O
sort O
, O


will O
not O
be O
oppressed O
, O
I O
take O
it O
, O
by O
his O
own O
or O
other O
people O
’s O
hilarity O
. O
An O


episode O
of O
humour O
or O
kindness O
touches O
and O
amuses O
him O
here O
and O
there O
— O
a O
pretty O


child O
looking O
at O
a O
gingerbread O
stall O
; O
a O
pretty O
girl O
blushing O
whilst O
her O
lover O


talks O
to O
her O
and O
chooses O
her O
fairing O
; O
poor O
Tom B-PERSON
Fool I-PERSON
, O
yonder O
behind O
the O
waggon B-GPE
, O


mumbling O
his O
bone O
with O
the O
honest O
family O
which O
lives O
by O
his O
tumbling O
; O
but O
the O


general O
impression O
is O
one B-CARDINAL
more O
melancholy O
than O
mirthful O
. O
When O
you O
come O
home O
you O


sit O
down O
in O
a O
sober O
, O
contemplative O
, O
not O
uncharitable O
frame O
of O
mind O
, O
and O
apply O


yourself O
to O
your O
books O
or O
your O
business O
. O


I O
have O
no O
other O
moral O
than O
this O
to O
tag O
to O
the O
present O
story O
of O
 O
Vanity O
Fair O
. O
 O


Some O
people O
consider O
Fairs B-EVENT
immoral O
altogether O
, O
and O
eschew O
such O
, O
with O
their O


servants O
and O
families O
: O
very O
likely O
they O
are O
right O
. O
But O
persons O
who O
think O


otherwise O
, O
and O
are O
of O
a O
lazy O
, O
or O
a O
benevolent O
, O
or O
a O
sarcastic O
mood O
, O
may O
perhaps O


like O
to O
step O
in O
for O
half B-TIME
an I-TIME
hour I-TIME
, O
and O
look O
at O
the O
performances O
. O
There O
are O
scenes O


of O
all O
sorts O
; O
some O
dreadful O
combats O
, O
some O
grand O
and O
lofty O
horse O
- O
riding O
, O
some O


scenes O
of O
high O
life O
, O
and O
some O
of O
very O
middling O
indeed O
; O
some O
love O
- O
making O
for O
the O


sentimental O
, O
and O
some O
light O
comic O
business O
; O
the O
whole O
accompanied O
by O
appropriate O


scenery O
and O
brilliantly O
illuminated O
with O
the O
Author O
’s O
own O
candles O
. O


What O
more O
has O
the O
Manager O
of O
the O
Performance O
to O
say O
? O
— O
To O
acknowledge O
the O


kindness O
with O
which O
it O
has O
been O
received O
in O
all O
the O
principal O
towns O
of O
England B-GPE


through O
which O
the O
Show O
has O
passed O
, O
and O
where O
it O
has O
been O
most O
favourably O
noticed O


by O
the O
respected O
conductors O
of O
the B-ORG
public I-ORG
Press I-ORG
, O
and O
by O
the O
Nobility B-ORG
and O
Gentry O
. O


He O
is O
proud O
to O
think O
that O
his O
Puppets O
have O
given O
satisfaction O
to O
the O
very O
best O


company O
in O
this O
empire O
. O
The O
famous O
little O
Becky B-PERSON
Puppet I-PERSON
has O
been O
pronounced O
to O
be O


uncommonly O
flexible O
in O
the O
joints O
, O
and O
lively O
on O
the O
wire O
; O
the O
Amelia B-PERSON
Doll I-PERSON
, O


though O
it O
has O
had O
a O
smaller O
circle O
of O
admirers O
, O
has O
yet O
been O
carved O
and O
dressed O


with O
the O
greatest O
care O
by O
the O
artist O
; O
the O
Dobbin B-PERSON
Figure I-PERSON
, O
though O
apparently O


clumsy O
, O
yet O
dances O
in O
a O
very O
amusing O
and O
natural O
manner O
; O
the B-WORK_OF_ART
Little I-WORK_OF_ART
Boys I-WORK_OF_ART
’ I-WORK_OF_ART
Dance I-WORK_OF_ART


has O
been O
liked O
by O
some O
; O
and O
please O
to O
remark O
the O
richly O
dressed O
figure O
of O
the O


Wicked B-WORK_OF_ART
Nobleman I-WORK_OF_ART
, O
on O
which O
no O
expense O
has O
been O
spared O
, O
and O
which O
Old O
Nick O
will O


fetch O
away O
at O
the O
end O
of O
this O
singular O
performance O
. O


And O
with O
this O
, O
and O
a O
profound O
bow O
to O
his O
patrons O
, O
the O
Manager O
retires O
, O
and O
the O


curtain O
rises O
. O


LONDON B-GPE
, O
June B-DATE
28 I-DATE
, I-DATE
1848 I-DATE






windows O
of O
the O
stately O
old O
brick O
house O
. O
Nay B-PERSON
, O
the O
acute O
observer O
might O
have O



drawing O
- O
room O
. O


 O
It O
is O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
coach O
, O
sister O
, O
 O
said O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
 O
Sambo B-PERSON
, O
the O
black O



Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
departure O
, O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
? O
 O
asked O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
herself O
, O
that O



the O
correspondent O
of O
Mrs. O
Chapone B-PERSON
herself O
. O


 O
The O
girls O
were O
up O
at O
four B-TIME
this I-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
packing O
her O
trunks O
, O
sister O
, O
 O


replied O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
; O
 O
we O
have O
made O
her O
a O
bow O
- O
pot O
. O
 O



 O
Well O
, O
a O
booky O
as O
big O
almost O
as O
a O
hay O
- O
stack O
; O
I O
have O
put O
up O
two B-CARDINAL
bottles O
of O



Amelia B-PERSON
’s O
box O
. O
 O


 O
And O
I O
trust O
, O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
you O
have O
made O
a O
copy O
of O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
account O
. O


This O
is O
it O
, O
is O
it O
? O
Very O
good O
— O
ninety B-QUANTITY
- I-QUANTITY
three I-QUANTITY
pounds I-QUANTITY
, O
four B-MONEY
shillings I-MONEY
. O
Be O
kind O



In O
the O
present O
instance O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
’s O
 O
billet O
 O
was O
to O
the O
following O


effect O
: O
— O

 O
MADAM B-ORG
— O
After O
her O
six B-DATE
years I-DATE
’ I-DATE
residence O
at O
the O
Mall B-FAC
, O
I O



characterise O
the O
young O
English B-LANGUAGE
gentlewoman O
, O
those O
accomplishments O


which O
become O
her O
birth O
and O
station O
, O
will O
not O
be O
found O
wanting O
in O
the O


amiable O
Miss B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
, O
whose O

industry O

and O

obedience O


have O
endeared O
her O
to O
her O
instructors O
, O
and O
whose O
delightful O
sweetness O


of O
temper O
has O
charmed O
her O

aged O

and O
her O

youthful O


companions O
. O


realised O
her O
friends O
’ O

fondest O
wishes O
. O


deportment O
and O
carriage O
, O

so O
requisite O
for O
every O
young O


lady O
of O

fashion O
. O


has O
been O
honoured O
by O
the O
presence O
of O

The B-WORK_OF_ART
Great I-WORK_OF_ART


Lexicographer I-WORK_OF_ART
, O


herself O
, O

 O
P.S.—Miss O
Sharp O
accompanies O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
. O
It O
is O



not O
exceed O
ten B-DATE
days I-DATE
. O
The O
family O
of O
distinction O
with O
whom O
she O
is O


engaged O
, O
desire O
to O
avail O
themselves O
of O
her O
services O
as O
soon O
as O


possible O
. O
 O



the O
Mall B-FAC
. O
On O
the O
cover O
was O
inserted O
a O
copy O
of O
 O
Lines O
addressed O
to O
a O
young O



Doctor O
Samuel B-PERSON
Johnson I-PERSON
. O
 O
In O
fact O
, O
the O
Lexicographer B-PERSON
’s O
name O
was O
always O
on O
the O


lips O
of O
this O
majestic O
woman O
, O
and O
a O
visit O
he O
had O
paid O
to O
her O
was O
the O
cause O
of O


her O
reputation O
and O
her O
fortune O
. O


Being O
commanded O
by O
her O
elder O
sister O
to O
get O
 O
the O
Dictionary O
 O
from O
the O



receptacle O
in O
question O
. O
When O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
had O
finished O
the O
inscription O
in O


the O
first B-ORDINAL
, O
Jemima B-ORG
, O
with O
rather O
a O
dubious O
and O
timid O
air O
, O
handed O
her O
the O


second B-ORDINAL
. O


 O
For O
whom O
is O
this O
, O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
? O
 O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
with O
awful O


coldness O
. O


 O
For O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
, O
 O
answered O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
trembling O
very O
much O
, O
and O
blushing O
over O


her O
withered O
face O
and O
neck O
, O
as O
she O
turned O
her O
back O
on O
her O
sister O
. O
 O
For O
Becky B-PERSON


Sharp I-PERSON
: O
she O
’s O
going O
too O
. O
 O



miserable O
if O
she O
do O
n’t O
get O
one O
. O
 O


 O
Send O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
instantly O
to O
me O
, O
 O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
. O
And O
so O
venturing O


not O
to O
say O
another O
word O
, O
poor O
Jemima B-ORG
trotted O
off O
, O
exceedingly O
flurried O
and O


nervous O
. O



is O



disinterested O
instructor O
. O
Now O
, O
Miss O
Amelia B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
was O
a O
young O
lady O
of O
this O



the O
young O
ladies O
in O
the O
Mall B-FAC
. O
She O
had O
twelve B-CARDINAL
intimate O
and O
bosom O
friends O
out O


of O
the O
twenty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
four I-CARDINAL
young O
ladies O
. O
Even O
envious O
Miss O
Briggs B-PERSON
never O
spoke O
ill O
of O



tipsify O
her O
with O
salvolatile O
. O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
’s O
attachment O
was O
, O
as O
may O
be O


supposed O
, O
from O
the O
high O
position O
and O
eminent O
virtues O
of O
that O
lady O
, O
calm O
and O


dignified O
; O
but O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
had O
already O
whimpered O
several O
times O
at O
the O
idea O


of O
Amelia B-PERSON
’s O
departure O
; O
and O
, O
but O
for O
fear O
of O
her O
sister O
, O
would O
have O
gone O
off O


in O
downright O
hysterics O
, O
like O
the O
heiress O
( O
who O
paid O
double O
) O
of O
St. B-GPE
Kitt I-GPE
’s I-GPE
. O


Such O
luxury O
of O
grief O
, O
however O
, O
is O
only O
allowed O
to O
parlour O
- O
boarders O
. O
Honest O


Jemima B-PERSON
had O
all O
the O
bills O
, O
and O
the O
washing O
, O
and O
the O
mending O
, O
and O
the O


puddings O
, O
and O
the O
plate O
and O
crockery O
, O
and O
the O
servants O
to O
superintend O
. O
But O


why O
speak O
about O
her O
? O
It O
is O
probable O
that O
we O
shall O
not O
hear O
of O
her O
again O
from O


this O
moment O
to O
the O
end O
of O
time O
, O
and O
that O
when O
the O
great O
filigree O
iron O
gates O


are O
once O
closed O
on O
her O
, O
she O
and O
her O
awful O
sister O
will O
never O
issue O
therefrom O


into O
this O
little O
world O
of O
history O
. O


But O
as O
we O
are O
to O
see O
a O
great O
deal O
of O
Amelia B-PERSON
there O
is O
no O
harm O
in O
saying O
, O
at O


the O
outset O
of O
our O
acquaintance O
, O
that O
she O
was O
a O
dear O
little O
creature O
; O
and O
a O


great O
mercy O
it O
is O
, O
both O
in O
life O
and O
in O
novels O
, O
which O
( O
and O
the O
latter O


especially O
) O
abound O
in O
villains O
of O
the O
most O
sombre O
sort O
, O
that O
we O
are O
to O
have O


for O
a O
constant O
companion O
, O
so O
guileless O
and O
good O
- O
natured O
a O
person O
. O
As O
she O
is O


not O
a O
heroine O
, O
there O
is O
no O
need O
to O
describe O
her O
person O
; O
indeed O
I O
am O
afraid O


that O
her O
nose O
was O
rather O
short O
than O
otherwise O
, O
and O
her O
cheeks O
a O
great O
deal O


too O
round O
and O
red O
for O
a O
heroine O
; O
but O
her O
face O
blushed O
with O
rosy O
health O
, O
and O


her O
lips O
with O
the O
freshest O
of O
smiles O
, O
and O
she O
had O
a O
pair O
of O
eyes O
which O


sparkled O
with O
the O
brightest O
and O
honestest O
good O
- O
humour O
, O
except O
indeed O
when O


they O
filled O
with O
tears O
, O
and O
that O
was O
a O
great O
deal O
too O
often O
; O
for O
the O
silly O


thing O
would O
cry O
over O
a O
dead O
canary O
- O
bird O
; O
or O
over O
a O
mouse O
, O
that O
the O
cat O
haply O


had O
seized O
upon O
; O
or O
over O
the O
end O
of O
a O
novel O
, O
were O
it O
ever O
so O
stupid O
; O
and O
as O


for O
saying O
an O
unkind O
word O
to O
her O
, O
were O
any O
persons O
hard O
- O
hearted O
enough O
to O
do O


so O
— O
why O
, O
so O
much O
the O
worse O
for O
them O
. O
Even O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
that O
austere O
and O



So O
that O
when O
the O
day O
of O
departure O
came O
, O
between O
her O
two B-CARDINAL
customs O
of O
laughing O


and O
crying O
, O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
was O
greatly O
puzzled O
how O
to O
act O
. O
She O
was O
glad O
to O
go O


home O
, O
and O
yet O
most O
wofully O
sad O
at O
leaving O
school O
. O
For O
three B-DATE
days I-DATE
before I-DATE
, O



promises O
of O
writing O
every B-DATE
week I-DATE
: O
 O
Send O
my O
letters O
under O
cover O
to O
my O


grandpapa O
, O
the O
Earl O
of O
Dexter B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Saltire I-PERSON
( O
who O
, O
by O
the O
way O
, O
was O



wistfully O
, O
 O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
when O
I O
write O
to O
you O
I O
shall O
call O
you O
Mamma B-PERSON
. O
 O
All O
which O


details O
, O
I O
have O
no O
doubt O
, O
JONES B-PERSON
, O
who O
reads O
this O
book O
at O
his O
Club B-ORG
, O
will O



ultra O
- O
sentimental O
. O
Yes O
; O
I O
can O
see O
Jones B-PERSON
at O
this B-TIME
minute I-TIME
( O
rather O
flushed O
with O



scoring O
under O
the O
words O
 O
foolish O
, O
twaddling O
, O
 O
& B-ORG
amp;c I-ORG
. I-ORG
, O
and O
adding O
to O
them O


his O
own O
remark O
of O

 O
quite O
true O
. O
 O

Well O
, O
he O
is O
a O
lofty O
man O
of O
genius O
, O


and O
admires O
the O
great O
and O
heroic O
in O
life O
and O
novels O
; O
and O
so O
had O
better O
take O


warning O
and O
go O
elsewhere O
. O



speech O
caused O
Amelia B-PERSON
to O
philosophise O
, O
or O
that O
it O
armed O
her O
in O
any O
way O
with O
a O


calmness O
, O
the O
result O
of O
argument O
; O
but O
it O
was O
intolerably O
dull O
, O
pompous O
and O


tedious O
; O
and O
having O
the O
fear O
of O
her O
schoolmistress O
greatly O
before O
her O
eyes O
, O


Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
did O
not O
venture O
, O
in O
her O
presence O
, O
to O
give O
way O
to O
any O
ebullitions O


of O
private O
grief O
. O
A O
seed O
- O
cake O
and O
a O
bottle O
of O
wine O
were O
produced O
in O
the O


drawing O
- O
room O
, O
as O
on O
the O
solemn O
occasions O
of O
the O
visits O
of O
parents O
, O
and O
these O


refreshments O
being O
partaken O
of O
, O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
was O
at O
liberty O
to O
depart O
. O



to O
a O
young O
lady O
of O
whom O
nobody O
took O
any O
notice O
and O
who O
was O
coming O
down O


stairs O
with O
her O
own O
bandbox O
. O


 O
I O
suppose O
I O
must O
, O
 O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
calmly O
, O
and O
much O
to O
the O
wonder O
of O
Miss O


Jemima B-PERSON
; O
and O
the O
latter O
having O
knocked O
at O
the O
door O
, O
and O
receiving O
permission O


to O
come O
in O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
advanced O
in O
a O
very O
unconcerned O
manner O
, O
and O
said O
in O


French B-LANGUAGE
, O
and O
with O
a O
perfect O
accent O
, O
 O
Mademoiselle O
, O
je B-PERSON
viens I-PERSON
vous O
faire O
mes O


adieux B-ORG
. O
 O


Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
did O
not O
understand O
French B-NORP
; O
she O
only O
directed O
those O
who O
did O
: O


but O
biting O
her O
lips O
and O
throwing O
up O
her O
venerable O
and O
Roman B-NORP
- O
nosed O
head O
, O
( O
on O


the O
top O
of O
which O
figured O
a O
large O
and O
solemn O
turban O
, O
) O
she O
said O
, O
 O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O


I O
wish O
you O
a O
good O
morning O
. O
 O
As O
the O
Hammersmith O
Semiramis B-PERSON
spoke O
, O
she O
waved O


one O
hand O
, O
both O
by O
the O
way O
of O
adieu O
, O
and O
to O
give O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
an O
opportunity O
of O


shaking O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O
fingers O
of O
the O
hand O
which O
was O
left O
out O
for O
that O


purpose O
. O


Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
only O
folded O
her O
own O
hands O
with O
a O
very O
frigid O
smile O
and O
bow O
, O
and O


quite O
declined O
to O
accept O
the O
proffered O
honour O
; O
on O
which O
Semiramis B-ORG
tossed O
up O


her O
turban O
more O
indignantly O
than O
ever O
. O
In O
fact O
, O
it O
was O
a O
little O
battle O


between O
the O
young O
lady O
and O
the O
old O
one O
, O
and O
the O
latter O
was O
worsted O
. O
 O
Heaven O


bless O
you O
, O
my O
child O
, O
 O
said O
she O
, O
embracing O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
and O
scowling O
the O
while O


over O
the O
girl O
’s O
shoulder O
at O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
. O
 O
Come O
away O
, O
Becky B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
Miss O


Jemima B-PERSON
, O
pulling O
the O
young O
woman O
away O
in O
great O
alarm O
, O
and O
the O
drawingroom O


door O
closed O
upon O
them O
for O
ever O
. O


Then O
came O
the O
struggle O
and O
parting O
below O
. O
Words O
refuse O
to O
tell O
it O
. O
All O
the O


servants O
were O
there O
in O
the O
hall O
— O
all O
the O
dear O
friends O
— O
all O
the O
young O


ladies O
— O
the O
dancing O
- O
master O
who O
had O
just O
arrived O
; O
and O
there O
was O
such O
a O


scuffling O
, O
and O
hugging O
, O
and O
kissing O
, O
and O
crying O
, O
with O
the O
hysterical O


yoops O

of O
Miss O
Swartz B-PERSON
, O
the O
parlour O
- O
boarder O
, O
from O
her O
room O
, O
as O
no O


pen O
can O
depict O
, O
and O
as O
the O
tender O
heart O
would O
fain O
pass O
over O
. O
The O
embracing O


was O
over O
; O
they O
parted O
— O
that O
is O
, O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
parted O
from O
her O
friends O
. O
Miss O


Sharp B-PERSON
had O
demurely O
entered O
the O
carriage O
some B-TIME
minutes I-TIME
before O
. O
Nobody O
cried O


for O
leaving O

her O
. O


Sambo B-PERSON
of O
the O
bandy O
legs O
slammed O
the O
carriage O
door O
on O
his O
young O
weeping O


mistress O
. O
He O
sprang O
up O
behind O
the O
carriage O
. O
 O
Stop O
! O
 O
cried O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O


rushing O
to O
the O
gate O
with O
a O
parcel O
. O


 O
It O
’s O
some O
sandwiches O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
 O
said O
she O
to O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O
 O
You O
may O
be O
hungry O
, O


you O
know O
; O
and O
Becky B-PERSON
, O
Becky B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
, O
here O
’s O
a O
book O
for O
you O
that O
my O
sister O
— O
that O


is O
, O
I O
— O
Johnson B-PERSON
’s O
Dixonary O
, O
you O
know O
; O
you O
must O
n’t O
leave O
us O
without O
that O
. O


Good O
- O
by O
. O
Drive O
on O
, O
coachman O
. O
God B-PERSON
bless O
you O
! O
 O


And O
the O
kind O
creature O
retreated O
into O
the O
garden O
, O
overcome O
with O
emotion O
. O


But O
, O
lo O
! O
and O
just O
as O
the O
coach O
drove O
off O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
put O
her O
pale O
face O
out O


of O
the O
window O
and O
actually O
flung O
the O
book O
back O
into O
the O
garden O
. O


This O
almost O
caused O
Jemima B-PERSON
to O
faint O
with O
terror O
. O
 O
Well O
, O
I O
never,—said O


she—what O
an O
audacious—Emotion O
prevented O
her O
from O
completing O
either O


sentence O
. O
The O
carriage O
rolled O
away O
; O
the O
great O
gates O
were O
closed O
; O
the O
bell O


rang O
for O
the O
dancing O
lesson O
. O
The O
world O
is O
before O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
ladies O
; O
and O


so O
, O
farewell O
to O
Chiswick B-FAC
Mall I-FAC
. O



II O
. O
In O
Which O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
and O
Miss B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
Prepare I-PERSON
to O
Open O
the O


Campaign O


WHEN O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
had O
performed O
the O
heroical O
act O
mentioned O
in O
the O
last O
chapter O
, O


and O
had O
seen O
the O
Dixonary O
, O
flying O
over O
the O
pavement O
of O
the O
little O
garden O
, O


fall O
at O
length O
at O
the O
feet O
of O
the O
astonished O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON
, O
the O
young O
lady O
’s O


countenance O
, O
which O
had O
before O
worn O
an O
almost O
livid O
look O
of O
hatred O
, O
assumed O
a O


smile O
that O
perhaps O
was O
scarcely O
more O
agreeable O
, O
and O
she O
sank O
back O
in O
the O


carriage O
in O
an O
easy O
frame O
of O
mind O
, O
saying—So B-PERSON
much O
for O
the O
Dixonary O
; O
and O
, O


thank O
God O
, O
I O
’m O
out O
of O
Chiswick B-GPE
. O
 O


Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
was O
almost O
as O
flurried O
at O
the O
act O
of O
defiance O
as O
Miss O
Jemima B-PERSON


had O
been O
; O
for O
, O
consider O
, O
it O
was O
but O
one B-TIME
minute I-TIME
that O
she O
had O
left O
school O
, O
and O


the O
impressions O
of O
six B-DATE
years I-DATE
are O
not O
got O
over O
in O
that O
space O
of O
time O
. O
Nay B-PERSON
, O


with O
some O
persons O
those O
awes O
and O
terrors O
of O
youth O
last O
for O
ever O
and O
ever O
. O
I O



night O
that O
I O
was O
flogged O
by O
Dr. O
Raine B-PERSON
. O
 O
Fancy B-PERSON
had O
carried O
him O
back O



were O
just O
as O
awful O
to O
him O
in O
his O
heart O
, O
then O
, O
at O
sixty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
eight I-CARDINAL
, O
as O
they O
had O



 O
boy O
, O
take O
down O
your O
pant O
… O
? O
 O
Well O
, O
well O
, O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
was O
exceedingly O
alarmed O


at O
this O
act O
of O
insubordination O
. O


 O
How O
could O
you O
do O
so O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
? O
 O
at O
last O
she O
said O
, O
after O
a O
pause O
. O


 O
Why O
, O
do O
you O
think O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
will O
come O
out O
and O
order O
me O
back O
to O
the O


black O
- O
hole O
? O
 O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O


 O
No O
: O
but O
— O
— O
 O


 O
I O
hate O
the O
whole O
house O
, O
 O
continued O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
in O
a O
fury O
. O
 O
I O
hope O
I O
may O


never O
set O
eyes O
on O
it O
again O
. O
I O
wish O
it O
were O
in O
the O
bottom O
of O
the O
Thames B-GPE
, O
I O


do O
; O
and O
if O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
were O
there O
, O
I O
would O
n’t O
pick O
her O
out O
, O
that O
I O


would O
n’t O
. O
O O
how O
I O
should O
like O
to O
see O
her O
floating O
in O
the O
water O
yonder O
, O


turban O
and O
all O
, O
with O
her O
train O
streaming O
after O
her O
, O
and O
her O
nose O
like O
the O


beak O
of O
a O
wherry O
. O
 O


 O
Hush B-PERSON
! O
 O
cried O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
. O


 O
Why O
, O
will O
the O
black O
footman O
tell O
tales O
? O
 O
cried O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
 O
He O


may O
go O
back O
and O
tell O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
that O
I O
hate O
her O
with O
all O
my O
soul O
; O
and O
I O


wish O
he O
would O
; O
and O
I O
wish O
I O
had O
a O
means O
of O
proving O
it O
, O
too O
. O
For O
two B-DATE
years I-DATE
I O


have O
only O
had O
insults O
and O
outrage O
from O
her O
. O
I O
have O
been O
treated O
worse O
than O


any O
servant O
in O
the O
kitchen O
. O
I O
have O
never O
had O
a O
friend O
or O
a O
kind O
word O
, O
except O


from O
you O
. O
I O
have O
been O
made O
to O
tend O
the O
little O
girls O
in O
the O
lower O
schoolroom O
, O


and O
to O
talk O
French B-NORP
to O
the O
Misses O
, O
until O
I O
grew O
sick O
of O
my O
mother O
- O
tongue O
. O
But O


that O
talking O
French B-NORP
to O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
was O
capital O
fun O
, O
was O
n’t O
it O
? O
She O


does O
n’t O
know O
a O
word O
of O
French B-NORP
, O
and O
was O
too O
proud O
to O
confess O
it O
. O
I O
believe O
it O



Vive O
la O
France B-GPE
! O
Vive B-PRODUCT
l’Empereur O
! O
Vive B-PERSON
Bonaparte I-PERSON
! O
 O


 O
O O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
for O
shame O
! O
 O
cried O
Miss O
Sedley B-PERSON
; O
for O
this O
was O
the O



England B-GPE
, O
to O
say O
, O
 O
Long O
live O
Bonaparte B-PERSON
! O
 O
was O
as O
much O
as O
to O
say O
, O
 O
Long O
live O


Lucifer B-PERSON
! O
 O
 O
How O
can O
you O
— O
how O
dare O
you O
have O
such O
wicked O
, O
revengeful O


thoughts O
? O
 O


 O
Revenge O
may O
be O
wicked O
, O
but O
it O
’s O
natural O
, O
 O
answered O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
. O
 O
I O
’m O
no O



disposition O
. O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
not O
, O
then O
, O
in O
the O
least O
kind O
or O
placable O
. O
All O


the O
world O
used O
her O
ill O
, O
said O
this O
young O
misanthropist B-NORP
, O
and O
we O
may O
be O
pretty O


certain O
that O
persons O
whom O
all O
the O
world O
treats O
ill O
deserve O
entirely O
the O


treatment O
they O
get O
. O
The O
world O
is O
a O
looking O
- O
glass O
, O
and O
gives O
back O
to O
every O


man O
the O
reflection O
of O
his O
own O
face O
. O
Frown O
at O
it O
, O
and O
it O
will O
in O
turn O
look O


sourly O
upon O
you O
; O
laugh O
at O
it O
and O
with O
it O
, O
and O
it O
is O
a O
jolly O
kind O
companion O
; O


and O
so O
let O
all O
young O
persons O
take O
their O
choice O
. O
This O
is O
certain O
, O
that O
if O
the O



not O
be O
expected O
that O
every O
one O
should O
be O
of O
the O
humble O
and O
gentle O
temper O
of O


Miss O
Amelia B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
; O
should O
take O
every O
opportunity O
to O
vanquish O
Rebecca B-PERSON
’s O


hard O
- O
heartedness O
and O
ill O
- O
humor O
; O
and O
, O
by O
a B-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
kind O
words O
and O
offices O
, O


overcome O
, O
for O
once O
at O
least O
, O
her O
hostility O
to O
her O
kind O
. O


Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
’s O
father O
was O
an O
artist O
, O
and O
in O
that O
quality O
had O
given O
lessons O
of O


drawing O
at O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
’s I-PERSON
school O
. O
He O
was O
a O
clever O
man O
; O
a O
pleasant O


companion O
; O
a O
careless O
student O
; O
with O
a O
great O
propensity O
for O
running O
into O


debt O
, O
and O
a O
partiality O
for O
the O
tavern O
. O
When O
he O
was O
drunk O
, O
he O
used O
to O
beat O


his O
wife O
and O
daughter O
; O
and O
the B-TIME
next I-TIME
morning I-TIME
, O
with O
a O
headache O
, O
he O
would O
rail O


at O
the O
world O
for O
its O
neglect O
of O
his O
genius O
, O
and O
abuse O
, O
with O
a O
good O
deal O
of O


cleverness O
, O
and O
sometimes O
with O
perfect O
reason O
, O
the O
fools O
, O
his O
brother O



was O
by O
profession O
an O
opera O
- O
girl O
. O
The O
humble O
calling O
of O
her O
female O
parent O
, O



descent O
from O
them O
. O
And O
curious O
it O
is O
, O
that O
as O
she O
advanced O
in O
life O
this O


young O
lady O
’s O
ancestors O
increased O
in O
rank O
and O
splendour O
. O


Rebecca B-PERSON
’s O
mother O
had O
had O
some O
education O
somewhere O
, O
and O
the O
daughter O
spoke O


French B-NORP
with O
purity O
and O
a O
Parisian B-NORP
accent O
. O
It O
was O
in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
rather O
a O
rare O


accomplishment O
, O
and O
led O
to O
her O
engagement O
with O
the O
orthodox O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
. O


For O
her O
mother O
being O
dead O
, O
her O
father O
, O
finding O
himself O
not O
likely O
to O


recover O
, O
after O
his O
third B-ORDINAL
attack O
of O

delirium O
tremens O
, O

wrote O
a O
manly O


and O
pathetic O
letter O
to O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
recommending O
the O
orphan O
child O
to O
her O


protection O
, O
and O
so O
descended O
to O
the O
grave O
, O
after O
two B-CARDINAL
bailiffs O
had O
quarrelled O


over O
his O
corpse O
. O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
seventeen B-DATE
when O
she O
came O
to O
Chiswick B-GPE
, O
and O
was O


bound O
over O
as O
an O
articled O
pupil O
; O
her O
duties O
being O
to O
talk O
French B-NORP
, O
as O
we O
have O


seen O
; O
and O
her O
privileges O
to O
live O
cost O
free O
, O
and O
, O
with O
a B-MONEY
few I-MONEY
guineas I-MONEY
a O
year O
, O


to O
gather O
scraps O
of O
knowledge O
from O
the O
professors O
who O
attended O
the O


school O
. O



reading O
- O
desk O
. O
This O
infatuated O
young O
man O
used O
sometimes O
to O
take O
tea O
with O
Miss O


Pinkerton B-PERSON
, O
to O
whom O
he O
had O
been O
presented O
by O
his O
mamma O
, O
and O
actually O
proposed O


something O
like O
marriage O
in O
an O
intercepted O
note O
, O
which O
the O
one B-CARDINAL
- O
eyed O


apple O
- O
woman O
was O
charged O
to O
deliver O
. O
Mrs. O
Crisp B-PERSON
was O
summoned O
from O
Buxton B-ORG
, O
and O



Rebecca B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
looked O
like O
a O
child O
. O
But O
she O
had O
the O
dismal O
precocity O
of O


poverty O
. O
Many O
a O
dun O
had O
she O
talked O
to O
, O
and O
turned O
away O
from O
her O
father O
’s O


door O
; O
many O
a O
tradesman O
had O
she O
coaxed O
and O
wheedled O
into O
goodhumour O
, O
and O
into O


the O
granting O
of O
one B-CARDINAL
meal O
more O
. O
She O
sate O
commonly O
with O
her O
father O
, O
who O
was O


very O
proud O
of O
her O
wit O
, O
and O
heard O
the O
talk O
of O
many O
of O
his O
wild O


companions O
— O
often O
but O
ill O
- O
suited O
for O
a O
girl O
to O
hear O
. O
But O
she O
never O
had O
been O
a O


girl O
, O
she O
said O
; O
she O
had O
been O
a O
woman O
since O
she O
was O
eight B-DATE
years I-DATE
old I-DATE
. O
O O
why O


did O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
let O
such O
a O
dangerous O
bird O
into O
her O
cage O
? O




nursing O
it O
in O
school B-TIME
- I-TIME
hours I-TIME
. O
How O
the O
father O
and O
daughter O
laughed O
as O
they O


trudged O
home O
together O
after O
the O
evening B-TIME
party O
, O
( O
it O
was O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O


the O
speeches O
, O
when O
all O
the O
professors O
were O
invited O
, O
) O
and O
how O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON


would O
have O
raged O
had O
she O
seen O
the O
caricature O
of O
herself O
which O
the O
little O


mimic O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
managed O
to O
make O
out O
of O
her O
doll O
. O
Becky B-PERSON
used O
to O
go O
through O



known O
to O
them O
, O
poor O
soul O
! O
as O
Mr. O
Lawrence B-PERSON
or O
President O
West O
. O
Once O
Rebecca B-PERSON



father O
. O
She O
had O
a O
little O
room O
in O
the O
garret O
, O
where O
the O
maids O
heard O
her O


walking O
and O
sobbing O
at O
night B-TIME
; O
but O
it O
was O
with O
rage O
, O
and O
not O
with O
grief O
. O
She O


had O
not O
been O
much O
of O
a O
dissembler O
, O
until O
now O
her O
loneliness O
taught O
her O
to O


feign O
. O
She O
had O
never O
mingled O
in O
the O
society O
of O
women O
: O
her O
father O
, O
reprobate O


as O
he O
was O
, O
was O
a O
man O
of O
talent O
; O
his O
conversation O
was O
a B-CARDINAL
thousand I-CARDINAL
times O
more O


agreeable O
to O
her O
than O
the O
talk O
of O
such O
of O
her O
own O
sex O
as O
she O
now O


encountered O
. O
The O
pompous O
vanity O
of O
the O
old O
schoolmistress O
, O
the O
foolish O


good O
- O
humour O
of O
her O
sister O
, O
the O
silly O
chat O
and O
scandal O
of O
the O
elder O
girls O
, O


and O
the O
frigid O
correctness O
of O
the O
governesses O
equally O
annoyed O
her O
; O
and O
she O


had O
no O
soft O
maternal O
heart O
, O
this O
unlucky O
girl O
, O
otherwise O
the O
prattle O
and O


talk O
of O
the O
younger O
children O
, O
with O
whose O
care O
she O
was O
chiefly O
intrusted O
, O


might O
have O
soothed O
and O
interested O
her O
; O
but O
she O
lived O
among O
them O
two B-DATE
years I-DATE
, O


and O
not O
one O
was O
sorry O
that O
she O
went O
away O
. O
The O
gentle O
tender O
- O
hearted O
Amelia B-PERSON



The O
happiness O
— O
the O
superior O
advantages O
of O
the O
young O
women O
round O
about O
her O
, O


gave O
Rebecca B-PERSON
inexpressible O
pangs O
of O
envy O
. O
 O
What O
airs O
that O
girl O
gives O



they O
cringe O
and O
bow O
to O
that O
Creole B-NORP
, O
because O
of O
her B-QUANTITY
hundred I-QUANTITY
thousand I-QUANTITY
pounds I-QUANTITY
! O


I O
am O
a O
thousand O
times O
cleverer O
and O
more O
charming O
than O
that O
creature O
, O
for O
all O


her O
wealth O
. O
I O
am O
as O
well O
bred O
as O
the O
Earl O
’s O
grand O
- O
daughter O
, O
for O
all O
her O
fine O


pedigree O
; O
and O
yet O
every O
one B-CARDINAL
passes O
me O
by O
here O
. O
And O
yet O
, O
when O
I O
was O
at O
my O



pass O
the O
evening O
with O
me O
? O
 O
She O
determined O
at O
any O
rate O
to O
get O
free O
from O
the O


prison O
in O
which O
she O
found O
herself O
, O
and O
now O
began O
to O
act O
for O
herself O
, O
and O
for O


the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
to O
make O
connected O
plans O
for O
the O
future O
. O


She O
took O
advantage O
, O
therefore O
, O
of O
the O
means O
of O
study O
the O
place O
offered O
her O
; O


and O
as O
she O
was O
already O
a O
musician O
and O
a O
good O
linguist O
, O
she O
speedily O
went O


through O
the O
little O
course O
of O
study O
which O
was O
considered O
necessary O
for O
ladies O


in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
. O
Her O
music O
she O
practised O
incessantly O
, O
and O
one B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
when O
the O


girls O
were O
out O
, O
and O
she O
had O
remained O
at O
home O
, O
she O
was O
overheard O
to O
play O
a O


piece O
so O
well O
, O
that O
Minerva B-PERSON
thought O
wisely O
, O
she O
could O
spare O
herself O
the O


expense O
of O
a O
master O
for O
the O
juniors O
, O
and O
intimated O
to O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
that O
she O


was O
to O
instruct O
them O
in O
music O
for O
the O
future O
. O



majestic O
mistress O
of O
the O
school O
. O
 O
I O
am O
here O
to O
speak O
French B-NORP
with O
the O


children O
, O
 O
Rebecca B-PERSON
said O
abruptly O
, O
 O
not O
to O
teach O
them O
music O
, O
and O
save O
money O


for O
you O
. O
Give O
me O
money O
, O
and O
I O
will O
teach O
them O
. O
 O


Minerva B-PERSON
was O
obliged O
to O
yield O
, O
and O
, O
of O
course O
, O
disliked O
her O
from O
that B-DATE
day I-DATE
. O


 O
For O
five B-DATE
- I-DATE
and I-DATE
- I-DATE
thirty I-DATE
years I-DATE
, O
 O
she O
said O
, O
and O
with O
great O
justice O
, O
 O
I O
never O
have O


seen O
the O
individual O
who O
has O
dared O
in O
my O
own O
house O
to O
question O
my O
authority O
. O


I O
have O
nourished O
a O
viper O
in O
my O
bosom O
. O
 O


 O
A O
viper O
— O
a O
fiddlestick O
, O
 O
said O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
to O
the O
old O
lady O
, O
almost O
fainting O


with O
astonishment O
. O
 O
You O
took O
me O
because O
I O
was O
useful O
. O
There O
is O
no O
question O


of O
gratitude O
between O
us O
. O
I O
hate O
this O
place O
, O
and O
want O
to O
leave O
it O
. O
I O
will O
do O


nothing O
here O
but O
what O
I O
am O
obliged O
to O
do O
. O
 O


It O
was O
in O
vain O
that O
the O
old O
lady O
asked O
her O
if O
she O
was O
aware O
she O
was O


speaking O
to O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
? O
Rebecca B-PERSON
laughed O
in O
her O
face O
, O
with O
a O
horrid O


sarcastic O
demoniacal O
laughter O
, O
that O
almost O
sent O
the O
schoolmistress O
into O


fits O
. O
 O
Give O
me O
a O
sum O
of O
money O
, O
 O
said O
the O
girl O
, O
 O
and O
get O
rid O
of O
me O
— O
or O
, O
if O
you O


like O
better O
, O
get O
me O
a O
good O
place O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
noblesman B-PERSON
’s O
family O
— O
you O


can O
do O
so O
if O
you O
please O
. O
 O
And O
in O
their O
further O
disputes O
she O
always O
returned O


to O
this O
point O
, O
 O
Get O
me O
a O
situation O
— O
we O
hate O
each O
other O
, O
and O
I O
am O
ready O
to O


go O
. O
 O


Worthy B-PERSON
Miss I-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
, O
although O
she O
had O
a O
Roman B-NORP
nose O
and O
a O
turban O
, O
and O
was O


as O
tall O
as O
a O
grenadier O
, O
and O
had O
been O
up O
to O
this O
time O
an O
irresistible O


princess O
, O
had O
no O
will O
or O
strength O
like O
that O
of O
her O
little O
apprentice O
, O
and O
in O


vain O
did O
battle O
against O
her O
, O
and O
tried O
to O
overawe O
her O
. O
Attempting O
once O
to O


scold O
her O
in O
public O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
hit O
upon O
the O
beforementioned B-ORG
plan O
of O
answering O


her O
in O
French B-NORP
, O
which O
quite O
routed O
the O
old O
woman O
. O
In O
order O
to O
maintain O



Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
for O
the O
situation O
, O
firebrand O
and O
servant O
as O
she O
was O
. O
 O
I O
can O
not O
, O


certainly O
, O
 O
she O
said O
, O
 O
find O
fault O
with O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
’s O
conduct O
, O
except O
to O


myself O
; O
and O
must O
allow O
that O
her O
talents O
and O
accomplishments O
are O
of O
a O
high O


order O
. O
As O
far O
as O
the O
head O
goes O
, O
at O
least O
, O
she O
does O
credit O
to O
the O
educational O


system O
pursued O
at O
my O
establishment O
. O
 O


And O
so O
the O
schoolmistress O
reconciled O
the O
recommendation O
to O
her O
conscience O
, O


and O
the O
indentures O
were O
cancelled O
, O
and O
the O
apprentice O
was O
free O
. O
The O
battle O


here O
described O
in O
a O
few O
lines O
, O
of O
course O
, O
lasted O
for O
some B-DATE
months I-DATE
. O
And O
as O



and O
had O
a O
friendship O
for O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
( O
 O
’ O
tis O
the O
only O
point O
in O
Amelia B-PERSON
’s O


behaviour O
, O
 O
said O
Minerva B-PERSON
, O
 O
which O
has O
not O
been O
satisfactory O
to O
her O


mistress O
, O
 O
) O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
was O
invited O
by O
her O
friend O
to O
pass O
a B-DATE
week I-DATE
with O
her O
at O


home O
, O
before O
she O
entered O
upon O
her O
duties O
as O
governess O
in O
a O
private O


family O
. O


Thus O
the O
world O
began O
for O
these O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
ladies O
. O
For O
Amelia B-PERSON
it O
was O
quite O
a O



answer O

to O
another O
letter O
) O
. O
But O
who O
can O
tell O
you O
the O
real O
truth O


of O
the O
matter O
? O
At O
all O
events O
, O
if O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
not O
beginning O
the O
world O
, O
she O


was O
beginning O
it O
over O
again O
. O



he O
was O
riding O
by O
and O
said O
, O
 O
A O
dem B-NORP
fine O
gal O
, O
egad O
! O
 O
and O
before O
the O
carriage O



Lord O
Mayor B-PERSON
’s O
ball O
she O
knew O
she O
was O
to O
go O
. O
And O
when O
at O
length O
home O
was O


reached O
, O
Miss O
Amelia B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
skipped O
out O
on O
Sambo B-PERSON
’s O
arm O
, O
as O
happy O
and O
as O


handsome O
a O
girl O
as O
any O
in O
the O
whole O
big O
city O
of O
London B-GPE
. O
Both O
he O
and O
coachman O


agreed O
on O
this O
point O
, O
and O
so O
did O
her O
father O
and O
mother O
, O
and O
so O
did O
every O
one O


of O
the O
servants O
in O
the O
house O
, O
as O
they O
stood O
bobbing O
and O
curtseying O
, O
and O


smiling O
, O
in O
the O
hall O
to O
welcome O
their O
young O
mistress O
. O


You O
may O
be O
sure O
that O
she O
showed O
Rebecca B-PERSON
over O
every O
room O
of O
the O
house O
, O
and O


everything O
in O
every O
one O
of O
her O
drawers O
; O
and O
her O
books O
, O
and O
her O
piano O
, O
and O


her O
dresses O
, O
and O
all O
her O
necklaces O
, O
brooches O
, O
laces O
, O
and O
gimcracks B-ORG
. O
She O


insisted O
upon O
Rebecca B-PERSON
accepting O
the O
white O
cornelian O
and O
the O
turquoise O
rings O
, O


and O
a O
sweet O
sprigged O
muslin O
, O
which O
was O
too O
small O
for O
her O
, O
though O
it O
would O


fit O
her O
friend O
to O
a O
nicety O
; O
and O
she O
determined O
in O
her O
heart O
to O
ask O
her O


mother O
’s O
permission O
to O
present O
her O
white O
Cashmere B-PERSON
shawl O
to O
her O
friend O
. O
Could O



be O
delightful O
to O
have O
a O
brother O
, O
 O
and O
easily O
got O
the O
pity O
of O
the O


tender O
- O
hearted O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
for O
being O
alone O
in O
the O
world O
, O
an O
orphan O
without O


friends O
or O
kindred O
. O


 O
Not O
alone O
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
; O
 O
you O
know O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
I O
shall O
always O
be O
your O


friend O
, O
and O
love O
you O
as O
a O
sister O
— O
indeed O
I O
will O
. O
 O


 O
Ah O
, O
but O
to O
have O
parents O
, O
as O
you O
have O
— O
kind O
, O
rich O
, O
affectionate O
parents O
, O
who O


give O
you O
everything O
you O
ask O
for O
; O
and O
their O
love O
, O
which O
is O
more O
precious O
than O


all O
! O
My O
poor O
papa O
could O
give O
me O
nothing O
, O
and O
I O
had O
but O
two B-CARDINAL
frocks O
in O
all O
the O


world O
! O
And O
then O
, O
to O
have O
a O
brother O
, O
a O
dear O
brother O
! O
Oh O
, O
how O
you O
must O
love O


him O
! O
 O


Amelia B-PERSON
laughed O
. O


 O
What O
! O

do O
n’t O

you O
love O
him O
? O
you O
, O
who O
say O
you O
love O
everybody O
? O
 O


 O
Yes O
, O
of O
course O
, O
I O
do O
— O
only O
— O
 O


 O
Only O
what O
? O
 O



me O
two B-CARDINAL
fingers O
to O
shake O
when O
he O
arrived O
after O
ten B-DATE
years I-DATE
’ I-DATE
absence O
! O
He O
is O
very O


kind O
and O
good O
, O
but O
he O
scarcely O
ever O
speaks O
to O
me O
; O
I O
think O
he O
loves O
his O
pipe O


a O
great O
deal O
better O
than O
his O
 O
… O
but O
here O
Amelia B-PERSON
checked O
herself O
, O
for O
why O


should O
she O
speak O
ill O
of O
her O
brother O
? O
 O
He O
was O
very O
kind O
to O
me O
as O
a O
child O
, O
 O


she O
added O
; O
 O
I O
was O
but O
five B-DATE
years I-DATE
old I-DATE
when O
he O
went O
away O
. O
 O


 O
Is O
n’t O
he O
very O
rich O
? O
 O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
. O
 O
They O
say O
all O
Indian B-NORP
nabobs O
are O


enormously O
rich O
. O
 O


 O
I O
believe O
he O
has O
a O
very O
large O
income O
. O
 O


 O
And O
is O
your O
sister O
- O
in O
- O
law O
a O
nice O
pretty O
woman O
? O
 O


 O
La B-WORK_OF_ART
! O
Joseph B-PERSON
is O
not O
married O
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
again O
. O


Perhaps O
she O
had O
mentioned O
the O
fact O
already O
to O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
but O
that O
young O
lady O


did O
not O
appear O
to O
have O
remembered O
it O
; O
indeed O
, O
vowed O
and O
protested O
that O
she O


expected O
to O
see O
a O
number O
of O
Amelia B-PERSON
’s O
nephews O
and O
nieces O
. O
She O
was O
quite O



 O
I O
think O
you O
must O
have O
had O
enough O
of O
them O
at O
Chiswick B-GPE
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
rather O



deceiving O
, O
poor O
innocent O
creature O
! O
and O
making O
her O
own O
experience O
in O
her O
own O



is O
rich O
and O
unmarried O
, O
why O
should O
I O
not O
marry O
him O
? O
I O
have O
only O
a O
fortnight O
, O


to O
be O
sure O
, O
but O
there O
is O
no O
harm O
in O
trying O
. O
 O
And O
she O
determined O
within O


herself O
to O
make O
this O
laudable O
attempt O
. O
She O
redoubled O
her O
caresses O
to O
Amelia B-PERSON
; O


she O
kissed O
the O
white O
cornelian O
necklace O
as O
she O
put O
it O
on O
; O
and O
vowed O
she O


would O
never O
, O
never O
part O
with O
it O
. O
When O
the O
dinner O
- O
bell O
rang O
she O
went O
down O


stairs O
with O
her O
arm O
round O
her O
friend O
’s O
waist O
, O
as O
is O
the O
habit O
of O
young O


ladies O
. O
She O
was O
so O
agitated O
at O
the O
drawing O
- O
room O
door O
, O
that O
she O
could O
hardly O


find O
courage O
to O
enter O
. O
 O
Feel O
my O
heart O
, O
how O
it O
beats O
, O
dear O
! O
 O
said O
she O
to O
her O


friend O
. O


 O
No O
, O
it O
does O
n’t O
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O
 O
Come O
in O
, O
do O
n’t O
be O
frightened O
. O
Papa O
wo O
n’t O
do O


you O
any O
harm O
. O
 O



III O
. O
Rebecca B-PERSON
Is O
in O
Presence O
of O
the O
Enemy O


A O
VERY O
stout O
, O
puffy O
man O
, O
in O
buckskins O
and O
Hessian B-NORP
boots O
, O
with O
several O
immense O


neckcloths B-PERSON
, O
that O
rose O
almost O
to O
his O
nose O
, O
with O
a O
red O
striped O
waistcoat O
and O


an O
apple O
green O
coat O
with O
steel O
buttons O
almost O
as O
large O
as O
crown O
pieces O
, O
( O
it O


was O
the O
morning B-TIME
costume O
of O
a O
dandy O
or O
blood O
of O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
) O
was O
reading O
the O


paper O
by O
the O
fire O
when O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
girls O
entered O
, O
and O
bounced O
off O
his O
arm O
- O
chair O
, O


and O
blushed O
excessively O
, O
and O
hid O
his O
entire O
face O
almost O
in O
his O
neckcloths O
at O


this O
apparition O
. O


 O
It O
’s O
only O
your O
sister O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
and O
shaking O
the O
two B-CARDINAL


fingers O
which O
he O
held O
out O
. O
 O
I O
’ve O
come O
home O

for O
good O
, O

you O
know O
; O
and O


this O
is O
my O
friend O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
whom O
you O
have O
heard O
me O
mention O
. O
 O


 O
No O
, O
never O
, O
upon O
my O
word O
, O
 O
said O
the O
head O
under O
the O
neckcloth B-PERSON
, O
shaking O
very O


much,—that B-PERSON
is O
, O
yes,—what O
abominably O
cold O
weather O
, O
Miss;—and O
herewith O
he O


fell O
to O
poking O
the O
fire O
with O
all O
his O
might O
, O
although O
it O
was O
in O
the O
middle O
of O


June B-DATE
. O


 O
He O
’s O
very O
handsome O
, O
 O
whispered O
Rebecca B-PERSON
to O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
rather O
loud O
. O


 O
Do O
you O
think O
so O
? O
 O
said O
the O
latter O
. O
 O
I O
’ll O
tell O
him O
. O
 O


 O
Darling O
! O
not O
for O
worlds O
, O
 O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
, O
starting O
back O
as O
timid O
as O
a O


fawn O
. O
She O
had O
previously O
made O
a O
respectful O
virgin O
- O
like O
curtsey O
to O
the O


gentleman O
, O
and O
her O
modest O
eyes O
gazed O
so O
perseveringly O
on O
the O
carpet O
that O
it O


was O
a O
wonder O
how O
she O
should O
have O
found O
an O
opportunity O
to O
see O
him O
. O


 O
Thank O
you O
for O
the O
beautiful O
shawls O
, O
brother O
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
to O
the O
fire O


poker O
. O
 O
Are O
they O
not O
beautiful O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
? O
 O


 O
O O
heavenly O
! O
 O
said O
Miss B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
, O
and O
her O
eyes O
went O
from O
the O
carpet O
straight O


to O
the O
chandelier O
. O


Joseph B-PERSON
still O
continued O
a O
huge O
clattering O
at O
the O
poker O
and O
tongs O
, O
puffing O


and O
blowing O
the O
while O
, O
and O
turning O
as O
red O
as O
his O
yellow O
face O
would O
allow O


him O
. O
 O
I O
ca O
n’t O
make O
you O
such O
handsome O
presents O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
 O
continued O
his O


sister O
, O
 O
but O
while O
I O
was O
at O
school O
, O
I O
have O
embroidered O
for O
you O
a O
very O


beautiful O
pair O
of O
braces O
. O
 O


 O
Good O
Gad B-PERSON
! O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
 O
cried O
the O
brother O
, O
in O
serious O
alarm O
, O
 O
what O
do O
you O


mean O
? O
 O
and O
plunging O
with O
all O
his O
might O
at O
the O
bell O
- O
rope O
, O
that O
article O
of O


furniture O
came O
away O
in O
his O
hand O
, O
and O
increased O
the O
honest O
fellow O
’s O


confusion O
. O
 O
For O
heaven O
’s O
sake O
see O
if O
my O
buggy O
’s O
at O
the O
door O
. O
I O


ca O
n’t O

wait O
. O
I O
must O
go O
. O
D O
— O
that O
groom O
of O
mine O
. O
I O
must O
go O
. O
 O


At O
this B-TIME
minute I-TIME
the O
father O
of O
the O
family O
walked O
in O
, O
rattling O
his O
seals O
like O


a O
true O
British B-NORP
merchant O
. O
 O
What O
’s O
the O
matter O
, O
Emmy B-PERSON
? O
 O
says O
he O
. O


 O
Joseph B-PERSON
wants O
me O
to O
see O
if O
his O
— O
his O
buggy O
is O
at O
the O
door O
. O
What O
is O
a O
buggy O
, O


papa O
? O
 O


 O
It O
is O
a O
one B-CARDINAL
- O
horse O
palanquin O
, O
 O
said O
the O
old O
gentleman O
, O
who O
was O
a O
wag O
in O
his O


way O
. O


Joseph B-PERSON
at O
this O
burst O
out O
into O
a O
wild O
fit O
of O
laughter O
; O
in O
which O
, O


encountering O
the O
eye O
of O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
he O
stopped O
all O
of O
a O
sudden O
, O
as O
if O
he O
had O


been O
shot O
. O


 O
This O
young O
lady O
is O
your O
friend O
? O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
I O
am O
very O
happy O
to O
see O
you O
. O


Have O
you O
and O
Emmy B-PERSON
been O
quarrelling O
already O
with O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
that O
he O
wants O
to O
be O


off O
? O
 O


 O
I O
promised O
Bonamy B-PERSON
of O
our O
service O
, O
sir O
, O
 O
said O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
 O
to O
dine O
with O


him O
. O
 O


 O
O O
fie O
! O
did O
n’t O
you O
tell O
your O
mother O
you O
would O
dine O
here O
? O
 O


 O
But O
in O
this O
dress O
it O
’s O
impossible O
. O
 O


 O
Look O
at O
him O
, O
is O
n’t O
he O
handsome O
enough O
to O
dine O
anywhere O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
? O
 O


On O
which O
, O
of O
course O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
looked O
at O
her O
friend O
, O
and O
they O
both O
set O
off O


in O
a O
fit O
of O
laughter O
, O
highly O
agreeable O
to O
the O
old O
gentleman O
. O


 O
Did O
you O
ever O
see O
a O
pair O
of O
buckskins O
like O
those O
at O
Miss B-PERSON
Pinkerton I-PERSON
’s I-PERSON
? O
 O


continued O
he O
, O
following O
up O
his O
advantage O
. O


 O
Gracious O
heavens O
! O
Father O
, O
 O
cried O
Joseph B-PERSON
. O


 O
There O
now O
, O
I O
have O
hurt O
his O
feelings O
. O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
my O
dear O
, O
I O
have O
hurt O


your O
son O
’s O
feelings O
. O
I O
have O
alluded O
to O
his O
buckskins O
. O
Ask O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
if O
I O


have O
n’t O
? O
Come O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
be O
friends O
with O
Miss O
sharp O
and O
let O
us O
all O
go O
to O


dinner O
. O
 O


 O
There O
’s O
a O
pillau O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
just O
as O
you O
like O
it O
, O
and O
Papa B-PERSON
has O
brought O
home O


the O
best O
turbot O
in O
Billingsgate B-ORG
. O
 O


 O
Come O
, O
come O
, O
sir O
, O
walk O
down O
stairs O
with O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
and O
I O
will O
follow O
with O


these O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
women O
, O
 O
said O
the O
father O
, O
and O
he O
took O
an O
arm O
of O
wife O
and O


daughter O
and O
walked O
merrily O
off O
. O


If O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
Sharp I-PERSON
had O
determined O
in O
her O
heart O
upon O
making O
the O
conquest O


of O
this O
big O
beau O
, O
I O
do O
n’t O
think O
, O
ladies O
, O
we O
have O
any O
right O
to O
blame O
her O
; O
for O


though O
the O
task O
of O
husband O
- O
hunting O
is O
generally O
, O
and O
with O
becoming O
modesty O
, O


entrusted O
by O
young O
persons O
to O
their O
mammas O
, O
recollect O
that O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
had O
no O


kind O
parent O
to O
arrange O
these O
delicate O
matters O
for O
her O
, O
and O
that O
if O
she O
did O


not O
get O
a O
husband O
for O
herself O
, O
there O
was O
no O
one O
else O
in O
the O
wide O
world O
who O


would O
take O
the O
trouble O
off O
her O
hands O
. O
What O
causes O
young O
people O
to O
 O
come O


out O
, O
 O
but O
the O
noble O
ambition O
of O
matrimony O
? O
What O
sends O
them O
trooping O
to O


watering O
- O
places O
? O
What O
keeps O
them O
dancing O
till O
five B-TIME
o’clock I-TIME
in I-TIME
the I-TIME
morning I-TIME


through O
a O
whole O
mortal O
season O
? O
What O
causes O
them O
to O
labour O
at O
piano O
- O
forte O


sonatas O
, O
and O
to O
learn O
four B-CARDINAL
songs O
from O
a O
fashionable O
master O
at O
a O
guinea O
a O


lesson O
, O
and O
to O
play O
the O
harp O
if O
they O
have O
handsome O
arms O
and O
neat O
elbows O
, O
and O


to O
wear O
Lincoln B-PERSON
Green I-PERSON
toxophilite O
hats O
and O
feathers O
, O
but O
that O
they O
may O
bring O


down O
some O
 O
desirable O
 O
young O
man O
with O
those O
killing O
bows O
and O
arrows O
of O


theirs O
? O
What O
causes O
respectable O
parents O
to O
take O
up O
their O
carpets O
, O
set O
their O


houses O
topsy O
- O
turvy O
, O
and O
spend O
a B-CARDINAL
fifth I-CARDINAL
of O
their O
year B-DATE
’s O
income O
in O
ball O
suppers O


and O
iced O
champagne O
? O
Is O
it O
sheer O
love O
of O
their O
species O
, O
an O
unadulterated O
wish O


to O
see O
young O
people O
happy O
and O
dancing O
? O
Psha O
! O
they O
want O
to O
marry O
their O


daughters O
; O
and O
, O
as O
honest O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
has O
, O
in O
the O
depths O
of O
her O
kind O
heart O
, O


already O
arranged O
a O
score O
of O
little O
schemes O
for O
the O
settlement O
of O
her O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O


so O
also O
had O
our O
beloved O
but O
unprotected O
Rebecca B-PERSON
determined O
to O
do O
her O
very O


best O
to O
secure O
the O
husband O
, O
who O
was O
even O
more O
necessary O
for O
her O
than O
for O
her O


friend O
. O
She O
had O
a O
vivid O
imagination O
; O
she O
had O
, O
besides O
, O
read O
the O

Arabian B-WORK_OF_ART


Nights I-WORK_OF_ART

and O

Guthrie B-PERSON
’s O
Geography O
; O

and O
it O
is O
a O
fact O
, O
that O


while O
she O
was O
dressing O
for O
dinner O
, O
and O
after O
she O
had O
asked O
Amelia B-PERSON
whether O


her O
brother O
was O
very O
rich O
, O
she O
had O
built O
for O
herself O
a O
most O
magnificent O


castle O
in O
the O
air O
, O
of O
which O
she O
was O
mistress O
, O
with O
a O
husband O
somewhere O
in O


the O
background O
( O
she O
had O
not O
seen O
him O
as O
yet O
, O
and O
his O
figure O
would O
not O


therefore O
be O
very O
distinct O
) O
; O
she O
had O
arrayed O
herself O
in O
an O
infinity O
of O


shawls O
, O
turbans O
, O
and O
diamond O
necklaces O
, O
and O
had O
mounted O
upon O
an O
elephant O
to O


the O
sound O
of O
the O
march O
in O
Bluebeard B-ORG
, O
in O
order O
to O
pay O
a O
visit O
of O
ceremony O
to O


the O
Grand O
Mogul O
. O
Charming B-PERSON
Alnaschar I-PERSON
visions O
! O
it O
is O
the O
happy O
privilege O
of O


youth O
to O
construct O
you O
, O
and O
many O
a O
fanciful O
young O
creature O
besides O
Rebecca B-PERSON


Sharp B-PERSON
has O
indulged O
in O
these O
delightful O
day O
- O
dreams O
ere O
now O
! O


Joseph B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
was O
twelve B-DATE
years I-DATE
older O
than O
his O
sister O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O
He O
was O
in O
the O


East B-ORG
India I-ORG
Company I-ORG
’s I-ORG
Civil I-ORG
Service I-ORG
, O
and O
his O
name O
appeared O
, O
at O
the O
period O
of O


which O
we O
write O
, O
in O
the O
Bengal B-GPE
division O
of O
the B-ORG
East I-ORG
India I-ORG
Register I-ORG
, O
as O


collector O
of O
Boggley B-ORG
Wollah I-ORG
, O
an O
honourable O
and O
lucrative O
post O
, O
as O
everybody O


knows O
: O
in O
order O
to O
know O
to O
what O
higher O
posts O
Joseph B-PERSON
rose O
in O
the O
service O
, O
the O


reader O
is O
referred O
to O
the O
same O
periodical O
. O


Boggley B-PERSON
Wollah I-PERSON
is O
situated O
in O
a O
fine O
, O
lonely O
, O
marshy O
, O
jungly B-GPE
district I-GPE
, O


famous O
for O
snipe O
- O
shooting O
, O
and O
where O
not O
unfrequently O
you O
may O
flush O
a O
tiger O
. O


Ramgunge B-PERSON
, O
where O
there O
is O
a O
magistrate O
, O
is O
only B-QUANTITY
forty I-QUANTITY
miles I-QUANTITY
off O
, O
and O
there O
is O


a O
cavalry O
station O
about B-QUANTITY
thirty I-QUANTITY
miles I-QUANTITY
farther O
; O
so O
Joseph B-PERSON
wrote O
home O
to O
his O


parents O
, O
when O
he O
took O
possession O
of O
his O
collectorship O
. O
He O
had O
lived O
for O


about B-DATE
eight I-DATE
years I-DATE
of O
his O
life O
, O
quite O
alone O
, O
at O
this O
charming O
place O
, O
scarcely O


seeing O
a O
Christian B-NORP
face O
except O
twice O
a O
year O
, O
when O
the O
detachment O
arrived O
to O


carry O
off O
the O
revenues O
which O
he O
had O
collected O
, O
to O
Calcutta B-ORG
. O


Luckily O
, O
at O
this O
time O
he O
caught O
a O
liver O
complaint O
, O
for O
the O
cure O
of O
which O
he O


returned O
to O
Europe B-LOC
, O
and O
which O
was O
the O
source O
of O
great O
comfort O
and O
amusement O


to O
him O
in O
his O
native O
country O
. O
He O
did O
not O
live O
with O
his O
family O
while O
in O


London B-GPE
, O
but O
had O
lodgings O
of O
his O
own O
, O
like O
a O
gay O
young O
bachelor O
. O
Before O
he O


went O
to O
India B-GPE
he O
was O
too O
young O
to O
partake O
of O
the O
delightful O
pleasures O
of O
a O


man O
about O
town O
, O
and O
plunged O
into O
them O
on O
his O
return O
with O
considerable O


assiduity O
. O
He O
drove O
his O
horses O
in O
the O
Park O
; O
he O
dined O
at O
the O
fashionable O


taverns O
( O
for O
the B-ORG
Oriental I-ORG
Club I-ORG
was O
not O
as O
yet O
invented O
) O
; O
he O
frequented O
the O


theatres O
, O
as O
the O
mode O
was O
in O
those B-DATE
days I-DATE
, O
or O
made O
his O
appearance O
at O
the O


opera O
, O
laboriously O
attired O
in O
tights O
and O
a O
cocked O
hat O
. O


On O
returning O
to O
India B-GPE
, O
and O
ever O
after O
, O
he O
used O
to O
talk O
of O
the O
pleasure O
of O


this O
period O
of O
his O
existence O
with O
great O
enthusiasm O
, O
and O
give O
you O
to O


understand O
that O
he O
and O
Brummel B-PERSON
were O
the O
leading O
bucks O
of O
the B-DATE
day I-DATE
. O
But O
he O
was O


as O
lonely O
here O
as O
in O
his O
jungle O
at O
Boggley B-FAC
Wollah I-FAC
. O
He O
scarcely O
knew O
a O
single O


soul O
in O
the O
metropolis O
: O
and O
were O
it O
not O
for O
his O
doctor O
, O
and O
the O
society O
of O


his O
blue O
- O
pill O
, O
and O
his O
liver O
complaint O
, O
he O
must O
have O
died O
of O
loneliness O
. O
He O


was O
lazy O
, O
peevish O
, O
and O
a O

bon O
- O
vivant O
; O

the O
appearance O
of O
a O
lady O


frightened O
him O
beyond O
measure O
; O
hence O
it O
was O
but O
seldom O
that O
he O
joined O
the O


paternal O
circle O
in O
Russell B-FAC
Square I-FAC
, O
where O
there O
was O
plenty O
of O
gaiety O
, O
and O


where O
the O
jokes O
of O
his O
good O
natured O
old O
father O
frightened O
his O


amour O
- O
propre O
. O

His O
bulk O
caused O
Joseph B-PERSON
much O
anxious O
thought O
and O


alarm O
; O
now O
and O
then O
he O
would O
make O
a O
desperate O
attempt O
to O
get O
rid O
of O
his O


superabundant O
fat O
; O
but O
his O
indolence O
and O
love O
of O
good O
living O
speedily O
got O


the O
better O
of O
these O
endeavours O
at O
reform O
, O
and O
he O
found O
himself O
again O
at O
his O


three B-DATE
meals I-DATE
a I-DATE
day I-DATE
. O
he O
never O
was O
well O
dressed O
; O
but O
he O
took O
the O
hugest O
pains O


to O
adorn O
his O
big O
person O
, O
and O
passed O
many B-TIME
hours I-TIME
daily B-DATE
in O
that O
occupation O
. O
His O


valet O
made O
a O
fortune O
out O
of O
his O
wardrobe O
: O
his O
toilet O
- O
table O
was O
covered O
with O


as O
many O
pomatums O
and O
essences O
as O
ever O
were O
employed O
by O
an O
old O
beauty O
: O
he O
had O


tried O
, O
in O
order O
to O
give O
himself O
a O
waist O
, O
every O
girth O
, O
stay O
, O
and O
waistband O


then O
invented O
. O
Like O
most O
fat O
men O
, O
he O

would O

have O
his O
clothes O
made O


too O
tight O
, O
and O
took O
care O
they O
should O
be O
of O
the O
most O
brilliant O
colours O
and O


youthful O
cut O
. O
When O
dressed O
at O
length O
, O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
he O
would O
issue O
forth O


to O
take O
a O
drive O
with O
nobody O
in O
the O
Park O
; O
and O
then O
would O
come O
back O
in O
order O


to O
dress O
again O
and O
go O
and O
dine O
with O
nobody O
at O
the B-FAC
Piazza I-FAC
Coffee I-FAC
- I-FAC
House I-FAC
. O
He O


was O
as O
vain O
as O
a O
girl O
; O
and O
perhaps O
his O
extreme O
shyness O
was O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
the O


results O
of O
his O
extreme O
vanity O
. O
If O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
can O
get O
the O
better O
of O


him O
, O

and O
at O
her O
first B-ORDINAL
entrance O
into O
life O
, O
she O
is O
a O
young O
person O


of O
no O
ordinary O
cleverness O
. O


The O
first B-ORDINAL
move O
showed O
considerable O
skill O
. O
When O
she O
called O
Sedley B-PERSON
a O
very O


handsome O
man O
, O
she O
knew O
that O
Amelia B-PERSON
would O
tell O
her O
mother O
, O
who O
would O
probably O


tell O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
or O
who O
, O
at O
any O
rate O
, O
would O
be O
pleased O
by O
the O
compliment O
paid O
to O


her O
son O
. O
All O
mothers O
are O
. O
If O
you O
had O
told O
Sycorax B-PERSON
that O
her O
son O
Caliban B-PERSON
was O


as O
handsome O
as O
Apollo B-ORG
, O
she O
would O
have O
been O
pleased O
, O
witch O
as O
she O
was O
. O


Perhaps O
, O
too O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
would O
overhear O
the O
compliment O
— O
Rebecca B-PERSON
spoke O
loud O


enough O
— O
and O
he O

did O

hear O
, O
and O
( O
thinking O
in O
his O
heart O
that O
he O
was O
a O


very O
fine O
man O
) O
, O
the O
praise O
thrilled O
through O
every O
fibre O
of O
his O
big O
body O
, O
and O


made O
it O
tingle O
with O
pleasure O
. O


Then O
, O
however O
, O
came O
a O
recoil O
. O
 O
Is O
the O
girl O
making O
fun O
of O
me O
? O
 O
he O
thought O
, O


and O
straightway O
he O
bounced O
towards O
the O
bell O
, O
and O
was O
for O
retreating O
, O
as O
we O


have O
seen O
, O
when O
his O
father O
’s O
jokes O
and O
his O
mother O
’s O
entreaties O
caused O
him O
to O


pause O
and O
stay O
where O
he O
was O
. O
He O
conducted O
the O
young O
lady O
down O
to O
dinner O
in O
a O


dubious O
and O
agitated O
frame O
of O
mind O
. O
 O
Does O
she O
really O
think O
I O
am O
handsome O
? O
 O


thought O
he O
, O
 O
or O
is O
she O
only O
making O
game O
of O
me O
? O
 O
We O
have O
talked O
of O
Joseph B-PERSON


Sedley I-PERSON
being O
as O
vain O
as O
a O
girl O
. O
Heaven O
help O
us O
! O
the O
girls O
have O
only O
to O
turn O


the O
tables O
, O
and O
say O
of O
one B-CARDINAL
of O
their O
own O
sex O
, O
 O
She O
is O
as O
vain O
as O
a O
man O
, O
 O
and O


they O
will O
have O
perfect O
reason O
. O
The O
bearded O
creatures O
are O
quite O
as O
eager O
for O


praise O
, O
quite O
as O
finikin O
over O
their O
toilets O
, O
quite O
as O
proud O
of O
their O


personal O
advantages O
, O
quite O
as O
conscious O
of O
their O
powers O
of O
fascination O
, O
as O


any O
coquette O
in O
the O
world O
. O


Down O
stairs O
, O
then O
, O
they O
went O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
very O
red O
and O
blushing O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
very O


modest O
, O
and O
holding O
her O
green O
eyes O
downwards O
. O
She O
was O
dressed O
in O
white O
, O
with O


bare O
shoulders O
as O
white O
as O
snow O
— O
the O
picture O
of O
youth O
, O
unprotected O
innocence O
, O


and O
humble O
virgin O
simplicity O
. O
 O
I O
must O
be O
very O
quiet O
, O
 O
thought O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
 O
and O


very O
much O
interested O
about O
India B-GPE
. O
 O


Now O
we O
have O
heard O
how O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
had O
prepared O
a O
fine O
curry O
for O
her O
son O
, O


just O
as O
he O
liked O
it O
, O
and O
in O
the O
course O
of O
dinner O
a O
portion O
of O
this O
dish O
was O


offered O
to O
Rebecca B-PERSON
. O
 O
What O
is O
it O
? O
 O
said O
she O
, O
turning O
an O
appealing O
look O
to O
Mr. O


Joseph B-PERSON
. O


 O
Capital O
, O
 O
said O
he O
. O
His O
mouth O
was O
full O
of O
it O
; O
his O
face O
quite O
red O
with O
the O


delightful O
exercise O
of O
gobbling O
. O
 O
Mother O
, O
it O
’s O
as O
good O
as O
my O
own O
curries O
in O


India B-GPE
. O
 O


 O
Oh O
, O
I O
must O
try O
some O
, O
if O
it O
is O
an O
Indian B-NORP
dish O
, O
 O
said O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
. O
 O
I O
am O


sure O
everything O
must O
be O
good O
that O
comes O
from O
there O
. O
 O


 O
Give O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
some O
curry O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
 O
said O
Mr. O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O


Rebecca B-PERSON
had O
never O
tasted O
the O
dish O
before O
. O


 O
Do O
you O
find O
it O
as O
good O
as O
everything O
else O
from O
India B-GPE
? O
 O
said O
Mr. O


Sedley B-PERSON
. O


 O
Oh O
, O
excellent O
! O
 O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
who O
was O
suffering O
tortures O
with O
the O
cayenne O


pepper O
. O


 O
Try O
a O
chili O
with O
it O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
really O
interested O
. O


 O
A O
chili O
, O
 O
said O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
gasping O
. O
 O
Oh O
, O
yes O
! O
 O
She O
thought O
a O
chili O
was O


something O
cool O
, O
as O
its O
name O
imported O
, O
and O
was O
served O
with O
some O
. O
 O
How O
fresh O


and O
green O
they O
look O
, O
 O
she O
said O
, O
and O
put O
one B-CARDINAL
into O
her O
mouth O
. O
It O
was O
hotter O


than O
the O
curry O
; O
flesh O
and O
blood O
could O
bear O
it O
no O
longer O
. O
She O
laid O
down O
her O


fork O
. O
 O
Water O
, O
for O
Heaven O
’s O
sake O
, O
water O
! O
 O
she O
cried O
. O
Mr. O
Sedley B-PERSON
burst O
out O


laughing O
( O
he O
was O
a O
coarse O
man O
, O
from O
the B-ORG
Stock I-ORG
Exchange I-ORG
, O
where O
they O
love O
all O


sorts O
of O
practical O
jokes O
) O
. O
 O
They O
are O
real O
Indian B-NORP
, O
I O
assure O
you O
, O
 O
said O
he O
. O


 O
Sambo B-PERSON
, O
give O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
some O
water O
. O
 O


The O
paternal O
laugh O
was O
echoed O
by O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
who O
thought O
the O
joke O
capital O
. O
The O


ladies O
only O
smiled O
a O
little O
. O
They O
thought O
poor O
Rebecca B-PERSON
suffered O
too O
much O
. O


She O
would O
have O
liked O
to O
choke O
old O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
but O
she O
swallowed O
her O


mortification O
as O
well O
as O
she O
had O
the O
abominable O
curry O
before O
it O
, O
and O
as O
soon O


as O
she O
could O
speak O
, O
said O
, O
with O
a O
comical O
, O
good O
- O
humoured O
air O
— O


 O
I O
ought O
to O
have O
remembered O
the O
pepper O
which O
the O
Princess O
of O
Persia O
puts O
in O


the O
cream O
- O
tarts O
in O
the O

Arabian B-WORK_OF_ART
Nights I-WORK_OF_ART
. O

Do O
you O
put O
cayenne O
into O
your O


cream O
- O
tarts O
in O
India B-GPE
, O
sir O
? O
 O


Old O
Sedley B-PERSON
began O
to O
laugh O
, O
and O
thought O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
a O
good O
- O
humoured O
girl O
. O


Joseph B-PERSON
simply O
said—Cream O
- O
tarts O
, O
Miss O
? O
Our O
cream O
is O
very O
bad O
in O
Bengal B-GPE
. O
We O


generally O
use O
goats O
’ O
milk O
; O
and O
, O
’ O
gad O
, O
do O
you O
know O
, O
I O
’ve O
got O
to O
prefer O


it O
! O
 O


 O
You O
wo O
n’t O
like O

everything O

from O
India B-GPE
now O
, O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
the O


old O
gentleman O
; O
but O
when O
the O
ladies O
had O
retired O
after O
dinner O
, O
the O
wily O
old O


fellow O
said O
to O
his O
son O
, O
 O
Have O
a O
care O
, O
Joe B-PERSON
; O
that O
girl O
is O
setting O
her O
cap O
at O


you O
. O
 O


 O
Pooh B-PERSON
! O
nonsense O
! O
 O
said O
Joe B-PERSON
, O
highly O
flattered O
. O
 O
I O
recollect O
, O
sir O
, O
there O
was O


a O
girl O
at O
Dumdum B-LOC
, O
a O
daughter O
of O
Cutler B-PERSON
of O
the O
Artillery B-ORG
, O
and O
afterwards O


married O
to O
Lance B-ORG
, O
the O
surgeon O
, O
who O
made O
a O
dead O
set O
at O
me O
in O
the B-DATE
year I-DATE
’ I-DATE
4 I-DATE
— O
at O


me O
and O
Mulligatawney B-PERSON
, O
whom O
I O
mentioned O
to O
you O
before O
dinner O
— O
a O
devilish O
good O


fellow O
, O
Mulligatawney B-PERSON
— O
he O
’s O
a O
magistrate O
at O
Budgebudge B-ORG
, O
and O
sure O
to O
be O
in O


council O
in O
five B-DATE
years I-DATE
. O
Well O
, O
sir O
, O
the O
Artillery B-ORG
gave O
a O
ball O
, O
and O
Quintin B-PERSON
, O
of O


the O
King O
’s O
14th B-ORDINAL
, O
said O
to O
me O
, O
‘ O
Sedley B-PERSON
, O
’ O
said O
he O
, O
‘ O
I O
bet O
you O
thirteen B-CARDINAL
to I-CARDINAL
ten I-CARDINAL


that O
Sophy B-PERSON
Cutler I-PERSON
hooks O
either O
you O
or O
Mulligatawney B-ORG
before O
the O
rains O
. O
’ O


‘ O
Done O
, O
’ O
says O
I O
; O
and O
egad O
, O
sir O
— O
this O
claret O
’s O
very O
good O
. O
Adamson B-PERSON
’s O
or O


Carbonell B-PERSON
’s O
? O
 O
… O


A O
slight O
snore O
was O
the O
only O
reply O
: O
the O
honest O
stock O
- O
broker O
was O
asleep O
, O
and O


so O
the O
rest O
of O
Joseph B-PERSON
’s O
story O
was O
lost O
for O
that B-DATE
day I-DATE
. O
But O
he O
was O
always O


exceedingly O
communicative O
in O
a O
man O
’s O
party O
, O
and O
has O
told O
this O
delightful O


tale O
many O
scores O
of O
times O
to O
his O
apothecary O
, O
Dr. O
Gollop B-PERSON
, O
when O
he O
came O
to O


inquire O
about O
the O
liver O
and O
the O
blue O
- O
pill O
. O


Being O
an O
invalid O
, O
Joseph B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
contented O
himself O
with O
a O
bottle O
of O
claret O


besides O
his O
Madeira B-LOC
at O
dinner O
, O
and O
he O
managed O
a O
couple O
of O
plates O
full O
of O


strawberries O
and O
cream O
, O
and O
twenty B-CARDINAL
- I-CARDINAL
four I-CARDINAL
little O
rout O
cakes O
, O
that O
were O
lying O


neglected O
in O
a O
plate O
near O
him O
, O
and O
certainly O
( O
for O
novelists O
have O
the O


privilege O
of O
knowing O
everything O
) O
, O
he O
thought O
a O
great O
deal O
about O
the O
girl O


upstairs O
. O
 O
A O
nice O
, O
gay O
, O
merry O
young O
creature O
, O
 O
thought O
he O
to O
himself O
. O
 O
How O


she O
looked O
at O
me O
when O
I O
picked O
up O
her O
handkerchief O
at O
dinner O
! O
She O
dropped O
it O


twice O
. O
Who O
’s O
that O
singing O
in O
the O
drawing O
- O
room O
? O
’ O
Gad B-PERSON
! O
shall O
I O
go O
up O
and O


see O
? O
 O


But O
his O
modesty O
came O
rushing O
upon O
him O
with O
uncontrollable O
force O
. O
His O
father O


was O
asleep O
: O
his O
hat O
was O
in O
the O
hall O
: O
there O
was O
a O
hackney O
- O
coach O
stand O
hard O
by O


in O
Southampton B-ORG
Row I-ORG
. O
 O
I O
’ll O
go O
and O
see O
the O

Forty O
Thieves O
, O
 O

said O
he O
, O


 O
and O
Miss B-PERSON
Decamp I-PERSON
’s O
dance O
; O
 O
and O
he O
slipped O
gently O
away O
on O
the O
pointed O
toes O
of O


his O
boots O
, O
and O
disappeared O
, O
without O
waking O
his O
worthy O
parent O
. O


 O
There O
goes O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
who O
was O
looking O
from O
the O
open O
windows O
of O


the O
drawing O
- O
room O
, O
while O
Rebecca B-PERSON
was O
singing O
at O
the O
piano O
. O


 O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
has O
frightened O
him O
away O
, O
 O
said O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
. O
 O
Poor O
Joe B-PERSON
, O
why O


will O

he O
be O
so O
shy O
? O
 O



IV O
. O
The B-ORG
Green I-ORG
Silk I-ORG
Purse I-ORG


POOR I-ORG
Joe I-ORG
’s I-ORG
panic O
lasted O
for O
two B-DATE
or I-DATE
three I-DATE
days I-DATE
; O
during O
which O
he O
did O
not O
visit O


the O
house O
, O
nor O
during O
that O
period O
did O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
ever O
mention O
his O
name O
. O


She O
was O
all O
respectful O
gratitude O
to O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
; O
delighted O
beyond O
measure O
at O


the O
Bazaars B-ORG
; O
and O
in O
a O
whirl O
of O
wonder O
at O
the O
theatre O
, O
whither O
the O


good O
- O
natured O
lady O
took O
her O
. O
One B-DATE
day I-DATE
, O
Amelia B-PERSON
had O
a O
head O
- O
ache O
, O
and O
could O
not O


go O
upon O
some O
party O
of O
pleasure O
to O
which O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
young O
people O
were O
invited O
; O


nothing O
could O
induce O
her O
friend O
to O
go O
without O
her O
. O
 O
What O
! O
you O
who O
have O
shown O


the O
poor O
orphan O
what O
happiness O
and O
love O
are O
for O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
time O
in O
her O


life O
— O
quit O

you O
? O

never O
! O
 O
and O
the O
green O
eyes O
looked O
up O
to O
Heaven O
and O


filled O
with O
tears O
; O
and O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
could O
not O
but O
own O
that O
her O
daughter O
’s O


friend O
had O
a O
charming O
kind O
heart O
of O
her O
own O
. O


As O
for O
Mr. O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
jokes O
, O
Rebecca B-PERSON
laughed O
at O
them O
with O
a O
cordiality O
and O


perseverance O
which O
not O
a O
little O
pleased O
and O
softened O
that O
good O
- O
natured O


gentleman O
. O
Nor O
was O
it O
with O
the O
chiefs O
of O
the O
family O
alone O
that O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON


found O
favour O
. O
She O
interested O
Mrs. O
Blenkinsop B-PERSON
by O
evincing O
the O
deepest O


sympathy O
in O
the O
raspberry O
- O
jam O
preserving O
, O
which O
operation O
was O
then O
going O
on O


in O
the O
Housekeeper B-ORG
’s O
room O
; O
she O
persisted O
in O
calling O
Sambo B-PERSON
 O
Sir O
, O
 O
and O
 O
Mr. O


Sambo B-PERSON
, O
 O
to O
the O
delight O
of O
that O
attendant O
; O
and O
she O
apologised O
to O
the O
lady O
’s O


maid O
for O
giving O
her O
trouble O
in O
venturing O
to O
ring O
the O
bell O
, O
with O
such O


sweetness O
and O
humility O
, O
that O
the B-ORG
Servants I-ORG
’ I-ORG
Hall I-ORG
was O
almost O
as O
charmed O
with O


her O
as O
the O
Drawing O
Room O
. O


Once O
, O
in O
looking O
over O
some O
drawings O
which O
Amelia B-PERSON
had O
sent O
from O
school O
, O


Rebecca B-PERSON
suddenly O
came O
upon O
one O
which O
caused O
her O
to O
burst O
into O
tears O
and O


leave O
the O
room O
. O
It O
was O
on O
the B-DATE
day I-DATE
when O
Joe B-PERSON
Sedley I-PERSON
made O
his O
second B-ORDINAL


appearance O
. O


Amelia B-PERSON
hastened O
after O
her O
friend O
to O
know O
the O
cause O
of O
this O
display O
of O


feeling O
and O
the O
good O
- O
natured O
girl O
came O
back O
without O
her O
companion O
, O
rather O


affected O
too O
. O
 O
You O
know O
, O
her O
father O
was O
our O
drawing O
- O
master O
, O
Mamma B-PERSON
, O
at O


Chiswick B-GPE
, O
and O
used O
to O
do O
all O
the O
best O
parts O
of O
our O
drawings O
. O
 O


 O
My O
love O
! O
I O
’m O
sure O
I O
always O
heard O
Miss O
Pinkerton B-PERSON
say O
that O
he O
did O
not O
touch O


them O
— O
he O
only O

mounted O

them O
. O
 O


 O
It O
was O
called O
mounting O
, O
Mamma B-PERSON
. O
Rebecca B-PERSON
remembers O
the O
drawing O
, O
and O
her O


father O
working O
at O
it O
, O
and O
the O
thought O
of O
it O
came O
upon O
her O
rather O


suddenly O
— O
and O
so O
, O
you O
know O
, O
she O
— O
— O
 O


 O
The O
poor O
child O
is O
all O
heart O
, O
 O
said O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
. O


 O
I O
wish O
she O
could O
stay O
with O
us O
another B-DATE
week I-DATE
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O


 O
She O
’s O
devilish O
like O
Miss O
Cutler B-PERSON
that O
I O
used O
to O
meet O
at O
Dumdum B-LOC
, O
only O


fairer O
. O
She O
’s O
married O
now O
to O
Lance B-ORG
, I-ORG
the I-ORG
Artillery I-ORG
Surgeon I-ORG
. O
Do O
you O
know O
, O


Ma’am O
, O
that O
once O
Quintin B-PERSON
, O
of O
the O
14th B-ORDINAL
, O
bet O
me O
— O
— O
 O


 O
O O
Joseph B-PERSON
we O
know O
that O
story O
, O
 O
said O
Amelia B-PERSON
, O
laughing O
. O
 O
Never O
mind O
about O


telling O
that O
, O
but O
persuade O
Mamma B-PERSON
to O
write O
to O
Sir O
Something O
Crawley B-PERSON
for O
leave O


of O
absence O
for O
poor O
dear O
Rebecca:—here O
she O
comes O
, O
her O
eyes O
red O
with O


weeping O
. O
 O


 O
I O
’m O
better O
, O
now O
, O
 O
said O
the O
girl O
, O
with O
the O
sweetest O
smile O
possible O
, O
taking O


good O
- O
natured O
Mrs. O
Sedley B-PERSON
’s O
extended O
hand O
and O
kissing O
it O
respectfully O
. O
 O
How O


kind O
you O
all O
are O
to O
me O
! O
All O
, O
 O
she O
added O
, O
with O
a O
laugh O
, O
 O
except O
you O
, O
Mr. O


Joseph B-PERSON
. O
 O


 O
Me O
! O
 O
said O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
meditating O
an O
instant O
departure O
. O
 O
Gracious O
Heavens O
! O
Good O


Gad B-PERSON
! O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
! O
 O


 O
Yes O
; O
how O
could O
you O
be O
so O
cruel O
as O
to O
make O
me O
eat O
that O
horrid O
pepper O
- O
dish O


at O
dinner O
, O
the B-DATE
first I-DATE
day I-DATE
I O
ever O
saw O
you O
? O
You O
are O
not O
so O
good O
to O
me O
as O
dear O


Amelia B-PERSON
. O
 O


 O
He O
does O
n’t O
know O
you O
so O
well O
, O
 O
cried O
Amelia B-PERSON
. O


 O
I O
defy O
anybody O
not O
to O
be O
good O
to O
you O
, O
my O
dear O
, O
 O
said O
her O
mother O
. O


 O
The O
curry O
was O
capital O
; O
indeed O
it O
was O
, O
 O
said O
Joe B-PERSON
, O
quite O
gravely O
. O
 O
Perhaps O


there O
was O
not O
enough O
citron O
juice O
in O
it O
: O
no O
, O
there O
was O
not O
. O
 O


 O
And O
the O
chilis O
? O
 O


 O
By O
Jove B-PERSON
, O
how O
they O
made O
you O
cry O
out O
! O
 O
said O
Joe B-PERSON
, O
caught O
by O
the O
ridicule O
of O


the O
circumstance O
, O
and O
exploding O
in O
a O
fit O
of O
laughter O
which O
ended O
quite O


suddenly O
, O
as O
usual O
. O


 O
I O
shall O
take O
care O
how O
I O
let O

you O

choose O
for O
me O
another O
time O
, O
 O
said O


Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
as O
they O
went O
down O
again O
to O
dinner O
. O
 O
I O
did O
n’t O
think O
men O
were O
fond O
of O


putting O
poor O
harmless O
girls O
to O
pain O
. O
 O


 O
By O
Gad B-PERSON
, O
Miss O
Rebecca B-PERSON
, O
I O
would O
n’t O
hurt O
you O
for O
the O
world O
. O
 O


 O
No O
, O
 O
said O
she O
, O
 O
I O

know O

you O
would O
n’t O
; O
 O
and O
then O
she O
gave O
him O
ever O


so O
gentle O
a O
pressure O
with O
her O
little O
hand O
, O
and O
drew O
it O
back O
quite O


frightened O
, O
and O
looked O
first B-ORDINAL
for O
one B-CARDINAL
instant O
in O
his O
face O
, O
and O
then O
down O
at O


the O
carpet O
- O
rods O
; O
and O
I O
am O
not O
prepared O
to O
say O
that O
Joe B-PERSON
’s O
heart O
did O
not O
thump O


at O
this O
little O
involuntary O
, O
timid O
, O
gentle O
motion O
of O
regard O
on O
the O
part O
of O


the O
simple O
girl O
. O


It O
was O
an O
advance O
, O
and O
as O
such O
, O
perhaps O
, O
some O
ladies O
of O
indisputable O


correctness O
and O
gentility O
will O
condemn O
the O
action O
as O
immodest O
; O
but O
, O
you O
see O
, O


poor O
dear O
Rebecca B-PERSON
had O
all O
this O
work O
to O
do O
for O
herself O
. O
If O
a O
person O
is O
too O


poor O
to O
keep O
a O
servant O
, O
though O
ever O
so O
elegant O
, O
he O
must O
sweep O
his O
own O
rooms O
: O


if O
a O
dear O
girl O
has O
no O
dear O
Mamma B-PERSON
to O
settle O
matters O
with O
the O
young O
man O
, O
she O


must O
do O
it O
for O
herself O
. O
And O
oh O
, O
what O
a O
mercy O
it O
is O
that O
these O
women O
do O
not O


exercise O
their O
powers O
oftener O
! O
We O
ca O
n’t O
resist O
them O
, O
if O
they O
do O
. O
Let O
them O


show O
ever O
so O
little O
inclination O
, O
and O
men O
go O
down O
on O
their O
knees O
at O
once O
: O
old O


or O
ugly O
, O
it O
is O
all O
the O
same O
. O
And O
this O
I O
set O
down O
as O
a O
positive O
truth O
. O
A O


woman O
with O
fair O
opportunities O
, O
and O
without O
an O
absolute O
hump O
, O
may O
marry O
WHOM O


SHE B-PERSON
LIKES O
. O
Only O
let O
us O
be O
thankful O
that O
the O
darlings O
are O
like O
the O
beasts O
of O


the O
field O
, O
and O
do O
n’t O
know O
their O
own O
power O
. O
They O
would O
overcome O
us O
entirely O


if O
they O
did O
. O


 O
Egad O
! O
 O
thought O
Joseph B-PERSON
, O
entering O
the O
dining O
- O
room O
, O
 O
I O
exactly O
begin O
to O
feel O


as O
I O
did O
at O
Dumdum O
with O
Miss O
Cutler B-PERSON
. O
 O
Many O
sweet O
little O
appeals O
, O
half B-CARDINAL


tender O
, O
half B-CARDINAL
jocular O
, O
did O
Miss O
Sharp B-PERSON
make O
to O
him O
about O
the O
dishes O
at O
dinner O
; O


for O
by O
this O
time O
she O
was O
on O
a O
footing O
of O
considerable O
familiarity O
with O
the O


family O
, O
and O
as O
for O
the O
girls O
, O
they O
loved O
each O
other O
like O
sisters O
. O
Young O

